sentence	token	label
	The	O
	law	O
	should	O
	be	O
	amended	O
	to	O
	give	O
	the	O
	truth	O
	Justice	B-ORG
	and	I-ORG
	Reconciliation	I-ORG
	commission	I-ORG
	more	O
	powers	O
	and	O
	speed	O
	up	O
	its	O
	work	O
	","	O
	Deputy	O
	speaker	O
	Farah	B-ADLT
	Maalim	I-ADLT
	was	O
	saying	O
	during	O
	the	O
	consultative	O
	meeting	O
	in	O
	western	B-LOC
	Kenya	I-LOC
	.	O
	Unless	O
	you	O
	have	O
	independence	O
	","	O
	You	O
	will	O
	not	O
	go	O
	anywhere	O
	.	O
	Its	O
	therefore	O
	propose	O
	that	O
	the	O
	Act	O
	be	O
	amended	O
	to	O
	allow	O
	the	O
	commission	O
	when	O
	acting	O
	on	O
	issues	O
	have	O
	independence	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Misia	B-ADLT
	","	O
	a	O
	Japanese	O
	musician	O
	took	O
	a	O
	tour	O
	in	O
	2009	O
	to	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	slum	I-LOC
	.	O
	She	O
	saw	O
	how	O
	the	O
	people	O
	lived	O
	there	O
	and	O
	she	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	to	O
	help	O
	some	O
	children	O
	who	O
	she	O
	saw	O
	singing	O
	.	O
	They	O
	sang	O
	very	O
	well	O
	and	O
	deeply	O
	from	O
	singing	O
	their	O
	heart	O
	.	O
	She	O
	accepted	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	for	O
	their	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	and	O
	provide	O
	them	O
	with	O
	food	O
	and	O
	shelter	O
	.	O
	The	O
	children	O
	were	O
	happy	O
	and	O
	they	O
	all	O
	joined	O
	a	O
	nearby	O
	school	O
	which	O
	Misia	B-ADLT
	had	O
	visited	O
	.	O
	The	O
	school	O
	is	O
	MAGOSO	B-ORG
	where	O
	they	O
	were	O
	given	O
	a	O
	place	O
	to	O
	live	O
	and	O
	food	O
	to	O
	eat	O
	.	O
	All	O
	their	O
	need	O
	were	O
	being	O
	paid	O
	for	O
	by	O
	Misia	B-ADLT
	who	O
	was	O
	a	O
	very	O
	good	O
	Samaritan	O
	.	O
	The	O
	children	O
	still	O
	live	O
	to	O
	thank	O
	Misia	B-ADLT
	for	O
	helping	O
	and	O
	delivering	O
	them	O
	from	O
	their	O
	situation	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Nivea	B-ADLT
	is	O
	27	O
	years	O
	old	O
	here	O
	in	O
	East	B-LOC
	Africa	I-LOC
	however	O
	at	O
	a	O
	global	O
	level	O
	","	O
	2011	O
	marks	O
	","	O
	NIVEA	B-ADLT
	's	O
	100th	O
	anniversary	O
	.	O
	NIVEA	B-ADLT
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	most	O
	world	O
	's	O
	trusted	O
	skincare	O
	brands	O
	","	O
	but	O
	it	O
	took	O
	three	O
	minds	O
	.	O
	with	O
	one	O
	shared	O
	vision	O
	to	O
	make	O
	it	O
	happen	O
	.	O
	During	O
	the	O
	past	O
	century	O
	","	O
	NIVEA	B-ADLT
	has	O
	been	O
	a	O
	constant	O
	companion	O
	for	O
	the	O
	millions	O
	of	O
	people	O
	including	O
	some	O
	of	O
	the	O
	most	O
	recognizable	O
	faces	O
	in	O
	the	O
	world	O
	Global	O
	music	O
	icon	O
	Rihanna	B-ADLT
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	those	O
	recognizable	O
	faces	O
	","	O
	and	O
	now	O
	celebrating	O
	100th	O
	anniversary	O
	.	O
	NIVEA	B-ADLT
	is	O
	dedicated	O
	to	O
	making	O
	people	O
	feel	O
	comfortable	O
	in	O
	their	O
	own	O
	skin	O
	.	O
	NIVEA	B-ADLT
	is	O
	good	O
	and	O
	better	O
	for	O
	skin	O
	care	O
	so	O
	its	O
	good	O
	to	O
	use	O
	NIVEA	B-ADLT
	in	O
	your	O
	family	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	most	O
	dangerous	O
	disease	O
	which	O
	kills	O
	a	O
	big	O
	number	O
	of	O
	people	O
	a	O
	day	O
	is	O
	aids	O
	.	O
	Aids	O
	does	O
	not	O
	choose	O
	whom	O
	to	O
	kill	O
	.	O
	It	O
	kills	O
	everybody	O
	the	O
	rich	O
	","	O
	poor	O
	","	O
	orphans	O
	and	O
	disabled	O
	people	O
	.	O
	In	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	biggest	O
	slums	O
	in	O
	the	O
	world	O
	the	O
	epidermis	O
	is	O
	everywhere	O
	and	O
	kills	O
	many	O
	youths	O
	daily	O
	.	O
	In	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	the	O
	people	O
	who	O
	are	O
	mostly	O
	attacked	O
	by	O
	this	O
	dangerous	O
	disease	O
	are	O
	the	O
	youths	O
	who	O
	engage	O
	in	O
	pre	O
	-	O
	marital	O
	sex	O
	.	O
	The	O
	government	O
	once	O
	tried	O
	to	O
	help	O
	them	O
	but	O
	it	O
	has	O
	not	O
	able	O
	.	O
	The	O
	Kenyan	B-ORG
	government	I-ORG
	introduced	O
	free	O
	condoms	O
	to	O
	the	O
	youths	O
	which	O
	reduced	O
	the	O
	percentage	O
	of	O
	infection	O
	.	O
	The	O
	free	O
	condoms	O
	helped	O
	some	O
	youths	O
	but	O
	some	O
	was	O
	like	O
	playing	O
	a	O
	guitar	O
	to	O
	a	O
	goat	O
	.	O
	Nowadays	O
	some	O
	of	O
	these	O
	condoms	O
	are	O
	fake	O
	and	O
	contribute	O
	to	O
	the	O
	spread	O
	of	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	epidermis	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Jeff	B-ADLT
	Koinange	I-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	Kenyan	O
	journalist	O
	commonly	O
	known	O
	for	O
	his	O
	30	O
	mins	O
	interview	O
	programme	O
	called	O
	the	O
	bench	O
	.	O
	Jeff	O
	has	O
	his	O
	own	O
	television	O
	station	O
	known	O
	as	O
	K24	B-ORG
	which	O
	is	O
	the	O
	award	O
	winning	O
	station	O
	in	O
	the	O
	CNN	B-ORG
	Africa	B-LOC
	journalists	O
	of	O
	the	O
	year	O
	award	O
	.	O
	In	O
	his	O
	programme	O
	he	O
	hosts	O
	great	O
	people	O
	with	O
	great	O
	legacy	O
	","	O
	they	O
	come	O
	inspire	O
	us	O
	through	O
	their	O
	talk	O
	","	O
	he	O
	also	O
	interviews	O
	our	O
	leaders	O
	and	O
	we	O
	get	O
	to	O
	hear	O
	their	O
	manifestos	O
	and	O
	also	O
	future	O
	plans	O
	.	O
	Crucial	O
	topics	O
	are	O
	discussed	O
	and	O
	solutions	O
	given	O
	to	O
	some	O
	of	O
	our	O
	problems	O
	.	O
	Through	O
	his	O
	programme	O
	important	O
	is	O
	passed	O
	across	O
	the	O
	country	O
	and	O
	also	O
	the	O
	programme	O
	creates	O
	a	O
	lot	O
	of	O
	awareness	O
	.	O
	His	O
	programme	O
	is	O
	one	O
	that	O
	can	O
	not	O
	be	O
	afforded	O
	to	O
	be	O
	missed	O
	and	O
	everyone	O
	is	O
	always	O
	eager	O
	to	O
	watch	O
	it	O
	daily	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	Olympic	B-ORG
	games	I-ORG
	are	O
	among	O
	the	O
	most	O
	popular	O
	sports	O
	competitions	O
	that	O
	attract	O
	worldwide	O
	attention	O
	the	O
	games	O
	started	O
	in	O
	Greece	O
	776	O
	BC	O
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	held	O
	every	O
	four	O
	four	O
	years	O
	in	O
	a	O
	different	O
	country	O
	.	O
	In	O
	2008	O
	the	O
	Olympic	B-ORG
	Games	I-ORG
	were	O
	held	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	came	O
	to	O
	see	O
	how	O
	their	O
	players	O
	were	O
	going	O
	to	O
	participate	O
	in	O
	the	O
	athletes	O
	.	O
	There	O
	were	O
	special	O
	traffic	O
	and	O
	parking	O
	arrangements	O
	for	O
	the	O
	games	O
	.	O
	Spectators	O
	","	O
	athletes	O
	and	O
	officials	O
	made	O
	their	O
	way	O
	to	O
	venues	O
	.	O
	The	O
	games	O
	were	O
	full	O
	of	O
	surprises	O
	.	O
	Other	O
	Olympic	O
	and	O
	world	O
	records	O
	were	O
	set	O
	in	O
	different	O
	events	O
	.	O
	In	O
	steeplechase	O
	","	O
	Kenyan	O
	athletes	O
	dominated	O
	in	O
	their	O
	spectacular	O
	manner	O
	winning	O
	the	O
	first	O
	three	O
	position	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Poverty	O
	is	O
	the	O
	living	O
	a	O
	poor	O
	lifestyle	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	around	O
	the	O
	world	O
	are	O
	poor	O
	beggars	O
	and	O
	hustlers	O
	.	O
	These	O
	people	O
	are	O
	living	O
	in	O
	difficult	O
	conditions	O
	which	O
	make	O
	some	O
	of	O
	them	O
	perish	O
	.	O
	In	O
	my	O
	neighbourhood	O
	","	O
	there	O
	lived	O
	a	O
	poor	O
	man	O
	known	O
	as	O
	Wambui	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Wambui	B-ADLT
	was	O
	poor	O
	and	O
	sometimes	O
	had	O
	to	O
	beg	O
	from	O
	people	O
	around	O
	the	O
	town	O
	to	O
	earn	O
	a	O
	living	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	Wambui	B-ADLT
	was	O
	blessed	O
	with	O
	a	O
	job	O
	.	O
	He	O
	helped	O
	business	O
	men	O
	and	O
	women	O
	to	O
	carry	O
	their	O
	goods	O
	from	O
	the	O
	market	O
	to	O
	their	O
	various	O
	business	O
	locations	O
	.	O
	Wambui	B-ADLT
	used	O
	the	O
	money	O
	he	O
	got	O
	from	O
	the	O
	business	O
	men	O
	and	O
	women	O
	carefully	O
	while	O
	some	O
	he	O
	saved	O
	.	O
	Wambui	B-ADLT
	had	O
	a	O
	dream	O
	of	O
	becoming	O
	a	O
	driver	O
	in	O
	future	O
	.	O
	After	O
	10	O
	years	O
	of	O
	doing	O
	the	O
	same	O
	job	O
	Wambui	B-ADLT
	bought	O
	his	O
	own	O
	motor	O
	bike	O
	and	O
	started	O
	transporting	O
	goods	O
	and	O
	people	O
	from	O
	the	O
	market	O
	to	O
	the	O
	town	O
	.	O
	After	O
	another	O
	five	O
	years	O
	Wambui	B-ADLT
	had	O
	saved	O
	enough	O
	a	O
	Nissan	O
	and	O
	he	O
	used	O
	it	O
	to	O
	transport	O
	people	O
	from	O
	Nagumo	B-LOC
	to	O
	the	O
	town	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	In	O
	my	O
	village	O
	there	O
	lived	O
	a	O
	teenager	O
	who	O
	lived	O
	used	O
	to	O
	disturb	O
	","	O
	seduce	O
	and	O
	rape	O
	young	O
	girls	O
	.	O
	The	O
	teenager	O
	was	O
	known	O
	as	O
	Njoroge	B-MINR
	.	O
	He	O
	dropped	O
	out	O
	of	O
	school	O
	and	O
	started	O
	his	O
	small	O
	business	O
	of	O
	showing	O
	films	O
	.	O
	He	O
	would	O
	run	O
	the	O
	business	O
	up	O
	to	O
	six	O
	o	O
		O
	clock	O
	in	O
	the	O
	evening	O
	and	O
	then	O
	love	O
	young	O
	girls	O
	to	O
	his	O
	dirty	O
	house	O
	.	O
	most	O
	of	O
	the	O
	girls	O
	loved	O
	were	O
	school	O
	girls	O
	.	O
	He	O
	had	O
	sex	O
	with	O
	almost	O
	all	O
	the	O
	girls	O
	in	O
	the	O
	village	O
	.	O
	Half	O
	of	O
	the	O
	number	O
	ended	O
	being	O
	pregnant	O
	while	O
	some	O
	were	O
	infected	O
	with	O
	dangerous	O
	diseases	O
	.	O
	When	O
	time	O
	passed	O
	by	O
	Njoroge	B-MINR
	raped	O
	a	O
	class	O
	seven	O
	girl	O
	but	O
	he	O
	thought	O
	he	O
	would	O
	not	O
	be	O
	noticed	O
	.	O
	The	O
	girl	O
	reported	O
	the	O
	arse	O
	to	O
	the	O
	village	O
	chief	O
	.	O
	Njoroge	B-MINR
	was	O
	arrested	O
	for	O
	raping	O
	a	O
	school	O
	girl	O
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	imprisoned	O
	for	O
	five	O
	years	O
	when	O
	Njoroge	B-MINR
	came	O
	back	O
	he	O
	had	O
	changed	O
	his	O
	behaviour	O
	and	O
	respected	O
	young	O
	girls	O
	and	O
	their	O
	rights	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Kenya	B-LOC
	's	O
	leap	O
	in	O
	fight	O
	against	O
	cancer	O
	but	O
	now	O
	we	O
	have	O
	the	O
	latest	O
	screening	O
	treatment	O
	technology	O
	available	O
	for	O
	east	O
	Africans	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	has	O
	consolidated	O
	its	O
	position	O
	as	O
	regional	O
	medical	O
	hub	O
	with	O
	the	O
	opening	O
	of	O
	heart	O
	and	O
	cancer	O
	centre	O
	in	O
	Nairobi	B-LOC
	.	O
	The	O
	centre	O
	at	O
	the	O
	Aga	B-ORG
	khan	I-ORG
	university	I-ORG
	hospital	I-ORG
	is	O
	equipped	O
	with	O
	latest	O
	screening	O
	and	O
	treatment	O
	technologies	O
	.	O
	it	O
	will	O
	be	O
	the	O
	first	O
	region	O
	to	O
	do	O
	research	O
	on	O
	heart	O
	and	O
	cancer	O
	disease	O
	that	O
	is	O
	in	O
	Africa	B-LOC
	.	O
	There	O
	is	O
	no	O
	doubt	O
	since	O
	the	O
	doctors	O
	will	O
	alleviate	O
	the	O
	rise	O
	of	O
	non	O
	-	O
	communicable	O
	disease	O
	in	O
	sub	B-LOC
	-	I-LOC
	Saharan	I-LOC
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	This	O
	Kiswahili	B-ORG
	saying	O
	watu	O
	","	O
	watu	O
	wengi	O
	lakini	O
	binadamu	O
	wachache	O
	","	O
	fits	O
	this	O
	story	O
	.	O
	My	O
	friend	O
	victor	B-MINR
	and	O
	his	O
	brother	O
	lost	O
	their	O
	parents	O
	when	O
	they	O
	were	O
	young	O
	they	O
	had	O
	nobody	O
	to	O
	take	O
	care	O
	of	O
	them	O
	their	O
	aunt	O
	took	O
	them	O
	and	O
	went	O
	to	O
	stay	O
	with	O
	them	O
	","	O
	she	O
	took	O
	the	O
	challenge	O
	to	O
	live	O
	with	O
	them	O
	and	O
	her	O
	children	O
	they	O
	were	O
	taken	O
	care	O
	very	O
	well	O
	now	O
	Victor	B-MINR
	is	O
	a	O
	grown	O
	teenager	O
	in	O
	high	O
	school	O
	.	O
	May	O
	God	O
	bless	O
	her	O
	and	O
	her	O
	husband	O
	and	O
	Victor	B-MINR
	has	O
	promised	O
	to	O
	make	O
	their	O
	face	O
	smile	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Stealing	O
	is	O
	the	O
	taking	O
	of	O
	someone	O
	's	O
	property	O
	when	O
	he	O
	or	O
	she	O
	is	O
	not	O
	around	O
	or	O
	aware	O
	.	O
	Stealing	O
	leads	O
	to	O
	the	O
	death	O
	of	O
	many	O
	people	O
	because	O
	when	O
	thieves	O
	are	O
	caught	O
	they	O
	are	O
	burnt	O
	or	O
	stoned	O
	to	O
	death	O
	by	O
	the	O
	mob	O
	.	O
	When	O
	I	O
	was	O
	in	O
	class	O
	eight	O
	I	O
	had	O
	a	O
	friend	O
	of	O
	mine	O
	known	O
	as	O
	Kiala	B-MINR
	.	O
	Kiala	B-MINR
	was	O
	the	O
	class	O
	thief	O
	but	O
	nobody	O
	knew	O
	expect	O
	me	O
	.	O
	I	O
	tried	O
	to	O
	guide	O
	him	O
	and	O
	he	O
	refused	O
	and	O
	continued	O
	with	O
	his	O
	daily	O
	activity	O
	.	O
	KIala	B-MINR
	continued	O
	with	O
	his	O
	bad	O
	career	O
	and	O
	now	O
	he	O
	would	O
	even	O
	snatch	O
	valuable	O
	goods	O
	from	O
	strangers	O
	and	O
	run	O
	away	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	when	O
	we	O
	were	O
	going	O
	home	O
	from	O
	school	O
	Kiala	B-MINR
	saw	O
	an	O
	old	O
	woman	O
	in	O
	front	O
	of	O
	us	O
	carrying	O
	a	O
	phone	O
	.	O
	He	O
	left	O
	me	O
	behind	O
	and	O
	ran	O
	towards	O
	the	O
	old	O
	woman	O
	's	O
	hand	O
	and	O
	robbed	O
	her	O
	the	O
	phone	O
	.	O
	The	O
	old	O
	woman	O
	screamed	O
	loudly	O
	and	O
	the	O
	villagers	O
	who	O
	were	O
	around	O
	this	O
	place	O
	caught	O
	Kiara	B-MINR
	.	O
	Kiara	B-MINR
	was	O
	beaten	O
	properly	O
	before	O
	taken	O
	to	O
	the	O
	chief	O
	.	O
	I	O
	ran	O
	and	O
	left	O
	him	O
	behind	O
	.	O
	The	O
	chief	O
	gave	O
	him	O
	twenty	O
	strokes	O
	of	O
	cane	O
	.	O
	Since	O
	that	O
	day	O
	kiala	B-MINR
	changed	O
	his	O
	habit	O
	of	O
	stealing	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Njuguna	B-MINR
	","	O
	a	O
	corrupted	O
	young	O
	man	O
	with	O
	infinite	O
	potential	O
	","	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	join	O
	a	O
	gang	O
	of	O
	robbers	O
	after	O
	he	O
	drooped	O
	out	O
	of	O
	school	O
	when	O
	he	O
	was	O
	in	O
	form	O
	III	O
	.	O
	St	B-ORG
	.	I-ORG
	Paul	I-ORG
	in	O
	the	O
	year	O
	2007	O
	.	O
	The	O
	boy	O
	did	O
	not	O
	want	O
	to	O
	go	O
	to	O
	school	O
	again	O
	because	O
	the	O
	company	O
	he	O
	had	O
	joined	O
	.	O
	His	O
	parents	O
	were	O
	very	O
	rich	O
	and	O
	they	O
	did	O
	not	O
	want	O
	any	O
	child	O
	to	O
	drop	O
	out	O
	of	O
	school	O
	because	O
	they	O
	were	O
	full	O
	of	O
	everything	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	Njuguna	B-MINR
	decided	O
	to	O
	travel	O
	out	O
	of	O
	the	O
	country	O
	and	O
	went	O
	to	O
	Australia	B-LOC
	without	O
	informing	O
	his	O
	parents	O
	there	O
	in	O
	Australia	B-LOC
	the	O
	boy	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	broke	O
	into	O
	neighbours	O
	houses	O
	where	O
	he	O
	steals	O
	many	O
	things	O
	.	O
	Then	O
	later	O
	the	O
	neighbours	O
	took	O
	him	O
	to	O
	the	O
	jailed	O
	.	O
	Three	O
	days	O
	ago	O
	his	O
	parents	O
	were	O
	searching	O
	for	O
	her	O
	but	O
	he	O
	was	O
	no	O
	where	O
	to	O
	be	O
	found	O
	then	O
	later	O
	the	O
	braking	O
	news	O
	came	O
	that	O
	the	O
	child	O
	was	O
	jailed	O
	.	O
	They	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	go	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	what	O
	was	O
	needed	O
	and	O
	their	O
	child	O
	was	O
	found	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	She	O
	could	O
	be	O
	a	O
	drunkard	O
	","	O
	there	O
	's	O
	a	O
	couple	O
	that	O
	spent	O
	the	O
	entire	O
	night	O
	at	O
	a	O
	club	O
	the	O
	other	O
	Saturday	O
	.	O
	Nothing	O
	weird	O
	about	O
	that	O
	.	O
	That	O
	's	O
	what	O
	Saturday	O
	are	O
	for	O
	clubbing	O
	","	O
	drinking	O
	and	O
	maybe	O
	a	O
	little	O
	hanky	O
	panky	O
	later	O
	on	O
	.	O
	This	O
	particular	O
	couple	O
	however	O
	spent	O
	the	O
	entire	O
	night	O
	staring	O
	into	O
	each	O
	other	O
	's	O
	eyes	O
	and	O
	holding	O
	hands	O
	like	O
	a	O
	pair	O
	of	O
	high	O
	school	O
	love	O
	birds	O
	.	O
	How	O
	nice	O
	!	O
	Unfortunately	O
	","	O
	they	O
	both	O
	happen	O
	to	O
	be	O
	certified	O
	drunkards	O
	","	O
	Mututho	B-ADLT
	's	O
	damnable	O
	law	O
	notwithstanding	O
	.	O
	The	O
	dude	O
	was	O
	on	O
	Tusker	O
	and	O
	the	O
	lady	O
	on	O
	something	O
	imported	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	In	O
	kibera	B-LOC
	there	O
	is	O
	a	O
	club	O
	known	O
	as	O
	OB	B-ORG
	-	I-ORG
	OG	I-ORG
	club	I-ORG
	which	O
	is	O
	located	O
	in	O
	mashimoni	B-ORG
	Magoso	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	OB	B-ORG
	-	I-ORG
	OG	I-ORG
	club	I-ORG
	educates	O
	young	O
	girls	O
	and	O
	boys	O
	from	O
	primary	O
	school	O
	to	O
	secondary	O
	school	O
	.	O
	The	O
	club	O
	is	O
	changing	O
	the	O
	lives	O
	of	O
	many	O
	youths	O
	and	O
	some	O
	of	O
	those	O
	who	O
	were	O
	educated	O
	by	O
	this	O
	club	O
	are	O
	now	O
	big	O
	people	O
	and	O
	have	O
	jobs	O
	.	O
	Apart	O
	from	O
	educating	O
	people	O
	it	O
	also	O
	entails	O
	singing	O
	","	O
	dancing	O
	and	O
	recording	O
	the	O
	songs	O
	in	O
	CDs	O
	and	O
	tapes	O
	.	O
	OB	B-ORG
	-	I-ORG
	OG	I-ORG
	club	I-ORG
	is	O
	managed	O
	by	O
	a	O
	Japanese	O
	woman	O
	who	O
	loves	O
	young	O
	boys	O
	and	O
	girls	O
	.	O
	This	O
	club	O
	also	O
	educate	O
	","	O
	feed	O
	and	O
	help	O
	orphans	O
	because	O
	it	O
	has	O
	one	O
	branch	O
	of	O
	orphans	O
	.	O
	The	O
	big	O
	people	O
	from	O
	eighteen	O
	years	O
	and	O
	above	O
	are	O
	also	O
	taught	O
	carpentry	O
	","	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	awareness	O
	and	O
	there	O
	is	O
	a	O
	tailoring	O
	and	O
	computer	O
	classes	O
	going	O
	on	O
	in	O
	the	O
	compound	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Kanyeki	B-MINR
	was	O
	a	O
	student	O
	at	O
	Olkesuke	B-ORG
	primary	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	","	O
	he	O
	then	O
	graduated	O
	and	O
	called	O
	to	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	preforming	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	Rift	B-LOC
	valley	I-LOC
	known	O
	as	O
	Olkejuado	B-ORG
	High	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	.	O
	Due	O
	t	O
	financial	O
	instability	O
	her	O
	parent	O
	would	O
	not	O
	afford	O
	the	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	for	O
	his	O
	course	O
	at	O
	high	O
	school	O
	","	O
	so	O
	every	O
	time	O
	he	O
	was	O
	usually	O
	sent	O
	home	O
	for	O
	fees	O
	.	O
	By	O
	the	O
	third	O
	year	O
	course	O
	he	O
	had	O
	a	O
	balance	O
	of	O
	forty	O
	eight	O
	thousand	O
	","	O
	which	O
	the	O
	school	O
	would	O
	not	O
	withstand	O
	with	O
	him	O
	with	O
	a	O
	such	O
	balance	O
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	sent	O
	home	O
	","	O
	where	O
	he	O
	had	O
	only	O
	a	O
	single	O
	parent	O
	cause	O
	the	O
	father	O
	had	O
	died	O
	long	O
	ago	O
	since	O
	he	O
	was	O
	in	O
	primary	O
	level	O
	.	O
	due	O
	to	O
	this	O
	her	O
	mother	O
	was	O
	forced	O
	to	O
	go	O
	and	O
	smash	O
	stone	O
	","	O
	which	O
	she	O
	sold	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	for	O
	kanyekis	B-MINR
	fee	O
	.	O
	During	O
	the	O
	year	O
	Kanyeki	B-MINR
	was	O
	unable	O
	to	O
	be	O
	paid	O
	for	O
	the	O
	fees	O
	for	O
	the	O
	fourth	O
	course	O
	.	O
	He	O
	therefore	O
	explained	O
	the	O
	problem	O
	to	O
	the	O
	class	O
	teacher	O
	and	O
	the	O
	class	O
	teacher	O
	told	O
	the	O
	principal	O
	","	O
	by	O
	which	O
	the	O
	principal	O
	refused	O
	and	O
	after	O
	this	O
	information	O
	came	O
	to	O
	the	O
	recognition	O
	of	O
	the	O
	teacher	O
	","	O
	he	O
	was	O
	contributed	O
	for	O
	those	O
	fees	O
	.	O
	After	O
	the	O
	results	O
	Kanyeki	B-MINR
	emerged	O
	the	O
	top	O
	in	O
	the	O
	Rift	B-LOC
	-	I-LOC
	Valley	I-LOC
	province	I-LOC
	which	O
	in	O
	our	O
	surprise	O
	was	O
	all	O
	away	O
	from	O
	school	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	Kanyeki	B-MINR
	has	O
	been	O
	taken	O
	By	O
	equity	B-ORG
	to	O
	work	O
	before	O
	proceeding	O
	to	O
	a	O
	more	O
	higher	O
	learning	O
	institution	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Over	O
	the	O
	past	O
	two	O
	months	O
	","	O
	through	O
	the	O
	media	O
	from	O
	different	O
	persons	O
	","	O
	newspapers	O
	made	O
	crystal	O
	clear	O
	that	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	is	O
	starving	O
	.	O
	In	O
	the	O
	past	O
	it	O
	has	O
	been	O
	up	O
	to	O
	the	O
	government	O
	but	O
	this	O
	time	O
	round	O
	it	O
	is	O
	another	O
	case	O
	where	O
	by	O
	people	O
	.	O
	bob	B-ADLT
	Cullimore	I-ADLT
	Safaricom	B-ORG
	CEO	O
	came	O
	out	O
	in	O
	the	O
	awake	O
	Kenyans	O
	and	O
	shared	O
	and	O
	showed	O
	them	O
	how	O
	to	O
	solve	O
	their	O
	own	O
	problems	O
	and	O
	solutions	O
	he	O
	has	O
	been	O
	able	O
	to	O
	mobilize	O
	Kenyans	O
	through	O
	his	O
	move	O
	of	O
	Kenya	B-ORG
	for	I-ORG
	Kenyans	I-ORG
	where	O
	they	O
	have	O
	group	O
	sourced	O
	donations	O
	to	O
	buy	O
	food	O
	and	O
	feed	O
	the	O
	people	O
	at	O
	turkland	B-LOC
	who	O
	we	O
	are	O
	faced	O
	with	O
	hunger	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Prisca	B-ADLT
	Awinja	I-ADLT
	brought	O
	a	O
	project	O
	(	O
	KRA	B-ORG
	)	O
	","	O
	Kenya	B-ORG
	Rain	I-ORG
	water	I-ORG
	Association	I-ORG
	to	O
	help	O
	the	O
	community	O
	in	O
	conservation	O
	of	O
	water	O
	.	O
	The	O
	project	O
	was	O
	funded	O
	by	O
	Swedish	B-ORG
	International	I-ORG
	Development	I-ORG
	Agency	I-ORG
	.	O
	The	O
	project	O
	helped	O
	the	O
	community	O
	through	O
	the	O
	support	O
	of	O
	the	O
	founder	O
	to	O
	build	O
	tankers	O
	in	O
	order	O
	to	O
	conserve	O
	rainwater	O
	for	O
	domestic	O
	use	O
	.	O
	Over	O
	three	O
	thousand	O
	villagers	O
	benefited	O
	from	O
	the	O
	project	O
	.	O
	the	O
	project	O
	took	O
	place	O
	in	O
	Rongo	B-LOC
	constituency	I-LOC
	","	I-LOC
	Migori	I-LOC
	County	I-LOC
	","	I-LOC
	Nyanza	I-LOC
	province	I-LOC
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	There	O
	was	O
	a	O
	boy	O
	living	O
	up	O
	country	O
	by	O
	a	O
	name	O
	called	O
	Washington	B-MINR
	Ochieng	I-MINR
	.	O
	His	O
	parents	O
	died	O
	when	O
	he	O
	was	O
	still	O
	young	O
	.	O
	But	O
	CARE	B-ORG
	KENYA	I-ORG
	has	O
	helped	O
	him	O
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	a	O
	good	O
	health	O
	CARE	B-ORG
	KENYA	I-ORG
	has	O
	also	O
	paid	O
	for	O
	him	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	since	O
	Baby	O
	class	O
	up	O
	to	O
	now	O
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	been	O
	given	O
	shoes	O
	","	O
	uniform	O
	and	O
	bag	O
	.	O
	''	O
	The	O
	boy	O
	thanks	O
	CARE	B-ORG
	KENYA	I-ORG
	for	O
	what	O
	they	O
	have	O
	done	O
	for	O
	him	O
	.	O
	He	O
	also	O
	tells	O
	them	O
	to	O
	continue	O
	helping	O
	other	O
	children	O
	who	O
	needs	O
	their	O
	help	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	the	O
	boy	O
	is	O
	in	O
	class	O
	one	O
	","	O
	next	O
	year	O
	he	O
	will	O
	be	O
	in	O
	class	O
	two	O
	","	O
	he	O
	asked	O
	the	O
	CARE	B-ORG
	KENYA	I-ORG
	to	O
	pay	O
	for	O
	him	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	until	O
	when	O
	he	O
	will	O
	finish	O
	EDUCATION	O
	.	O
	May	O
	the	O
	Lord	O
	be	O
	with	O
	you	O
	CARE	B-ORG
	KENYA	I-ORG
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Wahu	B-ADLT
	and	O
	Nameless	B-ADLT
	are	O
	couples	O
	and	O
	musicians	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	also	O
	choose	O
	as	O
	ambassador	O
	for	O
	Kenyans	B-ORG
	for	I-ORG
	the	I-ORG
	Kenya	I-ORG
	initiative	I-ORG
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	artists	O
	whom	O
	are	O
	recognized	O
	worldwide	O
	because	O
	of	O
	songs	O
	they	O
	compose	O
	and	O
	release	O
	them	O
	.	O
	They	O
	have	O
	shown	O
	their	O
	kind	O
	heart	O
	when	O
	they	O
	were	O
	donating	O
	food	O
	to	O
	North	B-LOC
	Eastern	I-LOC
	of	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	apart	O
	from	O
	singing	O
	generation	O
	have	O
	known	O
	them	O
	because	O
	of	O
	the	O
	generosity	O
	.	O
	They	O
	have	O
	shown	O
	their	O
	face	O
	to	O
	the	O
	Turkana	B-ORG
	tribe	I-ORG
	and	O
	lecture	O
	Turkana	B-LOC
	residents	O
	on	O
	how	O
	to	O
	invest	O
	and	O
	start	O
	irrigating	O
	to	O
	their	O
	community	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	what	O
	the	O
	to	O
	couples	O
	have	O
	been	O
	spending	O
	time	O
	roaming	O
	around	O
	but	O
	with	O
	a	O
	moderation	O
	of	O
	willing	O
	to	O
	help	O
	Kenyans	O
	and	O
	building	O
	our	O
	country	O
	to	O
	be	O
	time	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	","	O
	once	O
	one	O
	guy	O
	said	O
	the	O
	good	O
	we	O
	do	O
	today	O
	it	O
	becomes	O
	better	O
	tomorrow	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Wangari	B-ADLT
	Mathai	I-ADLT
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	women	O
	who	O
	made	O
	our	O
	environment	O
	decorative	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	born	O
	in	O
	1940	O
	in	O
	Ihithe	O
	village	O
	at	O
	Nyeri	B-LOC
	she	O
	was	O
	educated	O
	in	O
	the	O
	United	B-LOC
	States	I-LOC
	at	O
	Mount	B-LOC
	St.	I-LOC
	Scholastica	I-LOC
	and	O
	the	O
	university	B-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	Pittsburgh	I-ORG
	as	O
	well	O
	as	O
	university	B-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	Nairobi	I-ORG
	in	O
	1970	O
	she	O
	founded	O
	a	O
	Green	B-ORG
	Belt	I-ORG
	Movement	I-ORG
	a	O
	non	O
	governmental	O
	organisation	O
	focused	O
	on	O
	environmental	O
	and	O
	women	O
	's	O
	rights	O
	.	O
	In	O
	1984	O
	she	O
	was	O
	awarded	O
	the	O
	right	O
	livelihood	O
	and	O
	in	O
	2004	O
	she	O
	became	O
	the	O
	first	O
	African	O
	woman	O
	to	O
	receive	O
	the	O
	Nobel	B-ORG
	prize	I-ORG
	for	O
	her	O
	contribution	O
	to	O
	sustainable	O
	development	O
	democracy	O
	and	O
	peace	O
	she	O
	has	O
	shown	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	the	O
	importance	O
	of	O
	preserving	O
	the	O
	environment	O
	she	O
	is	O
	so	O
	wonderful	O
	and	O
	merciful	O
	to	O
	give	O
	our	O
	country	O
	what	O
	it	O
	deserves	O
	and	O
	make	O
	it	O
	look	O
	beautiful	O
	.	O
	Thank	O
	you	O
	to	O
	our	O
	mother	O
	Wangari	B-ADLT
	Mathai	I-ADLT
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Why	O
	the	O
	African	B-ORG
	union	I-ORG
	failed	O
	to	O
	deliver	O
	an	O
	any	O
	of	O
	its	O
	objectives	O
	?	O
	The	O
	53	O
	members	O
	of	O
	the	O
	AU	B-ORG
	recently	O
	met	O
	in	O
	Addis	B-LOC
	Ababa	I-LOC
	","	I-LOC
	Ethiopia	I-LOC
	for	O
	its	O
	16th	O
	Ordinary	O
	Session	O
	of	O
	the	O
	summit	O
	of	O
	Heads	O
	of	O
	states	O
	and	O
	government	O
	.	O
	Due	O
	to	O
	political	O
	standoff	O
	in	O
	Ivory	B-LOC
	Coast	I-LOC
	crisis	O
	in	O
	the	O
	continent	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	a	O
	clear	O
	pointer	O
	that	O
	the	O
	organisation	O
	has	O
	not	O
	fully	O
	played	O
	its	O
	role	O
	of	O
	helping	O
	to	O
	address	O
	Africa	B-LOC
	's	O
	challenges	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	at	O
	times	O
	we	O
	have	O
	heard	O
	of	O
	people	O
	displaced	O
	mainly	O
	because	O
	of	O
	land	O
	issues	O
	.	O
	Land	O
	always	O
	been	O
	a	O
	key	O
	issue	O
	to	O
	those	O
	of	O
	those	O
	that	O
	have	O
	displaced	O
	or	O
	those	O
	are	O
	having	O
	land	O
	disputes	O
	.	O
	Migingo	B-LOC
	is	O
	a	O
	land	O
	situated	O
	in	O
	the	O
	boarder	O
	of	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	and	O
	Uganda	B-LOC
	and	O
	its	O
	an	O
	island	O
	(	O
	Ugingo	B-LOC
	island	I-LOC
	)	O
	surrounding	O
	by	O
	lake	B-LOC
	Victoria	I-LOC
	.	O
	Both	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	and	O
	Uganda	B-LOC
	residents	O
	claim	O
	that	O
	the	O
	land	O
	is	O
	there	O
	and	O
	for	O
	some	O
	time	O
	both	O
	country	O
	have	O
	been	O
	fighting	O
	over	O
	this	O
	land	O
	.	O
	This	O
	has	O
	constantly	O
	made	O
	the	O
	residents	O
	of	O
	that	O
	area	O
	to	O
	be	O
	frightened	O
	cause	O
	there	O
	is	O
	tension	O
	in	O
	the	O
	area	O
	since	O
	both	O
	country	O
	keep	O
	fighting	O
	over	O
	the	O
	land	O
	even	O
	brought	O
	their	O
	forces	O
	to	O
	guard	O
	their	O
	land	O
	.	O
	Recently	O
	there	O
	was	O
	a	O
	need	O
	to	O
	settle	O
	the	O
	water	O
	and	O
	the	O
	two	O
	leaders	O
	representing	O
	countries	O
	wet	O
	and	O
	talked	O
	over	O
	the	O
	issue	O
	","	O
	they	O
	promised	O
	to	O
	maintain	O
	peace	O
	and	O
	did	O
	a	O
	survey	O
	to	O
	really	O
	identify	O
	where	O
	Migingo	B-LOC
	and	O
	Ugingo	B-LOC
	island	I-LOC
	is	O
	this	O
	settling	O
	the	O
	issue	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	Kenya	B-ORG
	Red	I-ORG
	Cross	I-ORG
	is	O
	an	O
	humanitarian	O
	relief	O
	organisation	O
	which	O
	prepares	O
	people	O
	for	O
	emergencies	O
	and	O
	keep	O
	people	O
	safe	O
	everyday	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	come	O
	to	O
	the	O
	rescue	O
	of	O
	many	O
	tragedies	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	For	O
	instance	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	during	O
	the	O
	blast	O
	red	B-ORG
	cross	I-ORG
	released	O
	its	O
	workers	O
	to	O
	rescue	O
	the	O
	victims	O
	during	O
	post	O
	election	O
	violence	O
	it	O
	helped	O
	the	O
	IDPs	O
	.	O
	That	O
	s	O
	not	O
	enough	O
	in	O
	the	O
	current	O
	situation	O
	of	O
	the	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	for	O
	Kenyans	O
	are	O
	donating	O
	money	O
	food	O
	for	O
	thousand	O
	of	O
	people	O
	who	O
	were	O
	dying	O
	of	O
	hunger	O
	at	O
	Turkana	B-ORG
	.	O
	In	O
	line	O
	to	O
	this	O
	it	O
	has	O
	launched	O
	a	O
	drought	O
	initiative	O
	targeting	O
	to	O
	raise	O
	1	O
	.	O
	9	O
	million	O
	shillings	O
	to	O
	help	O
	1	O
	.	O
	8	O
	beneficiaries	O
	in	O
	the	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	for	O
	Kenya	B-ORG
	initiative	I-ORG
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Chiaki	B-ADLT
	hayakawa	I-ADLT
	has	O
	been	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	ambassadors	O
	in	O
	Magoso	B-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	for	I-ORG
	Education	I-ORG
	.	O
	She	O
	always	O
	see	O
	to	O
	it	O
	that	O
	children	O
	get	O
	not	O
	only	O
	Education	O
	but	O
	quality	O
	Education	O
	.	O
	She	O
	has	O
	incorporated	O
	some	O
	of	O
	her	O
	friends	O
	from	O
	her	O
	home	O
	County	O
	who	O
	act	O
	as	O
	sponsor	O
	to	O
	students	O
	who	O
	perform	O
	well	O
	in	O
	K.	B-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	P.	I-OTHR
	E.	I-OTHR
	especially	O
	the	O
	needy	O
	people	O
	and	O
	children	O
	from	O
	a	O
	very	O
	poor	O
	background	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	It	O
	was	O
	during	O
	the	O
	election	O
	of	O
	2007	O
	when	O
	there	O
	was	O
	clashes	O
	all	O
	over	O
	the	O
	country	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	lost	O
	their	O
	life	O
	and	O
	their	O
	beloved	O
	ones	O
	others	O
	were	O
	left	O
	homeless	O
	without	O
	knowing	O
	where	O
	to	O
	start	O
	a	O
	new	O
	life	O
	.	O
	Over	O
	a	O
	thousands	O
	children	O
	become	O
	orphans	O
	","	O
	but	O
	other	O
	people	O
	did	O
	not	O
	see	O
	that	O
	they	O
	continued	O
	fighting	O
	over	O
	and	O
	over	O
	.	O
	There	O
	was	O
	no	O
	peace	O
	in	O
	the	O
	country	O
	although	O
	some	O
	people	O
	tried	O
	their	O
	best	O
	to	O
	bring	O
	peace	O
	but	O
	all	O
	was	O
	in	O
	vain	O
	","	O
	even	O
	some	O
	churches	O
	tried	O
	but	O
	there	O
	was	O
	still	O
	no	O
	change	O
	instead	O
	it	O
	turned	O
	over	O
	to	O
	them	O
	again	O
	.	O
	I	O
	remember	O
	when	O
	someone	O
	came	O
	to	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	by	O
	president	O
	Obama	B-ADLT
	to	O
	come	O
	and	O
	make	O
	peace	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	When	O
	he	O
	come	O
	to	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	he	O
	sat	O
	down	O
	with	O
	all	O
	leader	O
	and	O
	tried	O
	to	O
	make	O
	the	O
	negotiated	O
	to	O
	each	O
	other	O
	.	O
	He	O
	made	O
	peace	O
	between	O
	him	O
	Raila	B-ADLT
	and	O
	Prudential	O
	Kibaki	B-ADLT
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Since	O
	Kofi	B-ADLT
	Astop-x	I-ADLT
	came	O
	to	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	the	O
	was	O
	at	O
	least	O
	some	O
	change	O
	from	O
	clashes	O
	.	O
	The	O
	arrival	O
	of	O
	Kofi	B-ADLT
	Astop-x	I-ADLT
	made	O
	our	O
	country	O
	to	O
	live	O
	at	O
	least	O
	with	O
	some	O
	peace	O
	.	O
	Several	O
	years	O
	now	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	famine	O
	crisis	O
	has	O
	become	O
	a	O
	very	O
	crucial	O
	thing	O
	Eastern	B-LOC
	and	O
	northern	O
	part	O
	of	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	have	O
	died	O
	due	O
	to	O
	starvation	O
	thus	O
	making	O
	the	O
	population	O
	of	O
	the	O
	parts	O
	decrease	O
	drastically	O
	.	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	all	O
	the	O
	country	O
	site	O
	have	O
	come	O
	together	O
	to	O
	help	O
	those	O
	in	O
	need	O
	of	O
	their	O
	cash	O
	by	O
	initiating	O
	a	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	forum	O
	which	O
	will	O
	contribute	O
	toward	O
	helping	O
	them	O
	.	O
	This	O
	initiative	O
	helps	O
	an	O
	any	O
	way	O
	possible	O
	even	O
	the	O
	children	O
	can	O
	contribute	O
	with	O
	10	O
	shillings	O
	.	O
	The	O
	money	O
	contributed	O
	will	O
	help	O
	in	O
	bring	O
	food	O
	for	O
	the	O
	people	O
	living	O
	in	O
	those	O
	areas	O
	and	O
	also	O
	building	O
	irrigation	O
	schemes	O
	which	O
	will	O
	serve	O
	as	O
	a	O
	long	O
	term	O
	solution	O
	for	O
	those	O
	people	O
	to	O
	reduce	O
	the	O
	cases	O
	of	O
	starvation	O
	in	O
	the	O
	deserted	O
	and	O
	not	O
	well	O
	fertile	O
	areas	O
	.	O
	Food	O
	and	O
	water	O
	has	O
	been	O
	transported	O
	to	O
	those	O
	area	O
	hence	O
	helping	O
	in	O
	sustaining	O
	their	O
	lives	O
	for	O
	a	O
	shorter	O
	period	O
	of	O
	time	O
	thus	O
	need	O
	for	O
	a	O
	long	O
	term	O
	solution	O
	which	O
	has	O
	just	O
	started	O
	recently	O
	by	O
	constructing	O
	borehole	O
	sand	O
	also	O
	irrigation	O
	schemes	O
	for	O
	that	O
	particular	O
	matter	O
	involved	O
	.	O
	all	O
	along	O
	this	O
	period	O
	of	O
	contributing	O
	have	O
	shown	O
	that	O
	they	O
	have	O
	a	O
	heart	O
	of	O
	helping	O
	others	O
	and	O
	their	O
	neighbours	O
	and	O
	country	O
	men	O
	at	O
	large	O
	.	O
	With	O
	the	O
	resources	O
	we	O
	have	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	it	O
	is	O
	well	O
	","	O
	able	O
	for	O
	the	O
	government	O
	to	O
	feed	O
	its	O
	own	O
	country	O
	men	O
	without	O
	looking	O
	for	O
	aids	O
	from	O
	other	O
	countries	O
	who	O
	we	O
	are	O
	so	O
	grateful	O
	they	O
	are	O
	doing	O
	so	O
	and	O
	may	O
	God	O
	continue	O
	to	O
	bless	O
	them	O
	and	O
	increase	O
	them	O
	with	O
	the	O
	resourcefulness	O
	they	O
	have	O
	thus	O
	help	O
	in	O
	contributing	O
	to	O
	other	O
	countries	O
	as	O
	well	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	If	O
	someone	O
	has	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	Aid	O
	he	O
	need	O
	care	O
	","	O
	support	O
	and	O
	to	O
	be	O
	helped	O
	by	O
	someone	O
	.	O
	If	O
	you	O
	do	O
	not	O
	help	O
	someone	O
	suffering	O
	from	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AID	O
	he	O
	might	O
	die	O
	and	O
	you	O
	might	O
	go	O
	to	O
	person	O
	or	O
	suffer	O
	the	O
	consequences	O
	.	O
	my	O
	friend	O
	Kevin	B-ADLT
	his	O
	uncle	O
	he	O
	is	O
	suffering	O
	from	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	affected	O
	with	O
	AIDs	O
	two	O
	thousand	O
	and	O
	eight	O
	this	O
	sickness	O
	has	O
	been	O
	very	O
	bad	O
	and	O
	harmful	O
	even	O
	if	O
	has	O
	beed	O
	given	O
	to	O
	children	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	the	O
	government	O
	has	O
	been	O
	taking	O
	care	O
	of	O
	this	O
	people	O
	but	O
	they	O
	ca	O
	not	O
	help	O
	them	O
	to	O
	go	O
	out	O
	of	O
	this	O
	country	O
	so	O
	that	O
	they	O
	can	O
	get	O
	treatment	O
	for	O
	their	O
	own	O
	money	O
	and	O
	for	O
	them	O
	to	O
	get	O
	more	O
	treatment	O
	.	O
	If	O
	the	O
	government	O
	had	O
	been	O
	tacking	O
	care	O
	of	O
	these	O
	people	O
	suffering	O
	from	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	some	O
	of	O
	them	O
	could	O
	be	O
	now	O
	well	O
	and	O
	happy	O
	to	O
	know	O
	that	O
	their	O
	are	O
	people	O
	taking	O
	care	O
	of	O
	them	O
	and	O
	they	O
	can	O
	be	O
	very	O
	very	O
	good	O
	to	O
	stay	O
	with	O
	their	O
	family	O
	and	O
	to	O
	be	O
	with	O
	their	O
	relatives	O
	in	O
	the	O
	up	O
	-	O
	country	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	In	O
	slums	O
	areas	O
	we	O
	had	O
	many	O
	talented	O
	children	O
	including	O
	footballers	O
	though	O
	it	O
	has	O
	been	O
	so	O
	brutal	O
	to	O
	see	O
	that	O
	this	O
	children	O
	have	O
	been	O
	not	O
	exposed	O
	and	O
	boasted	O
	their	O
	talent	O
	indeed	O
	they	O
	do	O
	not	O
	have	O
	someone	O
	to	O
	support	O
	them	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	why	O
	Airtel	B-ORG
	and	O
	Mathare	B-ORG
	youth	I-ORG
	sports	I-ORG
	association	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	MYSA	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	have	O
	considered	O
	and	O
	come	O
	up	O
	with	O
	a	O
	strategy	O
	of	O
	progressing	O
	sports	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	they	O
	have	O
	add	O
	more	O
	perhaps	O
	in	O
	slum	O
	areas	O
	they	O
	have	O
	provided	O
	alot	O
	including	O
	Jerseys	O
	balls	O
	and	O
	more	O
	","	O
	it	O
	has	O
	been	O
	like	O
	fulfilling	O
	the	O
	desire	O
	of	O
	Kenyans	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	what	O
	mysa	B-ORG
	and	O
	airtel	B-ORG
	are	O
	fascinating	O
	are	O
	focusing	O
	is	O
	to	O
	build	O
	more	O
	fields	O
	for	O
	sports	O
	and	O
	to	O
	be	O
	more	O
	fascinating	O
	and	O
	complementing	O
	.	O
	They	O
	have	O
	shown	O
	generosity	O
	to	O
	us	O
	and	O
	Kenyans	O
	should	O
	repay	O
	them	O
	by	O
	showing	O
	their	O
	talents	O
	and	O
	playing	O
	hard	O
	so	O
	that	O
	next	O
	time	O
	they	O
	will	O
	deliver	O
	something	O
	greater	O
	than	O
	before	O
	.	O
	But	O
	where	O
	we	O
	are	O
	Kenyans	O
	had	O
	shown	O
	something	O
	where	O
	three	O
	players	O
	of	O
	Kenyan	O
	are	O
	playing	O
	abroad	O
	and	O
	that	O
	has	O
	been	O
	fabulous	O
	and	O
	also	O
	making	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	name	O
	to	O
	shine	O
	world	O
	wide	O
	.	O
	This	O
	all	O
	is	O
	because	O
	of	O
	MYSA	B-ORG
	and	O
	Airtel	B-ORG
	and	O
	their	O
	reward	O
	is	O
	by	O
	showing	O
	them	O
	what	O
	we	O
	are	O
	","	O
	showcasing	O
	our	O
	talent	O
	fully	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Ashley	B-ORG
	beauty	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	is	O
	the	O
	main	O
	sponsor	O
	of	O
	miss	B-ORG
	world	I-ORG
	Kenya	I-ORG
	what	O
	they	O
	do	O
	is	O
	they	O
	give	O
	a	O
	chance	O
	to	O
	all	O
	Kenyan	O
	girls	O
	who	O
	have	O
	an	O
	interest	O
	to	O
	model	O
	.	O
	During	O
	this	O
	year	O
	's	O
	miss	B-ORG
	world	I-ORG
	Ashley	I-ORG
	's	O
	CEO	O
	awarded	O
	Rose	B-ADLT
	the	O
	miss	O
	hope	O
	crown	O
	therefore	O
	making	O
	her	O
	a	O
	model	O
	.	O
	Among	O
	those	O
	awarded	O
	too	O
	is	O
	a	O
	young	O
	girl	O
	who	O
	went	O
	to	O
	class	O
	4	O
	but	O
	had	O
	a	O
	dropout	O
	because	O
	of	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	.	O
	Because	O
	of	O
	her	O
	sincerity	O
	to	O
	share	O
	her	O
	story	O
	with	O
	Kenyans	O
	she	O
	was	O
	awarded	O
	a	O
	scholarship	O
	by	O
	Ashley	B-ORG
	to	O
	study	O
	beauty	O
	.	O
	They	O
	have	O
	awakened	O
	so	O
	many	O
	dreams	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Look	O
	forward	O
	for	O
	what	O
	lies	O
	ahead	O
	and	O
	not	O
	look	O
	backward	O
	on	O
	what	O
	lies	O
	behind	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	has	O
	started	O
	to	O
	be	O
	city	O
	everywhere	O
	even	O
	in	O
	rural	O
	areas	O
	members	O
	of	O
	parliament	O
	have	O
	constructed	O
	tarmac	O
	road	O
	health	O
	centres	O
	school	O
	where	O
	education	O
	is	O
	found	O
	and	O
	more	O
	of	O
	developing	O
	.	O
	If	O
	you	O
	look	O
	MP	O
	of	O
	Butere	B-LOC
	/	O
	mumias	B-ADLT
	wycliff	I-ADLT
	oparanya	I-ADLT
	has	O
	done	O
	more	O
	potential	O
	in	O
	Butere	B-LOC
	district	I-LOC
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	considered	O
	top	O
	five	O
	using	O
	CDF	B-ORG
	money	O
	for	O
	construction	O
	schools	O
	and	O
	hospitals	O
	.	O
	He	O
	is	O
	also	O
	a	O
	minister	O
	of	O
	planning	O
	.	O
	MPs	O
	are	O
	the	O
	same	O
	everywhere	O
	even	O
	where	O
	there	O
	is	O
	a	O
	road	O
	they	O
	promise	O
	to	O
	built	O
	a	O
	bridge	O
	but	O
	Hon	B-ADLT
	.	I-ADLT
	Oparanya	I-ADLT
	he	O
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	best	O
	MP	O
	I	O
	've	O
	ever	O
	seen	O
	.	O
	He	O
	is	O
	ready	O
	to	O
	give	O
	anything	O
	and	O
	make	O
	someone	O
	to	O
	be	O
	somebody	O
	in	O
	his	O
	or	O
	her	O
	community	O
	he	O
	is	O
	beloved	O
	MP	O
	in	O
	Butare	B-LOC
	district	I-LOC
	and	O
	he	O
	is	O
	investing	O
	more	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Music	O
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	ways	O
	in	O
	which	O
	people	O
	communicate	O
	.	O
	Some	O
	of	O
	the	O
	songs	O
	have	O
	a	O
	message	O
	in	O
	which	O
	it	O
	has	O
	helped	O
	many	O
	Kenyans	O
	.	O
	Some	O
	of	O
	the	O
	songs	O
	have	O
	a	O
	message	O
	in	O
	which	O
	it	O
	has	O
	helped	O
	many	O
	Kenyans	O
	to	O
	help	O
	one	O
	another	O
	and	O
	live	O
	like	O
	brothers	O
	and	O
	sisters	O
	.	O
	These	O
	songs	O
	are	O
	to	O
	educate	O
	Kenyans	O
	.	O
	Some	O
	songs	O
	have	O
	educated	O
	Kenyans	O
	about	O
	various	O
	diseases	O
	such	O
	as	O
	AIDS	O
	and	O
	STIS	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	educated	O
	many	O
	Kenyans	O
	about	O
	the	O
	EFFECTS	O
	of	O
	DRUGS	O
	.	O
	EKO	B-ADLT
	DIDA	I-ADLT
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	musicians	O
	who	O
	has	O
	encouraged	O
	Kenyans	O
	to	O
	live	O
	a	O
	positive	O
	life	O
	.	O
	For	O
	example	O
	he	O
	has	O
	sang	O
	a	O
	song	O
	called	O
	Ghetto	O
	love	O
	.	O
	This	O
	song	O
	tells	O
	us	O
	that	O
	when	O
	he	O
	Eko	B-ADLT
	Dida	I-ADLT
	saw	O
	the	O
	life	O
	which	O
	people	O
	live	O
	.	O
	He	O
	concluded	O
	to	O
	come	O
	with	O
	a	O
	song	O
	which	O
	educate	O
	people	O
	that	O
	even	O
	the	O
	rich	O
	people	O
	came	O
	from	O
	the	O
	slums	O
	.	O
	So	O
	this	O
	song	O
	tells	O
	us	O
	that	O
	it	O
	is	O
	only	O
	God	O
	who	O
	provides	O
	.	O
	It	O
	also	O
	since	O
	charity	O
	begins	O
	at	O
	home	O
	.	O
	This	O
	song	O
	tells	O
	us	O
	that	O
	we	O
	should	O
	live	O
	in	O
	peace	O
	and	O
	harmony	O
	.	O
	We	O
	should	O
	not	O
	have	O
	tribalism	O
	corruption	O
	and	O
	nepotism	O
	.	O
	I	O
	think	O
	this	O
	man	O
	did	O
	a	O
	great	O
	thing	O
	in	O
	composing	O
	that	O
	song	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	helped	O
	many	O
	Kenyans	O
	to	O
	live	O
	in	O
	peace	O
	and	O
	harmony	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	In	O
	the	O
	year	O
	of	O
	2009	O
	I	O
	had	O
	finished	O
	my	O
	K.	B-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	P.	I-OTHR
	E.	I-OTHR
	examination	I-OTHR
	and	O
	I	O
	was	O
	anxiously	O
	to	O
	go	O
	to	O
	a	O
	national	O
	school	O
	.	O
	I	O
	passed	O
	the	O
	exams	O
	with	O
	flying	O
	colours	O
	.	O
	I	O
	got	O
	four	O
	hundred	O
	and	O
	three	O
	and	O
	I	O
	was	O
	called	O
	in	O
	Mang'u	B-ORG
	Boys	I-ORG
	high	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	.	O
	but	O
	unfortunately	O
	my	O
	dream	O
	failed	O
	since	O
	my	O
	parents	O
	could	O
	not	O
	pay	O
	my	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	.	O
	That	O
	is	O
	when	O
	my	O
	uncle	O
	who	O
	lived	O
	in	O
	Nairobi	B-LOC
	had	O
	to	O
	admit	O
	me	O
	in	O
	Chavakali	B-ORG
	High	I-ORG
	School	I-ORG
	and	O
	paid	O
	for	O
	my	O
	necessities	O
	up	O
	to	O
	when	O
	he	O
	died	O
	and	O
	there	O
	was	O
	no	O
	any	O
	other	O
	to	O
	continue	O
	with	O
	my	O
	uncles	O
	kindness	O
	.	O
	Within	O
	a	O
	few	O
	months	O
	my	O
	father	O
	was	O
	called	O
	back	O
	to	O
	job	O
	and	O
	was	O
	able	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	my	O
	fee	O
	although	O
	it	O
	was	O
	enough	O
	.	O
	That	O
	is	O
	when	O
	the	O
	principal	O
	Mr.	B-ADLT
	Indimuli	I-ADLT
	started	O
	his	O
	own	O
	project	O
	to	O
	help	O
	those	O
	in	O
	needy	O
	in	O
	our	O
	school	O
	.	O
	From	O
	that	O
	day	O
	on	O
	I	O
	have	O
	no	O
	problem	O
	with	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	and	O
	I	O
	thank	O
	God	O
	for	O
	rescuing	O
	me	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	B-ORG
	federation	I-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	women	I-ORG
	Lawyers	I-ORG
	-	I-ORG
	Kenya	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	FIDA	I-ORG
	kenya	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	a	O
	non	O
	-	O
	profit	O
	","	O
	Non	O
	-	O
	partisan	O
	membership	O
	organisation	O
	through	O
	diverse	O
	interventions	O
	is	O
	committed	O
	to	O
	creating	O
	a	O
	just	O
	society	O
	that	O
	is	O
	tree	O
	of	O
	all	O
	forms	O
	of	O
	discrimination	O
	against	O
	women	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	based	O
	on	O
	the	O
	realization	O
	that	O
	women	O
	form	O
	the	O
	majority	O
	of	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	's	O
	population	O
	play	O
	an	O
	active	O
	and	O
	significant	O
	role	O
	in	O
	the	O
	development	O
	of	O
	society	O
	.	O
	The	O
	women	O
	of	O
	Kakamenga	B-LOC
	were	O
	urged	O
	to	O
	be	O
	open	O
	of	O
	the	O
	challenges	O
	and	O
	face	O
	them	O
	.	O
	With	O
	16	O
	days	O
	of	O
	activism	O
	against	O
	gender	O
	based	O
	violence	O
	with	O
	the	O
	aim	O
	of	O
	stopping	O
	it	O
	cross	O
	the	O
	country	O
	and	O
	Kakamenga	B-LOC
	county	O
	was	O
	not	O
	to	O
	be	O
	left	O
	out	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Due	O
	to	O
	the	O
	widespread	O
	of	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	in	O
	the	O
	country	O
	and	O
	more so	O
	in	O
	the	O
	slums	O
	there	O
	came	O
	a	O
	need	O
	to	O
	educate	O
	the	O
	masses	O
	on	O
	the	O
	proper	O
	need	O
	of	O
	prevention	O
	and	O
	treatment	O
	and	O
	how	O
	to	O
	take	O
	care	O
	of	O
	the	O
	victims	O
	of	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	in	O
	order	O
	to	O
	prevent	O
	spread	O
	of	O
	the	O
	disease	O
	at	O
	an	O
	alarming	O
	rate	O
	in	O
	the	O
	slums	O
	with	O
	the	O
	high	O
	level	O
	of	O
	prostitution	O
	.	O
	That	O
	is	O
	the	O
	order	O
	of	O
	the	O
	day	O
	in	O
	the	O
	slums	O
	.	O
	Due	O
	to	O
	this	O
	Liverpool	B-ORG
	VCT	I-ORG
	launched	O
	a	O
	program	O
	to	O
	create	O
	VCT	O
	in	O
	all	O
	centres	O
	and	O
	part	O
	of	O
	the	O
	slums	O
	in	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	in	O
	order	O
	to	O
	test	O
	medication	O
	and	O
	guidance	O
	on	O
	how	O
	to	O
	deal	O
	with	O
	the	O
	disease	O
	in	O
	the	O
	slum	O
	and	O
	all	O
	parts	O
	so	O
	as	O
	to	O
	control	O
	its	O
	prevention	O
	at	O
	large	O
	.	O
	This	O
	has	O
	led	O
	to	O
	the	O
	reduction	O
	on	O
	the	O
	prevalence	O
	rate	O
	of	O
	the	O
	disease	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Aphial	B-ORG
	is	O
	Organisation	O
	that	O
	create	O
	awareness	O
	about	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	and	O
	takes	O
	care	O
	of	O
	children	O
	who	O
	are	O
	orphans	O
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	aided	O
	by	O
	USAID	B-ORG
	and	O
	a	O
	specific	O
	Programme	O
	in	O
	United	B-ORG
	Nation	I-ORG
	.	O
	It	O
	gives	O
	people	O
	who	O
	are	O
	infected	O
	by	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	a	O
	second	O
	chance	O
	to	O
	live	O
	and	O
	also	O
	increase	O
	their	O
	lifespan	O
	This	O
	Organisation	O
	has	O
	been	O
	in	O
	existence	O
	for	O
	several	O
	years	O
	now	O
	and	O
	many	O
	people	O
	have	O
	been	O
	helped	O
	and	O
	these	O
	same	O
	people	O
	have	O
	gone	O
	out	O
	to	O
	the	O
	World	O
	to	O
	teach	O
	and	O
	encourage	O
	those	O
	infected	O
	to	O
	strongly	O
	live	O
	and	O
	fulfil	O
	their	O
	dreams	O
	and	O
	ambitious	O
	in	O
	life	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	communities	O
	hear	O
	this	O
	Organisation	O
	have	O
	learned	O
	more	O
	than	O
	enough	O
	about	O
	discrimination	O
	of	O
	people	O
	living	O
	with	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	thus	O
	helping	O
	those	O
	living	O
	with	O
	it	O
	and	O
	even	O
	encouraging	O
	them	O
	as	O
	well	O
	.	O
	The	O
	Organisation	O
	takes	O
	care	O
	of	O
	those	O
	affected	O
	by	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	especially	O
	children	O
	left	O
	by	O
	their	O
	parents	O
	who	O
	wee	O
	consumed	O
	by	O
	this	O
	dangerous	O
	animal	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	give	O
	thanks	O
	to	O
	Margret	B-ADLT
	Wanjiru	I-ADLT
	for	O
	what	O
	she	O
	has	O
	done	O
	for	O
	use	O
	in	O
	side	O
	of	O
	roads	O
	.	O
	Accident	O
	was	O
	being	O
	announced	O
	on	O
	the	O
	radio	O
	every	O
	now	O
	and	O
	then	O
	some	O
	goods	O
	could	O
	not	O
	travel	O
	because	O
	of	O
	bad	O
	roads	O
	and	O
	they	O
	could	O
	cause	O
	accident	O
	to	O
	some	O
	people	O
	in	O
	the	O
	country	O
	Look	O
	some	O
	where	O
	like	O
	Eastleigh	B-LOC
	and	O
	huruma	B-LOC
	mathare	I-LOC
	is	O
	construction	O
	of	O
	roads	O
	and	O
	even	O
	in	O
	some	O
	other	O
	places	O
	here	O
	Nairobi	B-LOC
	roads	O
	have	O
	been	O
	made	O
	well	O
	so	O
	I	O
	can	O
	say	O
	that	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	has	O
	changed	O
	in	O
	side	O
	of	O
	roads	O
	.	O
	In	O
	Huruma	B-LOC
	state	I-LOC
	no	O
	cars	O
	could	O
	pass	O
	through	O
	these	O
	way	O
	because	O
	it	O
	was	O
	poorly	O
	constructed	O
	but	O
	now	O
	it	O
	has	O
	improved	O
	and	O
	one	O
	can	O
	say	O
	that	O
	she	O
	is	O
	not	O
	doing	O
	her	O
	work	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	President	B-ADLT
	Mzee	I-ADLT
	Jomo	I-ADLT
	Kenyatta	I-ADLT
	Was	O
	a	O
	respected	O
	well	O
	organised	O
	man	O
	.	O
	During	O
	the	O
	pre	O
	-	O
	colonial	O
	period	O
	the	O
	British	O
	came	O
	to	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	and	O
	started	O
	ruling	O
	our	O
	country	O
	directly	O
	.	O
	The	O
	British	O
	ruled	O
	our	O
	country	O
	and	O
	they	O
	took	O
	Kenyans	O
	farms	O
	and	O
	houses	O
	and	O
	most	O
	of	O
	all	O
	their	O
	wives	O
	.	O
	People	O
	began	O
	paying	O
	taxes	O
	and	O
	working	O
	in	O
	their	O
	own	O
	farms	O
	some	O
	of	O
	them	O
	were	O
	traded	O
	as	O
	slaves	O
	.	O
	But	O
	when	O
	Mzee	B-ADLT
	Jomo	I-ADLT
	Kenyatta	I-ADLT
	was	O
	elected	O
	as	O
	president	O
	of	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	many	O
	things	O
	changed	O
	he	O
	united	O
	the	O
	Kenyan	O
	's	O
	and	O
	fought	O
	against	O
	the	O
	British	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	British	O
	collaborated	O
	and	O
	gave	O
	back	O
	the	O
	lauds	O
	and	O
	farms	O
	of	O
	Kenyans	O
	.	O
	Financially	O
	president	B-ADLT
	Mzee	I-ADLT
	Jomo	I-ADLT
	Kenyatta	I-ADLT
	lead	O
	Kenyans	O
	to	O
	independent	O
	in	O
	1963	O
	.	O
	Kenyans	O
	lived	O
	in	O
	peace	O
	and	O
	harmony	O
	all	O
	thanks	O
	to	O
	him	O
	later	O
	on	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	become	O
	a	O
	Republic	O
	in	O
	1964	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	war	O
	against	O
	AIDS	O
	has	O
	been	O
	fought	O
	for	O
	decades	O
	with	O
	doctors	O
	looking	O
	for	O
	solutions	O
	to	O
	treat	O
	","	O
	prevent	O
	and	O
	control	O
	the	O
	spread	O
	of	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	in	O
	the	O
	world	B-ORG
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	a	O
	research	O
	that	O
	has	O
	consumed	O
	millions	O
	of	O
	dollars	O
	got	O
	when	O
	the	O
	research	O
	was	O
	done	O
	and	O
	the	O
	findings	O
	were	O
	out	O
	that	O
	circumcise	O
	men	O
	have	O
	a	O
	sixty five	O
	percent	O
	of	O
	protection	O
	from	O
	AIDS	O
	a	O
	program	O
	was	O
	enrolled	O
	in	O
	all	O
	parts	O
	of	O
	the	O
	country	O
	which	O
	is	O
	so	O
	evident	O
	in	O
	the	O
	area	O
	of	O
	Katwekera	B-LOC
	where	O
	a	O
	sensitization	O
	was	O
	done	O
	and	O
	people	O
	were	O
	educated	O
	on	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	prevention	O
	.	O
	This	O
	led	O
	to	O
	a	O
	large	O
	number	O
	of	O
	people	O
	emerging	O
	to	O
	be	O
	circumcised	O
	so	O
	as	O
	to	O
	be	O
	on	O
	the	O
	safer	O
	side	O
	.	O
	Due	O
	to	O
	this	O
	the	O
	rate	O
	of	O
	AIDS	O
	infection	O
	in	O
	the	O
	country	O
	has	O
	reduced	O
	at	O
	a	O
	high	O
	and	O
	good	O
	rate	O
	thus	O
	showing	O
	the	O
	positive	O
	war	O
	against	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	During	O
	the	O
	Women	O
	's	O
	International	O
	Day	O
	","	O
	My	O
	school	O
	had	O
	the	O
	opportunity	O
	of	O
	attending	O
	the	O
	function	O
	at	O
	the	O
	Salvation	B-ORG
	Army	I-ORG
	in	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	Lindi	I-LOC
	.	O
	We	O
	were	O
	taught	O
	on	O
	various	O
	issues	O
	concerning	O
	girls	O
	and	O
	we	O
	benefited	O
	a	O
	lot	O
	from	O
	the	O
	guest	O
	speaker	O
	after	O
	that	O
	we	O
	were	O
	awarded	O
	with	O
	exercise	O
	books	O
	and	O
	sanitary	O
	towels	O
	being	O
	that	O
	we	O
	come	O
	from	O
	very	O
	poor	O
	background	O
	.	O
	Thanks	O
	to	O
	Sita	B-ORG
	Kimya	I-ORG
	for	O
	their	O
	concern	O
	especially	O
	towards	O
	the	O
	girl	O
	child	O
	education	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	AIDS	O
	in	O
	Africa	B-LOC
	has	O
	had	O
	a	O
	short	O
	but	O
	devastating	O
	history	O
	.	O
	with	O
	evidence	O
	the	O
	it	O
	originated	O
	in	O
	Africa	B-LOC
	with	O
	a	O
	10	O
	year	O
	study	O
	completed	O
	in	O
	2005	O
	.	O
	Experts	O
	studying	O
	the	O
	spread	O
	of	O
	the	O
	epidermic	O
	suggest	O
	that	O
	about	O
	2000	O
	people	O
	in	O
	Africa	B-LOC
	may	O
	have	O
	been	O
	infected	O
	with	O
	HIV	O
	by	O
	the	O
	1960	O
	with	O
	this	O
	statistics	O
	the	O
	government	O
	together	O
	with	O
	NGOs	O
	have	O
	been	O
	in	O
	the	O
	fight	O
	to	O
	stop	O
	the	O
	spread	O
	of	O
	the	O
	virus	O
	and	O
	reduce	O
	the	O
	number	O
	of	O
	infected	O
	people	O
	with	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	are	O
	also	O
	given	O
	anti	O
	-	O
	retrovirus	O
	viral	O
	to	O
	help	O
	them	O
	live	O
	a	O
	healthy	O
	life	O
	.	O
	Here	O
	in	O
	western	B-LOC
	kenya	I-LOC
	kakamega	I-LOC
	the	O
	fight	O
	is	O
	still	O
	going	O
	on	O
	with	O
	NGOs	O
	like	O
	western	B-ORG
	HIV	I-ORG
	/	I-ORG
	AIDS	I-ORG
	network	I-ORG
	being	O
	in	O
	the	O
	front	O
	-	O
	line	O
	to	O
	fight	O
	the	O
	epidermic	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Pius	B-ADLT
	Olema	I-ADLT
	.	O
	I	O
	did	O
	my	O
	K.	B-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	P.	I-OTHR
	E.	I-OTHR
	exams	O
	way	O
	back	O
	in	O
	2009	O
	and	O
	passed	O
	highly	O
	","	O
	which	O
	got	O
	me	O
	on	O
	admission	O
	at	O
	Alliance	B-ORG
	High	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	","	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	national	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	I	O
	was	O
	very	O
	happy	O
	but	O
	my	O
	happiness	O
	were	O
	shortlisted	O
	","	O
	learning	O
	that	O
	my	O
	parents	O
	could	O
	not	O
	manage	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	my	O
	high	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	.	O
	Musa	B-ADLT
	Kazungu	I-ADLT
	","	O
	after	O
	learning	O
	my	O
	fate	O
	.	O
	He	O
	volunteered	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	my	O
	high	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	and	O
	he	O
	started	O
	even	O
	by	O
	buying	O
	me	O
	school	O
	shopping	O
	for	O
	my	O
	first	O
	time	O
	in	O
	high	O
	school	O
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	been	O
	supporting	O
	me	O
	all	O
	through	O
	and	O
	am	O
	really	O
	working	O
	hard	O
	to	O
	achieve	O
	my	O
	dream	O
	of	O
	being	O
	a	O
	doctor	O
	.	O
	Were	O
	it	O
	not	O
	for	O
	Musa	B-ADLT
	","	O
	I	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	ca	O
	nt	O
	imagine	O
	says	O
	Mary	B-ADLT
	that	O
	my	O
	husband	O
	died	O
	of	O
	HIV	O
	AIDS	O
	.	O
	I	O
	become	O
	stigmatised	O
	and	O
	discriminated	O
	by	O
	my	O
	fellow	O
	family	O
	members	O
	they	O
	took	O
	all	O
	my	O
	properties	O
	away	O
	and	O
	send	O
	me	O
	out	O
	of	O
	their	O
	compound	O
	.	O
	I	O
	had	O
	only	O
	2	O
	years	O
	old	O
	child	O
	.	O
	I	O
	refused	O
	to	O
	go	O
	to	O
	hospital	O
	","	O
	I	O
	felt	O
	I	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	die	O
	and	O
	follow	O
	my	O
	husband	O
	I	O
	had	O
	lost	O
	hope	O
	that	O
	if	O
	my	O
	husband	O
	died	O
	what	O
	s	O
	the	O
	need	O
	of	O
	me	O
	living	O
	and	O
	my	O
	child	O
	.	O
	But	O
	Delila	B-ADLT
	one	O
	of	O
	my	O
	CHW	O
	came	O
	and	O
	took	O
	me	O
	to	O
	hospital	O
	.	O
	After	O
	testing	O
	they	O
	put	O
	me	O
	immediately	O
	on	O
	drugs	O
	","	O
	my	O
	child	O
	was	O
	also	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	After	O
	2	O
	months	O
	I	O
	had	O
	recovered	O
	and	O
	staying	O
	positively	O
	","	O
	the	O
	organisation	O
	is	O
	helping	O
	me	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Sabina	B-MINR
	Khavai	I-MINR
	I	O
	did	O
	my	O
	K.	B-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	P.	I-OTHR
	E.	I-OTHR
	2	O
	years	O
	ago	O
	.	O
	My	O
	mother	O
	was	O
	not	O
	able	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	for	O
	my	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	because	O
	she	O
	had	O
	no	O
	one	O
	to	O
	support	O
	her	O
	.	O
	So	O
	it	O
	was	O
	good	O
	to	O
	have	O
	had	O
	from	O
	the	O
	media	O
	that	O
	equity	O
	was	O
	offering	O
	support	O
	to	O
	the	O
	needy	O
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	now	O
	supporting	O
	me	O
	with	O
	fee	O
	and	O
	am	O
	now	O
	in	O
	school	O
	in	O
	form	O
	two	O
	and	O
	doing	O
	very	O
	well	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Rose	B-ADLT
	I	O
	thank	O
	God	O
	for	O
	equity	B-ORG
	for	O
	paying	O
	my	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	when	O
	I	O
	was	O
	in	O
	St.	B-ORG
	Mary	I-ORG
	's	I-ORG
	High	I-ORG
	School	I-ORG
	and	O
	now	O
	through	O
	.	O
	I	O
	performed	O
	well	O
	got	O
	an	O
	A	O
	of	O
	which	O
	they	O
	took	O
	me	O
	again	O
	and	O
	gave	O
	me	O
	a	O
	job	O
	with	O
	them	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	with	O
	them	O
	for	O
	sometime	O
	as	O
	I	O
	wait	O
	to	O
	join	O
	University	O
	next	O
	year	O
	but	O
	still	O
	they	O
	will	O
	be	O
	supporting	O
	me	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Tom	B-ADLT
	Khasinyile	I-ADLT
	.	O
	my	O
	parents	O
	but	O
	my	O
	aunt	O
	called	O
	Rebecca	B-ADLT
	Kalukhana	I-ADLT
	has	O
	provided	O
	a	O
	timely	O
	support	O
	.	O
	she	O
	cares	O
	for	O
	me	O
	.	O
	In	O
	2007	O
	UNICEF	B-ORG
	enrolled	O
	her	O
	into	O
	a	O
	support	O
	programme	O
	with	O
	a	O
	monthly	O
	payment	O
	of	O
	ksh	O
	1500	O
	.	O
	From	O
	this	O
	our	O
	medication	O
	education	O
	and	O
	food	O
	provision	O
	is	O
	ensured	O
	.	O
	Iam	O
	very	O
	happy	O
	for	O
	my	O
	aunt	O
	and	O
	her	O
	efforts	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Mary	B-ADLT
	Wanjiku	I-ADLT
	living	O
	in	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	for	O
	the	O
	last	O
	10	O
	years	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	taken	O
	me	O
	Many	O
	years	O
	doing	O
	business	O
	but	O
	because	O
	of	O
	capital	O
	I	O
	was	O
	not	O
	doing	O
	well	O
	.	O
	I	O
	thank	O
	God	O
	for	O
	Kenya	B-ORG
	women	I-ORG
	finance	I-ORG
	Trust	I-ORG
	who	O
	are	O
	really	O
	supporting	O
	women	O
	in	O
	this	O
	town	O
	since	O
	they	O
	came	O
	.	O
	Me	O
	being	O
	one	O
	of	O
	them	O
	.	O
	They	O
	give	O
	us	O
	women	O
	loans	O
	to	O
	boost	O
	our	O
	business	O
	and	O
	we	O
	really	O
	doing	O
	very	O
	well	O
	here	O
	in	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Jessica	B-MINR
	Nyongesa	I-MINR
	from	O
	kakamega	B-LOC
	north	I-LOC
	district	I-LOC
	.	O
	my	O
	brother	O
	is	O
	Dishon	B-MINR
	Indeche	I-MINR
	and	O
	we	O
	both	O
	put	O
	up	O
	with	O
	our	O
	grandmother	O
	by	O
	name	O
	join	O
	a	O
	Shitobolo	O
	.	O
	The	O
	government	O
	through	O
	the	O
	provincial	O
	childrens	O
	officer	O
	enrolled	O
	my	O
	grandmother	O
	into	O
	a	O
	world	B-ORG
	bank	I-ORG
	programme	I-ORG
	in	O
	support	O
	of	O
	orphans	O
	and	O
	vulnerable	O
	children	O
	which	O
	is	O
	on	O
	going	O
	for	O
	5	O
	years	O
	.	O
	we	O
	are	O
	able	O
	to	O
	get	O
	our	O
	upkeep	O
	provided	O
	and	O
	for	O
	educational	O
	expenses	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Through	O
	support	O
	from	O
	CPDA	B-ORG
	National	I-ORG
	Aids	I-ORG
	Control	I-ORG
	Council	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	NACC	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	will	O
	be	O
	implementing	O
	a	O
	one	O
	year	O
	project	O
	to	O
	reduce	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDs	O
	-	O
	related	O
	stigma	O
	and	O
	discrimination	O
	in	O
	western	B-LOC
	kenya	I-LOC
	regions	O
	to	O
	increase	O
	acceptance	O
	of	O
	individuals	O
	and	O
	their	O
	families	O
	living	O
	with	O
	and	O
	affected	O
	by	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDs	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	based	O
	on	O
	the	O
	findings	O
	that	O
	stigma	O
	and	O
	discrimination	O
	associated	O
	with	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDs	O
	is	O
	the	O
	greatest	O
	barrier	O
	to	O
	preventing	O
	further	O
	infections	O
	.	O
	Providing	O
	adequate	O
	care	O
	support	O
	and	O
	treatment	O
	and	O
	minimising	O
	impact	O
	.	O
	Western	B-ORG
	water	I-ORG
	and	I-ORG
	sanitation	I-ORG
	forum	I-ORG
	","	I-ORG
	WEWASAFO	I-ORG
	","	O
	through	O
	the	O
	support	O
	of	O
	Amkeni	B-ORG
	wakenya	I-ORG
	has	O
	launched	O
	a	O
	civil	O
	education	O
	project	O
	to	O
	increase	O
	a	O
	citizens	O
	awareness	O
	on	O
	the	O
	new	O
	developed	O
	structures	O
	and	O
	avenues	O
	of	O
	representation	O
	.	O
	The	O
	project	O
	titled	O
	Utekelezaj	O
	initative	O
	aims	O
	at	O
	strengthening	O
	people	O
	's	O
	engagement	O
	on	O
	constitution	O
	of	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	especially	O
	chapter	O
	2	O
	on	O
	devolution	O
	.	O
	It	O
	will	O
	be	O
	implemented	O
	in	O
	4	O
	constituences	O
	for	O
	one	O
	year	O
	namely	O
	Shinyalu	B-LOC
	","	O
	Malava	B-LOC
	","	O
	Lurambi	B-LOC
	and	O
	Ikolomani	B-LOC
	.	O
	The	O
	overall	O
	goal	O
	of	O
	the	O
	project	O
	is	O
	to	O
	enhance	O
	citizen	O
	participation	O
	in	O
	the	O
	setting	O
	of	O
	people	O
	-	O
	centred	O
	accountable	O
	and	O
	responsive	O
	developed	O
	governments	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Only	O
	11	O
	%	O
	of	O
	public	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	have	O
	toilets	O
	that	O
	meet	O
	the	O
	minimums	O
	standards	O
	","	O
	a	O
	UN	B-ORG
	study	O
	has	O
	revealed	O
	.	O
	The	O
	study	O
	funded	O
	by	O
	United	B-ORG
	Nations	I-ORG
	fluman	I-ORG
	settlements	I-ORG
	program	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	Habitat	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	noted	O
	that	O
	most	O
	toilets	O
	in	O
	schools	O
	do	O
	not	O
	meet	O
	.	O
	Hygiene	O
	levels	O
	exposing	O
	many	O
	children	O
	to	O
	diarrhoea	O
	and	O
	other	O
	diseases	O
	.	O
	UN	B-ORG
	Habitat	I-ORG
	chief	O
	technical	O
	advisor	O
	Laban	B-ADLT
	onongno	I-ADLT
	said	O
	limited	O
	access	O
	to	O
	safe	O
	water	O
	an	O
	saitation	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	National	O
	celebrations	O
	to	O
	mark	O
	this	O
	year	O
	's	O
	World	O
	Aids	O
	Day	O
	on	O
	December	O
	I	O
	that	O
	will	O
	see	O
	people	O
	gather	O
	at	O
	different	O
	venues	O
	and	O
	discuss	O
	on	O
	the	O
	fight	O
	against	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	.	O
	The	O
	national	O
	AIDS	O
	control	O
	said	O
	the	O
	decision	O
	was	O
	made	O
	in	O
	recognition	O
	of	O
	the	O
	fact	O
	that	O
	the	O
	region	O
	has	O
	contributed	O
	immensely	O
	to	O
	the	O
	success	O
	of	O
	the	O
	male	O
	circumcission	O
	programme	O
	.	O
	Other	O
	activities	O
	set	O
	to	O
	mark	O
	world	O
	Aids	O
	Day	O
	include	O
	an	O
	awareness	O
	-	O
	creation	O
	run	O
	dubbed	O
	the	O
	women	O
	Aids	O
	run	O
	tat	O
	will	O
	also	O
	be	O
	held	O
	in	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	government	O
	has	O
	launched	O
	a	O
	strategic	O
	plan	O
	to	O
	deal	O
	with	O
	neglected	O
	Tropical	O
	disease	O
	.	O
	The	O
	public	O
	Health	O
	and	O
	sanitation	O
	Assistant	O
	Minister	O
	Dr.	B-ADLT
	James	I-ADLT
	Gesami	I-ADLT
	said	O
	that	O
	the	O
	disease	O
	hinder	O
	socio	O
	-	O
	economic	O
	development	O
	and	O
	affects	O
	the	O
	quality	O
	of	O
	life	O
	affected	O
	persons	O
	.	O
	The	O
	major	O
	NTDs	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	include	O
	:	O
	Schistomiasis	O
	","	O
	soil	O
	transmitted	O
	Helminthes	O
	","	O
	Lymphatic	O
	Filariasis	O
	","	O
	Trachoma	O
	and	O
	the	O
	Hydrated	O
	Disease	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	has	O
	been	O
	very	O
	common	O
	in	O
	our	O
	day	O
	-	O
	to	O
	-	O
	day	O
	life	O
	but	O
	not	O
	all	O
	people	O
	take	O
	it	O
	seriously	O
	.	O
	The	O
	USAID	B-ORG
	organisation	O
	came	O
	to	O
	our	O
	courty	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	in	O
	Shewie	B-LOC
	village	I-LOC
	and	O
	taught	O
	us	O
	of	O
	the	O
	risks	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	we	O
	can	O
	get	O
	and	O
	low	O
	to	O
	prevent	O
	ourselves	O
	","	O
	and	O
	if	O
	positive	O
	how	O
	to	O
	maintain	O
	ourself	O
	and	O
	live	O
	positively	O
	.	O
	And	O
	now	O
	most	O
	of	O
	us	O
	are	O
	aware	O
	of	O
	it	O
	and	O
	are	O
	trying	O
	all	O
	our	O
	best	O
	to	O
	avoid	O
	getting	O
	it	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Leah	B-ADLT
	Makheti	I-ADLT
	","	O
	a	O
	resident	O
	of	O
	shinyalu	B-LOC
	constituency	I-LOC
	and	O
	a	O
	teacher	O
	by	O
	profession	O
	.	O
	I	O
	had	O
	the	O
	priviledge	O
	of	O
	being	O
	one	O
	of	O
	those	O
	being	O
	taught	O
	about	O
	the	O
	new	O
	constitution	O
	by	O
	UNDP	B-ORG
	Amkeni	I-ORG
	Wakenya	I-ORG
	in	O
	partnership	O
	with	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	.	O
	We	O
	enlightened	O
	on	O
	our	O
	rights	O
	","	O
	gender	O
	and	O
	governance	O
	and	O
	devolved	O
	governance	O
	.	O
	We	O
	are	O
	very	O
	grateful	O
	for	O
	everything	O
	since	O
	we	O
	active	O
	now	O
	known	O
	a	O
	lot	O
	conserning	O
	the	O
	new	O
	constitution	O
	that	O
	we	O
	knew	O
	not	O
	.	O
	We	O
	are	O
	thankfull	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Before	O
	many	O
	people	O
	had	O
	ignored	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	testing	O
	but	O
	with	O
	the	O
	comming	O
	The	B-ORG
	Aids	I-ORG
	support	I-ORG
	Organisation	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	TASO	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	the	O
	people	O
	in	O
	my	O
	community	O
	have	O
	greatly	O
	paticipated	O
	in	O
	the	O
	Aids	O
	/	O
	Hiv	O
	testing	O
	programme	O
	.	O
	The	O
	people	O
	who	O
	found	O
	them	O
	selves	O
	negative	O
	have	O
	now	O
	started	O
	trusting	O
	the	O
	parteners	O
	and	O
	those	O
	who	O
	are	O
	found	O
	possitive	O
	are	O
	given	O
	treatment	O
	(	O
	ARVS	O
	)	O
	drug	O
	not	O
	only	O
	drugs	O
	but	O
	also	O
	taso	B-ORG
	guided	O
	and	O
	conselled	O
	both	O
	possitive	O
	and	O
	negative	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	Aids	O
	people	O
	and	O
	the	O
	spread	O
	of	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	Aids	O
	has	O
	lowered	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Petronila	B-MINR
	Wilunda	I-MINR
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	currently	O
	on	O
	a	O
	beneficiary	O
	programme	O
	in	O
	support	O
	of	O
	orphans	O
	and	O
	vulnerable	O
	children	O
	which	O
	enrolled	O
	my	O
	grandfather	O
	","	O
	mr	B-ADLT
	Wilunda	I-ADLT
	Mworii	I-ADLT
	in	O
	2008	O
	.	O
	Having	O
	been	O
	victims	O
	of	O
	circumstances	O
	of	O
	a	O
	harsh	O
	predicament	O
	","	O
	where	O
	our	O
	parents	O
	died	O
	leaving	O
	us	O
	hopeless	O
	","	O
	we	O
	really	O
	were	O
	in	O
	need	O
	of	O
	any	O
	such	O
	support	O
	as	O
	this	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	World	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	national	B-ORG
	control	I-ORG
	against	I-ORG
	Drug	I-ORG
	Abuse	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	NACADA	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	.	O
	The	O
	drinks	O
	and	O
	alcohol	O
	act	O
	that	O
	was	O
	passed	O
	early	O
	in	O
	the	O
	year	O
	brought	O
	about	O
	by	O
	the	O
	illegal	O
	brews	O
	being	O
	brewed	O
	by	O
	locals	O
	in	O
	the	O
	villagers	O
	and	O
	deaths	O
	caused	O
	by	O
	this	O
	brews	O
	to	O
	blindness	O
	.	O
	Nacada	B-ORG
	was	O
	advocating	O
	for	O
	the	O
	police	O
	and	O
	public	O
	to	O
	implement	O
	the	O
	act	O
	and	O
	see	O
	the	O
	illegal	O
	brew	O
	being	O
	banned	O
	from	O
	the	O
	public	O
	.	O
	Nacada	B-ORG
	was	O
	in	O
	our	O
	school	O
	to	O
	help	O
	us	O
	know	O
	of	O
	drug	O
	abuse	O
	plus	O
	their	O
	fight	O
	against	O
	the	O
	sell	O
	of	O
	liquor	O
	that	O
	has	O
	not	O
	been	O
	legalized	O
	by	O
	the	O
	government	O
	to	O
	the	O
	public	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Jane	B-MINR
	Wilunda	I-MINR
	","	O
	from	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	North	I-LOC
	district	I-LOC
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	an	O
	orphan	O
	and	O
	together	O
	with	O
	my	O
	siblings	O
	we	O
	stay	O
	with	O
	our	O
	grandfather	O
	","	O
	Wilunda	B-ADLT
	Mweri	I-ADLT
	.	O
	In	O
	2008	O
	the	O
	world	B-ORG
	bank	I-ORG
	came	O
	to	O
	our	O
	rescue	O
	in	O
	equipping	O
	us	O
	with	O
	the	O
	support	O
	we	O
	really	O
	cherished	O
	.	O
	We	O
	are	O
	now	O
	on	O
	a	O
	5	O
	year	O
	programme	O
	of	O
	support	O
	where	O
	we	O
	receive	O
	sh	O
	1500	O
	monthly	O
	to	O
	top	O
	off	O
	our	O
	needs	O
	for	O
	education	O
	and	O
	upkeep	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	youth	O
	of	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	country	I-LOC
	and	O
	the	O
	country	O
	as	O
	a	O
	whole	O
	had	O
	been	O
	neglected	O
	in	O
	alot	O
	of	O
	things	O
	from	O
	leadership	O
	","	O
	decision	O
	making	O
	","	O
	policies	O
	and	O
	even	O
	mentorship	O
	.	O
	This	O
	was	O
	about	O
	to	O
	change	O
	with	O
	Wewasafo	B-ORG
	coming	O
	up	O
	with	O
	a	O
	programme	O
	to	O
	help	O
	the	O
	youth	O
	of	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	county	I-LOC
	realise	O
	that	O
	they	O
	have	O
	alot	O
	to	O
	do	O
	and	O
	with	O
	their	O
	numbers	O
	they	O
	can	O
	be	O
	able	O
	to	O
	elect	O
	young	O
	leaders	O
	who	O
	have	O
	their	O
	thoughts	O
	in	O
	mind	O
	.	O
	Wewasafo	B-ORG
	was	O
	running	O
	the	O
	mentorship	O
	programme	O
	in	O
	four	O
	constituencies	O
	of	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	county	I-LOC
	.	O
	Namely	O
	Lurambi	B-LOC
	","	O
	Shinyalu	B-LOC
	","	O
	Ikolomani	B-LOC
	and	O
	Malava	B-LOC
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Andrew	B-ADLT
	Kavande	I-ADLT
	I	O
	reside	O
	in	O
	Kefinco	B-LOC
	and	O
	iam	O
	a	O
	student	O
	Sigalagala	B-ORG
	technical	I-ORG
	institute	I-ORG
	.	O
	During	O
	last	O
	holidays	O
	","	O
	VIPEP	B-ORG
	an	O
	organisation	O
	that	O
	works	O
	closely	O
	with	O
	AMREF	B-ORG
	invited	O
	me	O
	and	O
	other	O
	youths	O
	in	O
	a	O
	BCC	B-ORG
	","	O
	Behaviour	O
	change	O
	workshop	O
	armed	O
	at	O
	educating	O
	the	O
	youths	O
	of	O
	the	O
	subject	O
	.	O
	We	O
	were	O
	tought	O
	many	O
	things	O
	","	O
	ranging	O
	from	O
	how	O
	to	O
	conduct	O
	ourselves	O
	.	O
	Sex	O
	and	O
	sexuality	O
	was	O
	taught	O
	","	O
	being	O
	responsible	O
	","	O
	effects	O
	of	O
	drug	O
	abuse	O
	and	O
	alcohol	O
	were	O
	also	O
	touched	O
	and	O
	youth	O
	getting	O
	thorough	O
	education	O
	all	O
	the	O
	way	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	really	O
	educative	O
	and	O
	inspiring	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	story	O
	of	O
	Asunta	B-ADLT
	Wagura	I-ADLT
	is	O
	more	O
	than	O
	inspirational	O
	to	O
	the	O
	pupils	O
	and	O
	students	O
	of	O
	Lukume	O
	.	O
	Being	O
	the	O
	chairperson	O
	of	O
	Kenya	B-ORG
	Network	I-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	women	I-ORG
	with	I-ORG
	HIV	I-ORG
	/	I-ORG
	AIDS	I-ORG
	.	O
	23	O
	years	O
	gone	O
	when	O
	she	O
	was	O
	infected	O
	with	O
	the	O
	virus	O
	when	O
	she	O
	was	O
	only	O
	22	O
	years	O
	old	O
	.	O
	She	O
	is	O
	a	O
	woman	O
	of	O
	strength	O
	having	O
	3	O
	kids	O
	and	O
	drawing	O
	a	O
	lot	O
	of	O
	gratitude	O
	having	O
	a	O
	family	O
	.	O
	She	O
	showed	O
	us	O
	that	O
	nothing	O
	can	O
	stop	O
	you	O
	from	O
	achieving	O
	what	O
	you	O
	want	O
	in	O
	life	O
	.	O
	Through	O
	KENWA	B-ORG
	she	O
	has	O
	made	O
	people	O
	come	O
	out	O
	and	O
	declare	O
	their	O
	status	O
	and	O
	stop	O
	the	O
	perception	O
	of	O
	persons	O
	who	O
	are	O
	dying	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	nancy	B-MINR
	Mulimi	I-MINR
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	student	O
	at	O
	St.	B-ORG
	Mary	I-ORG
	's	I-ORG
	Mumias	I-ORG
	girls	I-ORG
	high	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	.	O
	During	O
	the	O
	holidays	O
	I	O
	had	O
	the	O
	priviledge	O
	of	O
	attending	O
	the	O
	BCC	B-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	behavour	I-ORG
	change	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	programme	I-ORG
	","	O
	organised	O
	by	O
	VIPEP	B-ORG
	","	O
	an	O
	NGO	O
	within	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	.	O
	I	O
	got	O
	to	O
	learn	O
	many	O
	things	O
	concerning	O
	sexuality	O
	being	O
	responsible	O
	","	O
	how	O
	to	O
	ensure	O
	peaceful	O
	co-	O
	existence	O
	in	O
	our	O
	community	O
	","	O
	treating	O
	the	O
	elderty	O
	","	O
	vices	O
	like	O
	drug	O
	abuse	O
	and	O
	alcohol	O
	taking	O
	and	O
	actually	O
	by	O
	the	O
	end	O
	of	O
	the	O
	whole	O
	session	O
	that	O
	lasted	O
	a	O
	week	O
	","	O
	I	O
	had	O
	gained	O
	alot	O
	to	O
	be	O
	precise	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	It	O
	was	O
	actually	O
	an	O
	eye	O
	opener	O
	for	O
	good	O
	life	O
	for	O
	me	O
	as	O
	a	O
	youth	O
	Aphia	B-ORG
	plus	O
	KAMILI	B-ORG
	a	O
	project	O
	funded	O
	by	O
	USAID	B-ORG
	that	O
	builds	O
	on	O
	the	O
	work	O
	done	O
	by	O
	APHIA	B-ORG
	1	I-ORG
	.	O
	Working	O
	through	O
	provincial	O
	health	O
	provincial	O
	health	O
	system	O
	in	O
	western	B-LOC
	central	I-LOC
	system	O
	in	O
	western	B-LOC
	central	I-LOC
	and	O
	eastern	B-LOC
	provinces	I-LOC
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	To	O
	provide	O
	","	O
	promote	O
	a	O
	holistic	O
	and	O
	coordinated	O
	approach	O
	that	O
	improves	O
	service	O
	delivery	O
	while	O
	making	O
	it	O
	more	O
	client	O
	focused	O
	at	O
	provincial	O
	","	O
	country	O
	district	O
	community	O
	levels	O
	They	O
	provide	O
	OVC	O
	and	O
	homebased	O
	care	O
	service	O
	in	O
	the	O
	region	O
	.	O
	The	O
	project	O
	has	O
	so	O
	far	O
	been	O
	succesful	O
	and	O
	seen	O
	the	O
	OVC	O
	","	O
	get	O
	home	O
	based	O
	care	O
	to	O
	the	O
	OVCS	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	John	B-ADLT
	Wentangula	I-ADLT
	.	O
	Am	O
	a	O
	resident	O
	of	O
	Shinyalu	B-LOC
	within	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	county	O
	.	O
	All	O
	my	O
	gratitude	O
	be	O
	directed	O
	to	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	in	O
	partnership	O
	with	O
	UNDP	B-ORG
	AMKENI	I-ORG
	WAKENYA	I-ORG
	for	O
	enlightening	O
	us	O
	about	O
	the	O
	new	O
	constitution	O
	.	O
	We	O
	've	O
	learned	O
	alot	O
	about	O
	the	O
	constitution	O
	implementation	O
	within	O
	the	O
	3	O
	weeks	O
	span	O
	.	O
	I	O
	have	O
	learned	O
	many	O
	things	O
	on	O
	develop	O
	fund	O
	gender	O
	and	O
	governance	O
	and	O
	also	O
	my	O
	rights	O
	therefore	O
	am	O
	equipped	O
	with	O
	the	O
	knowledge	O
	Orphans	O
	in	O
	Rakai	B-LOC
	district	I-LOC
	and	O
	Masaka	B-LOC
	were	O
	suffering	O
	in	O
	early	O
	19s	O
	but	O
	when	O
	world	B-ORG
	vision	I-ORG
	came	O
	it	O
	started	O
	to	O
	give	O
	them	O
	to	O
	school	O
	","	O
	building	O
	them	O
	houses	O
	and	O
	give	O
	these	O
	with	O
	Hiv	O
	Aids	O
	drugs	O
	(	O
	ARVS	O
	)	O
	in	O
	order	O
	to	O
	improve	O
	their	O
	standard	O
	of	O
	living	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Aphia	B-ORG
	11	I-ORG
	is	O
	an	O
	organisation	O
	we	O
	people	O
	of	O
	Shinyalu	B-LOC
	will	O
	live	O
	to	O
	remember	O
	.	O
	At	O
	one	O
	time	O
	there	O
	had	O
	been	O
	on	O
	outbreak	O
	of	O
	waterborne	O
	diseases	O
	and	O
	bad	O
	enough	O
	some	O
	lives	O
	had	O
	been	O
	claimed	O
	hence	O
	it	O
	had	O
	been	O
	really	O
	hard	O
	.	O
	Accessing	O
	quality	O
	medical	O
	services	O
	was	O
	hard	O
	bearing	O
	in	O
	mind	O
	that	O
	there	O
	were	O
	few	O
	dispensaries	O
	around	O
	.	O
	However	O
	Aphia	B-ORG
	11	I-ORG
	surprised	O
	many	O
	when	O
	they	O
	put	O
	in	O
	place	O
	a	O
	free	O
	medical	O
	camp	O
	for	O
	3	O
	days	O
	which	O
	saw	O
	many	O
	being	O
	treated	O
	and	O
	getting	O
	well	O
	all	O
	the	O
	same	O
	it	O
	was	O
	very	O
	big	O
	boast	O
	to	O
	the	O
	people	O
	of	O
	Shinyalu	B-LOC
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Oduol	B-ADLT
	Nyagumi	I-ADLT
	is	O
	my	O
	name	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	resident	O
	of	O
	Lurambi	B-LOC
	and	O
	i	O
	take	O
	my	O
	studies	O
	at	O
	St.	B-ORG
	Peters	I-ORG
	high	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	","	O
	sometime	O
	back	O
	","	O
	during	O
	the	O
	last	O
	holidays	O
	i	O
	attended	O
	a	O
	certain	O
	forum	O
	that	O
	incorporated	O
	our	O
	coming	O
	together	O
	and	O
	learning	O
	about	O
	BCC	B-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	Behaviour	I-ORG
	Change	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	The	O
	programme	O
	had	O
	been	O
	put	O
	in	O
	place	O
	by	O
	an	O
	NGO	O
	","	O
	with	O
	the	O
	name	O
	VIPEP	B-ORG
	.	O
	I	O
	together	O
	with	O
	other	O
	youth	O
	gathered	O
	alot	O
	from	O
	that	O
	initiative	O
	.	O
	The	O
	lessons	O
	which	O
	mamly	O
	touched	O
	on	O
	us	O
	youth	O
	taking	O
	charge	O
	ourselves	O
	and	O
	avoiding	O
	bad	O
	vices	O
	was	O
	of	O
	big	O
	boost	O
	in	O
	terms	O
	of	O
	advice	O
	.	O
	At	O
	the	O
	end	O
	of	O
	the	O
	entire	O
	session	O
	","	O
	we	O
	had	O
	actually	O
	gathered	O
	alot	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Rebecca	B-ADLT
	Luseno	I-ADLT
	from	O
	lukokho	B-LOC
	area	I-LOC
	in	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	North	I-LOC
	district	I-LOC
	i	O
	was	O
	left	O
	with	O
	my	O
	son	O
	's	O
	children	O
	when	O
	he	O
	died	O
	and	O
	in	O
	bringing	O
	them	O
	up	O
	faced	O
	many	O
	challenges	O
	but	O
	i	O
	am	O
	glad	O
	UNICEF	B-ORG
	and	O
	the	O
	world	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	facilitated	O
	a	O
	support	O
	programme	O
	for	O
	orphans	O
	and	O
	vulnerable	O
	children	O
	considering	O
	these	O
	one	O
	of	O
	mine	O
	(	O
	two	O
	of	O
	them	O
	)	O
	The	O
	east	B-ORG
	African	I-ORG
	legislative	I-ORG
	Assembly	I-ORG
	(	O
	member	O
	of	O
	parliament	O
	)	O
	came	O
	together	O
	to	O
	give	O
	a	O
	chance	O
	to	O
	all	O
	partiner	O
	states	O
	have	O
	one	O
	region	O
	one	O
	HIV	O
	law	O
	against	O
	discrimination	O
	against	O
	persons	O
	living	O
	with	O
	HIV	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	East	B-LOC
	Africa	I-LOC
	countries	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	","	O
	Uganda	B-LOC
	","	O
	Tanzania	B-LOC
	","	O
	Rwanda	B-LOC
	","	O
	Burundi	B-LOC
	and	O
	southern	B-LOC
	sudan	I-LOC
	are	O
	to	O
	pass	O
	a	O
	law	O
	that	O
	will	O
	protect	O
	persons	O
	infected	O
	with	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	in	O
	the	O
	EACcountries	O
	.	O
	T.	B-ORG
	A.	I-ORG
	S.	I-ORG
	O.	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	the	I-ORG
	AIDS	I-ORG
	support	I-ORG
	organisation	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	is	O
	credited	O
	of	O
	creating	O
	educational	O
	awerenes	O
	of	O
	AIDS	O
	among	O
	the	O
	people	O
	of	O
	wengo	O
	district	O
	.	O
	before	O
	the	O
	information	O
	flows	O
	from	O
	TASO	B-ORG
	AIDS	I-ORG
	in	O
	the	O
	area	O
	was	O
	spreeding	O
	on	O
	a	O
	high	O
	rate	O
	but	O
	after	O
	TASO	B-ORG
	organising	I-ORG
	seminar	O
	and	O
	workshop	O
	the	O
	spread	O
	come	O
	to	O
	a	O
	less	O
	spread	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	With	O
	the	O
	landmark	O
	moment	O
	in	O
	the	O
	world	B-ORG
	's	O
	tight	O
	against	O
	malaria	O
	.	O
	Results	O
	from	O
	a	O
	major	O
	trial	O
	of	O
	is	O
	460	O
	African	O
	children	O
	released	O
	early	O
	last	O
	month	O
	","	O
	showed	O
	that	O
	the	O
	RTS	O
	'	O
	s	O
	vaccine	O
	created	O
	by	O
	glaxosmithkline	B-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	gsk	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	has	O
	reduced	O
	the	O
	risk	O
	of	O
	malaria	O
	by	O
	55	O
	%	O
	in	O
	children	O
	aged	O
	between	O
	5	O
	-	O
	17	O
	.	O
	This	O
	came	O
	as	O
	good	O
	news	O
	since	O
	many	O
	children	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	and	O
	Western	B-LOC
	Kenya	I-LOC
	died	O
	of	O
	malaria	O
	and	O
	had	O
	high	O
	infections	O
	of	O
	malaria	O
	compared	O
	to	O
	other	O
	parts	O
	of	O
	the	O
	country	O
	.	O
	Malaria	O
	being	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	continents	O
	most	O
	debilitating	O
	diseases	O
	it	O
	came	O
	as	O
	good	O
	to	O
	the	O
	Western	B-LOC
	Kenya	I-LOC
	people	O
	since	O
	the	O
	vaccine	O
	would	O
	see	O
	the	O
	cases	O
	of	O
	malaria	O
	infection	O
	be	O
	a	O
	thing	O
	of	O
	the	O
	past	O
	.	O
	Glaxosmithkline	B-ORG
	gave	O
	free	O
	drugs	O
	to	O
	the	O
	villages	O
	in	O
	western	B-LOC
	Kenya	I-LOC
	with	O
	assistance	O
	that	O
	a	O
	vaccine	O
	would	O
	be	O
	found	O
	sooner	O
	than	O
	later	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Cindy	B-MINR
	Karuoya	I-MINR
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	student	O
	at	O
	Pangani	B-ORG
	girls	I-ORG
	","	O
	am	O
	still	O
	a	O
	youth	O
	.	O
	When	O
	i	O
	had	O
	gone	O
	to	O
	visit	O
	my	O
	aunt	O
	during	O
	the	O
	holidays	O
	in	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	","	O
	she	O
	introduced	O
	me	O
	to	O
	a	O
	certain	O
	forum	O
	for	O
	the	O
	youth	O
	aimed	O
	at	O
	educating	O
	them	O
	on	O
	behaviour	O
	change	O
	.	O
	It	O
	had	O
	been	O
	organised	O
	by	O
	a	O
	certain	O
	organisation	O
	called	O
	VIPED	B-ORG
	in	O
	conjuction	O
	with	O
	AMREF	B-ORG
	.	O
	I	O
	had	O
	thought	O
	it	O
	to	O
	be	O
	boring	O
	at	O
	first	O
	","	O
	but	O
	it	O
	all	O
	turned	O
	out	O
	good	O
	and	O
	we	O
	got	O
	to	O
	learn	O
	and	O
	benefit	O
	from	O
	the	O
	lessons	O
	that	O
	taughts	O
	on	O
	making	O
	the	O
	best	O
	out	O
	of	O
	our	O
	lives	O
	.	O
	It	O
	encouraged	O
	on	O
	focusing	O
	on	O
	positive	O
	things	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	really	O
	good	O
	and	O
	i	O
	benefited	O
	a	O
	great	O
	deal	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Salamba	B-MINR
	Lusichi	I-MINR
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	beneficiary	O
	of	O
	a	O
	World	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	programme	I-ORG
	of	O
	2008	O
	which	O
	has	O
	greatly	O
	transformed	O
	many	O
	of	O
	us	O
	.	O
	My	O
	grandmother	O
	has	O
	been	O
	energised	O
	by	O
	by	O
	this	O
	support	O
	of	O
	the	O
	World	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	and	O
	UNICEF	B-ORG
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	single	O
	orphan	O
	with	O
	my	O
	grandmother	O
	.	O
	with	O
	a	O
	monthly	O
	support	O
	of	O
	ksh	O
	1500	O
	","	O
	i	O
	am	O
	able	O
	to	O
	go	O
	to	O
	school	O
	","	O
	get	O
	my	O
	upkeep	O
	support	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Juliana	B-MINR
	Mukoboto	I-MINR
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	14	O
	and	O
	in	O
	form	O
	one	O
	at	O
	Mahira	B-ORG
	Secondary	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	.	O
	The	O
	world	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	will	O
	live	O
	alot	O
	in	O
	my	O
	mind	O
	as	O
	a	O
	redemptive	O
	base	O
	upon	O
	which	O
	my	O
	life	O
	hinged	O
	to	O
	be	O
	hopeful	O
	.	O
	Had	O
	it	O
	not	O
	been	O
	for	O
	this	O
	world	O
	boldly	O
	to	O
	come	O
	in	O
	handy	O
	in	O
	2008	O
	which	O
	I	O
	had	O
	given	O
	up	O
	in	O
	life	O
	","	O
	I	O
	think	O
	I	O
	would	O
	never	O
	have	O
	seen	O
	the	O
	appearance	O
	of	O
	the	O
	gates	O
	of	O
	a	O
	secondary	O
	school	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Lufina	B-ADLT
	Nalisi	I-ADLT
	from	O
	Lunyinya	B-LOC
	in	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	North	I-LOC
	district	I-LOC
	.	O
	I	O
	take	O
	care	O
	of	O
	orphans	O
	.	O
	These	O
	3	O
	children	O
	are	O
	all	O
	orphans	O
	which	O
	have	O
	also	O
	gained	O
	the	O
	blessings	O
	of	O
	the	O
	support	O
	by	O
	the	O
	World	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	.	O
	The	O
	World	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	was	O
	introduced	O
	to	O
	our	O
	community	O
	by	O
	the	O
	efforts	O
	of	O
	the	O
	children	O
	's	O
	department	O
	under	O
	the	O
	provincial	O
	children	O
	's	O
	office	O
	in	O
	2008	O
	and	O
	now	O
	do	O
	support	O
	on	O
	children	O
	for	O
	a	O
	period	O
	of	O
	5	O
	years	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	What	O
	Shadrack	B-ADLT
	had	O
	gone	O
	through	O
	straight	O
	from	O
	being	O
	born	O
	upto	O
	now	O
	is	O
	a	O
	story	O
	of	O
	courage	O
	","	O
	determination	O
	and	O
	perserverance	O
	.	O
	A	O
	good	O
	story	O
	of	O
	what	O
	education	O
	can	O
	do	O
	in	O
	one	O
	's	O
	life	O
	.	O
	A	O
	perfect	O
	example	O
	of	O
	from	O
	rugs	O
	to	O
	riches	O
	.	O
	Shadrack	B-ADLT
	Wafwali	I-ADLT
	being	O
	an	O
	orphan	O
	at	O
	the	O
	age	O
	of	O
	six	O
	had	O
	no	O
	option	O
	but	O
	to	O
	step	O
	out	O
	of	O
	school	O
	and	O
	go	O
	to	O
	the	O
	streets	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	until	O
	he	O
	realised	O
	now	O
	his	O
	friends	O
	whom	O
	he	O
	used	O
	to	O
	bit	O
	back	O
	in	O
	primary	O
	doing	O
	very	O
	well	O
	that	O
	he	O
	got	O
	a	O
	good	O
	samaritan	O
	who	O
	offered	O
	to	O
	take	O
	him	O
	to	O
	school	O
	and	O
	Shadrack	B-ADLT
	did	O
	not	O
	disappoint	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	C.	O
	E.	O
	O	O
	of	O
	a	O
	blue	O
	chip	O
	company	O
	in	O
	the	O
	country	O
	and	O
	runs	O
	a	O
	foundation	O
	","	O
	The	B-ORG
	Shadrack	I-ORG
	W	I-ORG
	foundation	I-ORG
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Victor	B-ADLT
	Musonye	I-ADLT
	","	O
	i	O
	am	O
	a	O
	native	O
	of	O
	Shinyalu	B-LOC
	constituency	I-LOC
	Kakamega	I-LOC
	East	I-LOC
	and	O
	i	O
	was	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	people	O
	with	O
	UNDP	B-ORG
	Amkeni	I-ORG
	Wakenya	I-ORG
	.	O
	I	O
	remember	O
	before	O
	this	O
	was	O
	put	O
	in	O
	place	O
	","	O
	i	O
	had	O
	not	O
	taken	O
	keen	O
	consideration	O
	in	O
	knowing	O
	more	O
	about	O
	the	O
	new	O
	constitution	O
	and	O
	stuff	O
	.	O
	I	O
	however	O
	started	O
	it	O
	after	O
	the	O
	lesson	O
	i	O
	discovered	O
	that	O
	i	O
	had	O
	been	O
	missing	O
	alot	O
	","	O
	it	O
	was	O
	interesting	O
	especially	O
	learning	O
	the	O
	devotion	O
	part	O
	","	O
	the	O
	fact	O
	that	O
	power	O
	has	O
	been	O
	transfered	O
	from	O
	top	O
	to	O
	bottom	O
	","	O
	i	O
	am	O
	really	O
	happy	O
	.	O
	The	O
	new	O
	constitution	O
	incorporates	O
	many	O
	strategies	O
	to	O
	encourage	O
	development	O
	and	O
	that	O
	's	O
	why	O
	many	O
	corporate	O
	bodies	O
	have	O
	come	O
	to	O
	sponsor	O
	our	O
	country	O
	in	O
	implementing	O
	the	O
	new	O
	constitution	O
	.	O
	One	O
	of	O
	the	O
	bodies	O
	is	O
	UNDP	B-ORG
	Amkeni	I-ORG
	Wakenya	I-ORG
	which	O
	has	O
	sponsored	O
	the	O
	implementation	O
	of	O
	the	O
	constitution	O
	on	O
	the	O
	ground	O
	in	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	county	I-LOC
	WAWESAFO	B-ORG
	an	O
	NGO	O
	is	O
	the	O
	one	O
	partnering	O
	with	O
	UNDP	B-ORG
	in	O
	educating	O
	people	O
	on	O
	chapter	O
	II	O
	of	O
	the	O
	constitution	O
	which	O
	mainly	O
	tackles	O
	the	O
	devolution	O
	part	O
	.	O
	The	O
	Key	O
	areas	O
	that	O
	it	O
	started	O
	with	O
	are	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	North	I-LOC
	(	I-LOC
	Malava	I-LOC
	)	I-LOC
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	South	I-LOC
	(	I-LOC
	Ikolomani	I-LOC
	)	I-LOC
	Kakamega	I-LOC
	Central	I-LOC
	(	I-LOC
	Lurambi	I-LOC
	)	I-LOC
	and	O
	Kakamega	B-LOC
	East	I-LOC
	(	I-LOC
	Shinyalu	I-LOC
	)	I-LOC
	.	O
	Many	O
	have	O
	benefited	O
	from	O
	the	O
	initiative	O
	and	O
	it	O
	is	O
	seeing	O
	our	O
	country	O
	advance	O
	to	O
	higher	O
	stakes	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Kenya	B-LOC
	certificate	O
	of	O
	secondary	O
	education	O
	candidates	O
	in	O
	Murhanda	B-LOC
	ward	O
	received	O
	lunch	O
	offer	O
	from	O
	the	O
	area	O
	councellor	O
	during	O
	the	O
	examination	O
	period	O
	Councellor	O
	Mark	B-ADLT
	Ashiono	I-ADLT
	distributed	O
	money	O
	to	O
	respected	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	Murhanda	B-LOC
	ward	O
	to	O
	be	O
	spend	O
	for	O
	candidates	O
	lunch	O
	kitty	O
	according	O
	to	O
	their	O
	numbers	O
	.	O
	This	O
	gave	O
	candidates	O
	from	O
	poor	O
	families	O
	a	O
	great	O
	boost	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	KAMADER	B-ORG
	-	O
	An	O
	organisation	O
	based	O
	in	O
	kakamega	B-LOC
	county	O
	of	O
	the	O
	former	O
	western	O
	province	O
	helps	O
	to	O
	raise	O
	the	O
	living	O
	standards	O
	of	O
	residents	O
	in	O
	the	O
	four	O
	countries	O
	of	O
	vihiga	B-LOC
	kakamega	B-LOC
	Busia	I-LOC
	and	O
	Bungoma	B-LOC
	.	O
	In	O
	this	O
	respect	O
	i	O
	will	O
	shortly	O
	meantion	O
	of	O
	an	O
	example	O
	where	O
	organisation	O
	has	O
	improved	O
	sanitation	O
	and	O
	provided	O
	for	O
	clean	O
	water	O
	services	O
	to	O
	various	O
	resident	O
	of	O
	hamisi	B-LOC
	District	I-LOC
	in	O
	Vihiga	B-LOC
	county	I-LOC
	.	O
	The	O
	organization	O
	has	O
	fully	O
	sponsored	O
	the	O
	construction	O
	of	O
	water	O
	tanks	O
	in	O
	most	O
	primary	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	vihiga	B-LOC
	division	I-LOC
	.	O
	This	O
	has	O
	enhanced	O
	cleanliness	O
	and	O
	efficient	O
	supply	O
	of	O
	clean	O
	water	O
	for	O
	domestic	O
	and	O
	animal	O
	use	O
	.	O
	Kukubudu	B-ORG
	","	O
	Ishiru	B-ORG
	","	O
	","	O
	mukuyi	B-ORG
	","	O
	kaptik	B-ORG
	and	O
	shaviringa	B-ORG
	primary	I-ORG
	schools	I-ORG
	are	O
	the	O
	living	O
	example	O
	of	O
	school	O
	which	O
	have	O
	received	O
	the	O
	asistance	O
	.	O
	This	O
	has	O
	promoted	O
	health	O
	life	O
	for	O
	all	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	It	O
	came	O
	to	O
	my	O
	education	O
	that	O
	international	O
	organisations	O
	play	O
	a	O
	vital	O
	role	O
	in	O
	sponsoring	O
	education	O
	activities	O
	and	O
	programmes	O
	in	O
	various	O
	African	O
	nation	O
	states	O
	","	O
	kenya	B-LOC
	being	O
	inclussive	O
	.	O
	A	O
	school	O
	mate	O
	at	O
	masinde	B-ORG
	muliro	I-ORG
	university	I-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	science	I-ORG
	and	I-ORG
	technology	I-ORG
	from	O
	a	O
	poor	O
	family	O
	background	O
	had	O
	his	O
	hopes	O
	of	O
	leading	O
	a	O
	better	O
	future	O
	raised	O
	after	O
	securing	O
	a	O
	financial	O
	or	O
	a	O
	full	O
	post	O
	-	O
	secondary	O
	scholarship	O
	from	O
	a	O
	canadian	O
	based	O
	organisation	O
	known	O
	as	O
	AFRICAN	B-ORG
	CANADIAN	I-ORG
	CONTINUING	I-ORG
	EDUCATION	I-ORG
	SOCIETY	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	ACCESS	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Hezron	B-MINR
	Mukenya	I-MINR
	who	O
	is	O
	an	O
	orphan	O
	secured	O
	a	O
	B	O
	plain	O
	in	O
	his	O
	K.	B-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	S.	I-OTHR
	E.	I-OTHR
	exams	I-OTHR
	and	O
	was	O
	unable	O
	to	O
	raise	O
	fees	O
	for	O
	just	O
	to	O
	make	O
	an	O
	attempt	O
	to	O
	apply	O
	.	O
	Currently	O
	he	O
	is	O
	a	O
	third	O
	year	O
	student	O
	of	O
	education	O
	and	O
	assured	O
	of	O
	completing	O
	her	O
	studies	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	In	O
	2004	O
	the	O
	World	B-ORG
	food	I-ORG
	programme	I-ORG
	extended	O
	its	O
	aid	O
	to	O
	supply	O
	food	O
	to	O
	primary	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	including	O
	Ayany	B-ORG
	primary	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	and	O
	Joseph	B-ORG
	Kang'ethe	I-ORG
	primary	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	.	O
	this	O
	was	O
	followed	O
	after	O
	the	O
	WFP	B-ORG
	realised	O
	that	O
	most	O
	students	O
	in	O
	these	O
	schools	O
	came	O
	from	O
	very	O
	humble	O
	homes	O
	where	O
	food	O
	was	O
	not	O
	always	O
	available	O
	.	O
	Mrs	B-ADLT
	Vaid	I-ADLT
	Karita	I-ADLT
	had	O
	a	O
	nephew	O
	who	O
	suffered	O
	a	O
	cerebral	O
	malaria	O
	attack	O
	at	O
	just	O
	eight	O
	months	O
	old	O
	and	O
	went	O
	into	O
	coma	O
	for	O
	three	O
	days	O
	.	O
	25	O
	years	O
	later	O
	after	O
	going	O
	through	O
	the	O
	hands	O
	of	O
	several	O
	doctors	O
	","	O
	her	O
	nephew	O
	's	O
	life	O
	improved	O
	tremendously	O
	and	O
	she	O
	started	O
	leading	O
	a	O
	normal	O
	life	O
	.	O
	Such	O
	close	O
	relations	O
	with	O
	people	O
	with	O
	disability	O
	prompted	O
	Vaid	B-ADLT
	's	O
	choice	O
	to	O
	dedicate	O
	her	O
	life	O
	to	O
	work	O
	with	O
	children	O
	with	O
	unique	O
	physical	O
	and	O
	mental	O
	challenges	O
	.	O
	She	O
	started	O
	advising	O
	parents	O
	not	O
	to	O
	bow	O
	to	O
	the	O
	pressure	O
	of	O
	stigma	O
	from	O
	the	O
	society	O
	;	O
	and	O
	told	O
	them	O
	to	O
	allow	O
	their	O
	children	O
	to	O
	interact	O
	with	O
	other	O
	children	O
	","	O
	talk	O
	","	O
	share	O
	and	O
	attend	O
	school	O
	functions	O
	.	O
	Mrs	B-ADLT
	Vaid	I-ADLT
	is	O
	now	O
	a	O
	special	O
	needs	O
	teacher	O
	at	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	Jaffery	I-ORG
	Academy	I-ORG
	","	O
	and	O
	she	O
	receives	O
	funds	O
	and	O
	unwavering	O
	support	O
	from	O
	the	O
	Kenya	B-ORG
	Institute	I-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	Special	I-ORG
	Needs	I-ORG
	Education	I-ORG
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	B-ORG
	AIDS	I-ORG
	Support	I-ORG
	Organisation	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	TASO	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	has	O
	done	O
	alot	O
	to	O
	control	O
	the	O
	spread	O
	of	O
	HIV	O
	/	O
	AIDS	O
	by	O
	creating	O
	educational	O
	awarenes	O
	among	O
	people	O
	through	O
	semminars	O
	and	O
	workshops	O
	prior	O
	that	O
	AIDS	O
	was	O
	spreading	O
	on	O
	a	O
	high	O
	speed	O
	but	O
	after	O
	that	O
	the	O
	percentage	O
	of	O
	people	O
	with	O
	AIDS	O
	has	O
	come	O
	down	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Riitwa	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	young	O
	man	O
	who	O
	lives	O
	in	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	slum	I-LOC
	.	O
	He	O
	is	O
	a	O
	dedicated	O
	security	O
	man	O
	who	O
	makes	O
	sure	O
	that	O
	the	O
	life	O
	of	O
	students	O
	in	O
	Chiromo	B-LOC
	campus	I-LOC
	(	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	University	I-ORG
	)	O
	is	O
	good	O
	and	O
	that	O
	they	O
	have	O
	a	O
	smooth	O
	running	O
	of	O
	their	O
	Mundane	O
	chores	O
	in	O
	the	O
	campus	O
	so	O
	that	O
	they	O
	can	O
	mould	O
	and	O
	mend	O
	their	O
	futures	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Kineke	B-ADLT
	is	O
	member	O
	of	O
	parliament	O
	of	O
	tharaka	B-LOC
	Nithi	I-LOC
	constituency	I-LOC
	.	O
	He	O
	came	O
	up	O
	with	O
	the	O
	idea	O
	of	O
	tournaments	O
	in	O
	football	O
	in	O
	his	O
	constituency	O
	.	O
	The	O
	project	O
	has	O
	enncouraged	O
	so	O
	many	O
	youths	O
	to	O
	train	O
	for	O
	the	O
	tournaments	O
	therefore	O
	they	O
	have	O
	less	O
	or	O
	no	O
	time	O
	for	O
	doing	O
	immoral	O
	things	O
	or	O
	even	O
	take	O
	drugs	O
	.	O
	The	O
	projects	O
	also	O
	promotes	O
	unity	O
	in	O
	the	O
	society	O
	because	O
	you	O
	'll	O
	find	O
	that	O
	people	O
	interact	O
	with	O
	each	O
	other	O
	often	O
	in	O
	the	O
	tournaments	O
	and	O
	discussing	O
	issues	O
	that	O
	affect	O
	their	O
	society	O
	The	B-ORG
	AIDS	I-ORG
	Support	I-ORG
	organisation	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	TASO	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	is	O
	providing	O
	educational	O
	awarenes	O
	among	O
	the	O
	people	O
	of	O
	Lwengo	B-LOC
	District	I-LOC
	through	O
	organising	O
	councilling	O
	services	O
	","	O
	workshops	O
	and	O
	semminars	O
	.	O
	before	O
	the	O
	coming	O
	of	O
	TASO	B-ORG
	AIDS	I-ORG
	was	O
	spreading	O
	on	O
	highest	O
	speed	O
	but	O
	when	O
	the	O
	organisation	O
	sterded	O
	to	O
	educate	O
	people	O
	AIDS	O
	minimized	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	K.	B-OTHR
	I.	I-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	is	O
	a	O
	large	O
	and	O
	tall	O
	building	O
	where	O
	various	O
	occassions	O
	are	O
	usually	O
	convened	O
	.	O
	it	O
	was	O
	started	O
	by	O
	Mzee	B-ADLT
	Jomo	I-ADLT
	Kenyatta	I-ADLT
	.	O
	he	O
	saw	O
	it	O
	wise	O
	to	O
	start	O
	it	O
	up	O
	far	O
	various	O
	meetings	O
	to	O
	be	O
	convened	O
	and	O
	done	O
	to	O
	its	O
	fullest	O
	and	O
	to	O
	satisfy	O
	people	O
	who	O
	could	O
	visit	O
	it	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Radio	B-ORG
	Africa	I-ORG
	is	O
	an	O
	umbrella	O
	for	O
	so	O
	many	O
	radio	O
	stations	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	assisted	O
	very	O
	much	O
	on	O
	the	O
	Kenyans	B-ORG
	for	I-ORG
	Kenya	I-ORG
	initiative	I-ORG
	that	O
	was	O
	initiated	O
	to	O
	help	O
	those	O
	people	O
	who	O
	dying	O
	from	O
	hunger	O
	in	O
	Turkana	B-ORG
	and	O
	the	O
	drought	O
	strucken	O
	deeds	O
	.	O
	They	O
	played	O
	a	O
	major	O
	role	O
	and	O
	i	O
	echo	O
	them	O
	for	O
	that	O
	Karunja	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	man	O
	with	O
	a	O
	highly	O
	respected	O
	ego	O
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	once	O
	a	O
	kenyan	O
	top	O
	millitary	O
	man	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	who	O
	even	O
	trained	O
	in	O
	Egypt	B-LOC
	","	O
	Yugoslavia	B-LOC
	","	O
	Sierra	B-LOC
	Leon	I-LOC
	and	O
	as	O
	well	O
	as	O
	Israel	B-LOC
	.	O
	He	O
	retired	O
	from	O
	millitary	O
	after	O
	a	O
	peace	O
	-	O
	keeping	O
	war	O
	in	O
	Vietnam	B-LOC
	where	O
	he	O
	was	O
	a	O
	captain	O
	because	O
	of	O
	escaping	O
	death	O
	by	O
	inches	O
	.	O
	After	O
	retirement	O
	","	O
	he	O
	set	O
	up	O
	a	O
	club	O
	where	O
	young	O
	men	O
	go	O
	to	O
	train	O
	for	O
	their	O
	physical	O
	fitness	O
	and	O
	also	O
	self	O
	defence	O
	.	O
	This	O
	project	O
	will	O
	reduce	O
	the	O
	amount	O
	of	O
	victims	O
	that	O
	the	O
	assaulted	O
	through	O
	robbery	O
	","	O
	rape	O
	and	O
	other	O
	unenchanting	O
	behaviors	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Narotso	B-ADLT
	was	O
	about	O
	to	O
	give	O
	birth	O
	she	O
	was	O
	in	O
	labour	O
	pains	O
	.	O
	The	O
	doctors	O
	had	O
	gone	O
	on	O
	strike	O
	over	O
	low	O
	payment	O
	and	O
	so	O
	there	O
	was	O
	no	O
	doctor	O
	in	O
	the	O
	hospital	O
	.	O
	People	O
	did	O
	not	O
	know	O
	what	O
	to	O
	do	O
	.	O
	Thanks	O
	God	O
	to	O
	Nakhulo	B-ADLT
	who	O
	came	O
	up	O
	with	O
	a	O
	way	O
	of	O
	helping	O
	Narotso	B-ADLT
	deliver	O
	a	O
	beautiful	O
	baby	O
	girl	O
	as	O
	she	O
	was	O
	a	O
	mid	O
	-	O
	wife	O
	ALL	B-ORG
	Nations	I-ORG
	Together	I-ORG
	Bible	I-ORG
	College	I-ORG
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	colleges	O
	in	O
	Uganda	B-LOC
	which	O
	has	O
	come	O
	up	O
	to	O
	change	O
	the	O
	society	O
	morally	O
	and	O
	economically	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	ANTBC	B-ORG
	has	O
	trained	O
	the	O
	people	O
	to	O
	be	O
	with	O
	social	O
	skills	O
	such	O
	as	O
	being	O
	linguistic	O
	in	O
	languages	O
	like	O
	Swahili	B-OTHR
	","	O
	English	B-OTHR
	","	O
	French	B-OTHR
	and	O
	so	O
	improving	O
	on	O
	the	O
	community	O
	communication	O
	.	O
	ANTBC	B-ORG
	has	O
	trained	O
	members	O
	on	O
	family	O
	and	O
	community	O
	counseling	O
	on	O
	different	O
	levels	O
	such	O
	as	O
	associate	O
	pastors	O
	","	O
	Bachelor	O
	pastors	O
	","	O
	Master	O
	missionary	O
	","	O
	Evangelism	O
	.	O
	This	O
	college	O
	has	O
	trained	O
	pastors	O
	to	O
	become	O
	professional	O
	volunteers	O
	","	O
	local	O
	and	O
	international	O
	interpreter	O
	when	O
	preaching	O
	the	O
	Word	O
	of	O
	God	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Books	O
	in	O
	Namanga	B-ORG
	primary	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	would	O
	disappear	O
	each	O
	and	O
	everyday	O
	pupils	O
	and	O
	teachers	O
	wondered	O
	what	O
	was	O
	happening	O
	as	O
	the	O
	books	O
	would	O
	disappear	O
	everyday	O
	.	O
	There	O
	was	O
	no	O
	trace	O
	of	O
	where	O
	the	O
	books	O
	were	O
	going	O
	to	O
	one	O
	day	O
	as	O
	Hadija	B-ADLT
	was	O
	walking	O
	on	O
	the	O
	streets	O
	he	O
	saw	O
	Mr	B-ADLT
	Kibkosia	I-ADLT
	selling	O
	the	O
	school	O
	books	O
	.	O
	Mr	B-ADLT
	Kibkosia	I-ADLT
	tried	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	her	O
	not	O
	to	O
	say	O
	but	O
	Hadija	B-ADLT
	went	O
	and	O
	told	O
	the	O
	headteacher	O
	the	O
	teacher	O
	paid	O
	for	O
	all	O
	the	O
	books	O
	that	O
	were	O
	missing	O
	.	O
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Mzee	B-ADLT
	gitonga	I-ADLT
	was	O
	suffering	O
	from	O
	a	O
	heart	O
	problem	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	found	O
	necessary	O
	that	O
	he	O
	should	O
	visit	O
	the	O
	hospital	O
	for	O
	medication	O
	and	O
	treatment	O
	everyday	O
	.	O
	As	O
	days	O
