sentence	token	label
	The	O
	law	O
	should	O
	be	O
	amended	O
	to	O
	give	O
	the	O
	truth	O
	Justice	B-ORG
	and	I-ORG
	Reconcilitiation	I-ORG
	commision	I-ORG
	more	O
	powers	O
	and	O
	speed	O
	up	O
	its	O
	work	O
	","	O
	Deputy	O
	speaker	O
	Farah	B-ADLT
	Maalim	I-ADLT
	was	O
	saying	O
	during	O
	the	O
	consultative	O
	meeting	O
	in	O
	western	B-LOC
	Kenya	I-LOC
	.	O
	Unless	O
	you	O
	have	O
	independence	O
	","	O
	You	O
	will	O
	not	O
	go	O
	anywhere	O
	.	O
	Its	O
	therefore	O
	propose	O
	that	O
	the	O
	Act	O
	be	O
	ammended	O
	to	O
	allow	O
	the	O
	commission	O
	when	O
	acting	O
	on	O
	issues	O
	have	O
	independence	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	Name	O
	is	O
	peter	B-ADLT
	.	O
	I'm	O
	21	O
	years	O
	old	O
	.	O
	and	O
	heppen	O
	to	O
	Have	O
	affected	O
	by	O
	Hiv	O
	-	O
	Aids	O
	.	O
	I	O
	was	O
	Bed	O
	Ridden	O
	for	O
	6	O
	months	O
	and	O
	after	O
	that	O
	i	O
	was	O
	put	O
	on	O
	ARV'S.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	just	O
	a	O
	Business	O
	man	O
	selling	O
	oranges	O
	in	O
	the	O
	market	O
	a	O
	few	O
	kilometers	O
	from	O
	home	O
	.	O
	Sometimes	O
	carrying	O
	the	O
	luggage	O
	and	O
	moving	O
	from	O
	place	O
	to	O
	place	O
	to	O
	sell	O
	Became	O
	a	O
	problem	O
	to	O
	me	O
	I	O
	thought	O
	of	O
	getting	O
	a	O
	Bicycle	O
	But	O
	it	O
	was	O
	no	O
	Easy	O
	Buying	O
	one	O
	since	O
	it	O
	was	O
	expensive	O
	for	O
	me	O
	.	O
	I	O
	heard	O
	of	O
	my	O
	fellow	O
	Business	O
	men	O
	talking	O
	about	O
	getting	O
	a	O
	bicycle	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	.	O
	I	O
	became	O
	Intrested	O
	in	O
	Buying	O
	one	O
	when	O
	I	O
	approched	O
	the	O
	organization	O
	an	O
	N.	O
	G.	O
	O	O
	known	O
	as	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	.	O
	They	O
	gave	O
	me	O
	a	O
	Bicycle	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	to	O
	Repay	O
	for	O
	6	O
	months	O
	.	O
	I	O
	have	O
	payed	O
	the	O
	loan	O
	and	O
	now	O
	","	O
	the	O
	Bicycle	O
	is	O
	Reelly	O
	surporting	O
	me	O
	do	O
	my	O
	Business	O
	well	O
	.	O
	I	O
	even	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	have	O
	a	O
	problem	O
	with	O
	transportation	O
	.	O
	I	O
	can	O
	leave	O
	Home	O
	Very	O
	Early	O
	in	O
	the	O
	morning	O
	and	O
	come	O
	Back	O
	late	O
	in	O
	the	O
	evening	O
	after	O
	securing	O
	customers	O
	that	O
	com	O
	from	O
	job	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Godfrey	B-ADLT
	is	O
	my	O
	name	O
	.	O
	I	O
	come	O
	to	O
	know	O
	John	B-ADLT
	in	O
	forum	O
	.	O
	Indeed	O
	Beside	O
	being	O
	close	O
	to	O
	John	B-ADLT
	I	O
	have	O
	benefited	O
	a	O
	lot	O
	from	O
	Him	O
	.	O
	when	O
	I	O
	knew	O
	Him	O
	.	O
	They	O
	describe	O
	him	O
	as	O
	a	O
	Hard	O
	working	O
	young	O
	man	O
	in	O
	his	O
	village	O
	.	O
	John	B-ADLT
	Has	O
	been	O
	successfull	O
	all	O
	through	O
	says	O
	one	O
	of	O
	us	O
	.	O
	John	B-ADLT
	the	O
	narreted	O
	to	O
	me	O
	a	O
	story	O
	on	O
	how	O
	he	O
	sucefull	O
	completed	O
	his	O
	fort	O
	form	O
	fees	O
	.	O
	through	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	Business	O
	.	O
	Right	O
	now	O
	as	O
	I'm	O
	speaking	O
	I'm	O
	a	O
	driver	O
	employed	O
	by	O
	John	B-ADLT
	who	O
	owns	O
	a	O
	matatu	O
	in	O
	town	O
	.	O
	I	O
	ca	O
	nt	O
	imagine	O
	this	O
	young	O
	man	O
	travelling	O
	all	O
	the	O
	way	O
	from	O
	being	O
	a	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	Businessman	O
	to	O
	the	O
	owner	O
	of	O
	a	O
	matatu	O
	in	O
	town	O
	","	O
	this	O
	is	O
	great	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	A	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	Business	O
	that	O
	turned	O
	to	O
	a	O
	Motor	O
	bike	O
	Business	O
	.	O
	This	O
	a	O
	succes	O
	full	O
	young	O
	man	O
	by	O
	the	O
	name	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	.	O
	I'm	O
	happy	O
	to	O
	say	O
	that	O
	it	O
	's	O
	not	O
	easy	O
	it	O
	requires	O
	Hard	O
	work	O
	?	O
	I	O
	secured	O
	a	O
	chance	O
	of	O
	getting	O
	to	O
	be	O
	a	O
	business	O
	man	O
	in	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	","	O
	sector	O
	one	O
	Day	O
	.	O
	It	O
	's	O
	not	O
	easy	O
	","	O
	the	O
	bicycle	O
	I	O
	started	O
	with	O
	I	O
	took	O
	it	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	from	O
	an	O
	N.	O
	G.	O
	O	O
	know	O
	as	O
	(	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	)	O
	.	O
	Paying	O
	the	O
	loan	O
	was	O
	not	O
	easy	O
	but	O
	I	O
	managed	O
	to	O
	finish	O
	.	O
	I	O
	continued	O
	well	O
	and	O
	secured	O
	a	O
	motor	O
	bike	O
	through	O
	loan	O
	from	O
	the	O
	Equity	B-ORG
	bank	I-ORG
	","	O
	That	O
	's	O
	when	O
	I	O
	started	O
	seeing	O
	difference	O
	in	O
	my	O
	life	O
	I	O
	never	O
	gave	O
	up	O
	to	O
	Risk	O
	","	O
	my	O
	Business	O
	is	O
	doing	O
	well	O
	I'm	O
	planning	O
	to	O
	Buy	O
	a	O
	Matatu	O
	and	O
	soon	O
	or	O
	later	O
	I	O
	will	O
	be	O
	a	O
	successfully	O
	Matatu	O
	owner	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Surprisingly	O
	it	O
	happened	O
	so	O
	fast	O
	that	O
	people	O
	were	O
	left	O
	to	O
	wonder	O
	.	O
	says	O
	James	B-ADLT
	.	O
	I	O
	ca	O
	n't	O
	Imagine	O
	from	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	Business	O
	I'm	O
	a	O
	millionare	O
	.	O
	I	O
	started	O
	off	O
	by	O
	carrying	O
	children	O
	to	O
	school	O
	.	O
	Parents	O
	used	O
	to	O
	tell	O
	me	O
	at	O
	the	O
	end	O
	of	O
	the	O
	month	O
	.	O
	I	O
	used	O
	to	O
	save	O
	my	O
	money	O
	with	O
	Equity	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	.	O
	I	O
	was	O
	introduced	O
	to	O
	this	O
	Bank	O
	(	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	)	O
	when	O
	I	O
	First	O
	bought	O
	a	O
	bicycle	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	.	O
	After	O
	saving	O
	my	O
	fellow	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	men	O
	could	O
	not	O
	believe	O
	their	O
	eyes	O
	when	O
	they	O
	saw	O
	me	O
	with	O
	brand	O
	new	O
	motor	O
	cycle	O
	.	O
	this	O
	is	O
	after	O
	I	O
	learnt	O
	","	O
	to	O
	do	O
	savings	O
	through	O
	John	B-ADLT
	an	O
	officer	O
	that	O
	taught	O
	us	O
	on	O
	micro	O
	-	O
	finace	O
	.	O
	I'm	O
	doing	O
	good	O
	business	O
	with	O
	my	O
	Bike	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Surprisingly	O
	it	O
	happened	O
	so	O
	fast	O
	that	O
	people	O
	were	O
	left	O
	to	O
	wonder	O
	.	O
	says	O
	James	B-ADLT
	.	O
	I	O
	ca	O
	n't	O
	Imagine	O
	from	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	Business	O
	I'm	O
	a	O
	millionare	O
	.	O
	I	O
	started	O
	off	O
	by	O
	carrying	O
	children	O
	to	O
	school	O
	.	O
	Parents	O
	used	O
	to	O
	tell	O
	me	O
	at	O
	the	O
	end	O
	of	O
	the	O
	month	O
	.	O
	I	O
	used	O
	to	O
	save	O
	my	O
	money	O
	with	O
	Equity	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	.	O
	I	O
	was	O
	introduced	O
	to	O
	this	O
	Bank	O
	(	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	)	O
	when	O
	I	O
	First	O
	bought	O
	a	O
	bicycle	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	.	O
	After	O
	saving	O
	my	O
	fellow	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	men	O
	could	O
	not	O
	believe	O
	their	O
	eyes	O
	when	O
	they	O
	saw	O
	me	O
	with	O
	brand	O
	new	O
	motor	O
	cycle	O
	.	O
	this	O
	is	O
	after	O
	I	O
	learnt	O
	","	O
	to	O
	do	O
	savings	O
	through	O
	John	B-ADLT
	an	O
	officer	O
	that	O
	taught	O
	us	O
	on	O
	micro	O
	-	O
	finace	O
	.	O
	I'm	O
	doing	O
	good	O
	business	O
	with	O
	my	O
	Bike	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Our	O
	relative	O
	:	O
	mothers	O
	","	O
	fathers	O
	","	O
	uncles	O
	","	O
	brothers	O
	","	O
	sisters	O
	and	O
	aunts	O
	have	O
	been	O
	dying	O
	of	O
	different	O
	dimantion	O
	","	O
	gunshort	O
	muder	O
	toutchering	O
	mudder	O
	by	O
	thurgs	O
	and	O
	police	O
	across	O
	the	O
	road	O
	sickness	O
	etc	O
	.	O
	These	O
	had	O
	made	O
	money	O
	children	O
	to	O
	be	O
	orphans	O
	in	O
	the	O
	(	O
	GHETTO	O
	)	O
	slum	O
	.	O
	being	O
	that	O
	they	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	have	O
	any	O
	gudian	O
	they	O
	have	O
	been	O
	just	O
	loitering	O
	within	O
	village	O
	village	O
	searching	O
	on	O
	what	O
	to	O
	eat	O
	and	O
	who	O
	to	O
	take	O
	them	O
	to	O
	school	O
	.	O
	Sum	O
	of	O
	them	O
	have	O
	been	O
	addicted	O
	to	O
	drugs	O
	","	O
	crime	O
	","	O
	prostitution	O
	at	O
	early	O
	stage	O
	and	O
	also	O
	early	O
	marriage	O
	this	O
	increases	O
	poverty	O
	.	O
	These	O
	children	O
	were	O
	being	O
	taken	O
	to	O
	BARAKA	B-ORG
	ZA	I-ORG
	IBRAHIM	I-ORG
	CHILDREN	I-ORG
	CENTER	I-ORG
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	name	O
	is	O
	Jane	B-ADLT
	from	O
	kakamega	B-LOC
	.	O
	I'm	O
	a	O
	business	O
	woman	O
	","	O
	I	O
	started	O
	selling	O
	vegetables	O
	but	O
	now	O
	I'm	O
	a	O
	whole	O
	seller	O
	.	O
	I	O
	supply	O
	a	O
	lorry	O
	of	O
	cabbages	O
	every	O
	week	O
	.	O
	I'm	O
	happy	O
	to	O
	be	O
	at	O
	this	O
	level	O
	beacuse	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	an	O
	N.	O
	G.	O
	O	O
	surpoted	O
	us	O
	as	O
	a	O
	group	O
	.	O
	They	O
	gave	O
	us	O
	a	O
	loan	O
	of	O
	50	O
	thousand	O
	.	O
	A	O
	group	O
	of	O
	10	O
	women	O
	to	O
	expand	O
	our	O
	excisting	O
	Business	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	able	O
	to	O
	feed	O
	for	O
	my	O
	2	O
	children	O
	learning	O
	in	O
	a	O
	secondary	O
	school	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	able	O
	to	O
	feed	O
	them	O
	well	O
	My	O
	health	O
	and	O
	the	O
	health	O
	of	O
	my	O
	children	O
	is	O
	good	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	single	O
	mother	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	working	O
	forward	O
	to	O
	by	O
	my	O
	own	O
	land	O
	and	O
	building	O
	it	O
	.	O
	wright	O
	now	O
	i	O
	stay	O
	in	O
	a	O
	2	O
	Roomed	O
	House	O
	(	O
	A	O
	Rental	O
	)	O
	house	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	going	O
	to	O
	work	O
	hard	O
	so	O
	as	O
	to	O
	improve	O
	in	O
	live	O
	more	O
	and	O
	more	O
	.	O
	Thanks	O
	very	O
	much	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Joshua	B-ADLT
	Burn	I-ADLT
	in	O
	a	O
	village	O
	known	O
	as	O
	shikhambi	B-LOC
	.	O
	my	O
	business	O
	was	O
	making	O
	local	O
	beer	O
	for	O
	people	O
	to	O
	take	O
	.	O
	Sometimes	O
	people	O
	blame	O
	me	O
	for	O
	that	O
	because	O
	their	O
	children	O
	.	O
	Are	O
	getting	O
	spoiled	O
	one	O
	day	O
	i	O
	met	O
	a	O
	friend	O
	of	O
	mine	O
	who	O
	adviced	O
	me	O
	and	O
	thought	O
	changing	O
	that	O
	business	O
	.	O
	Fortunately	O
	there	O
	was	O
	an	O
	offer	O
	in	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	on	O
	NGO	O
	they	O
	were	O
	selling	O
	bicycles	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	.	O
	I	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	change	O
	to	O
	bodaboda	O
	and	O
	closed	O
	the	O
	other	O
	business	O
	people	O
	in	O
	my	O
	village	O
	rejoiced	O
	and	O
	even	O
	others	O
	who	O
	used	O
	to	O
	be	O
	drunk	O
	charged	O
	and	O
	started	O
	a	O
	bodaboda	O
	business	O
	.	O
	From	O
	this	O
	time	O
	i	O
	come	O
	to	O
	realize	O
	there	O
	is	O
	nothing	O
	impossible	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	planning	O
	to	O
	expand	O
	my	O
	business	O
	in	O
	future	O
	as	O
	i	O
	excel	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	Joshua	B-ADLT
	Burn	I-ADLT
	in	O
	a	O
	village	O
	known	O
	as	O
	shikhambi	B-LOC
	.	O
	my	O
	business	O
	was	O
	making	O
	local	O
	beer	O
	for	O
	people	O
	to	O
	take	O
	.	O
	Sometimes	O
	people	O
	blame	O
	me	O
	for	O
	that	O
	because	O
	their	O
	children	O
	.	O
	Are	O
	getting	O
	spoiled	O
	one	O
	day	O
	i	O
	met	O
	a	O
	friend	O
	of	O
	mine	O
	who	O
	adviced	O
	me	O
	and	O
	thought	O
	changing	O
	that	O
	business	O
	.	O
	Fortunately	O
	there	O
	was	O
	an	O
	offer	O
	in	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	on	O
	NGO	O
	they	O
	were	O
	selling	O
	bicycles	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	.	O
	I	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	change	O
	to	O
	bodaboda	O
	and	O
	closed	O
	the	O
	other	O
	business	O
	people	O
	in	O
	my	O
	village	O
	rejoiced	O
	and	O
	even	O
	others	O
	who	O
	used	O
	to	O
	be	O
	drunk	O
	charged	O
	and	O
	started	O
	a	O
	bodaboda	O
	business	O
	.	O
	From	O
	this	O
	time	O
	i	O
	come	O
	to	O
	realize	O
	there	O
	is	O
	nothing	O
	impossible	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	planning	O
	to	O
	expand	O
	my	O
	business	O
	in	O
	future	O
	as	O
	i	O
	excel	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	From	O
	a	O
	poor	O
	young	O
	man	O
	to	O
	a	O
	rich	O
	young	O
	man	O
	.	O
	I	O
	am	O
	narrating	O
	this	O
	story	O
	with	O
	thanksgiving	O
	to	O
	my	O
	friend	O
	John	B-ADLT
	.	O
	John	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	project	O
	officer	O
	from	O
	Wewasafo	B-ORG
	an	O
	NGO	O
	in	O
	town	O
	.	O
	This	O
	young	O
	man	O
	trained	O
	us	O
	on	O
	micro	O
	enterprise	O
	development	O
	.	O
	He	O
	gave	O
	an	O
	idea	O
	to	O
	start	O
	a	O
	Boda	O
	boda	O
	business	O
	.	O
	We	O
	took	O
	bicycles	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	from	O
	her	O
	organization	O
	.	O
	When	O
	i	O
	paid	O
	the	O
	loan	O
	i	O
	found	O
	myself	O
	excelling	O
	.	O
	I	O
	started	O
	saving	O
	with	O
	Equity	B-ORG
	Bank	I-ORG
	.	O
	I	O
	used	O
	to	O
	save	O
	daily	O
	and	O
	when	O
	there	O
	was	O
	enough	O
	money	O
	on	O
	my	O
	account	O
	I	O
	asked	O
	for	O
	a	O
	loan	O
	to	O
	buy	O
	a	O
	motor	O
	bike	O
	.	O
	Right	O
	now	O
	I	O
	am	O
	really	O
	excelling	O
	from	O
	a	O
	poor	O
	Boda	O
	boda	O
	man	O
	to	O
	a	O
	rich	O
	man	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Melandas	B-ADLT
	suffering	O
	reached	O
	to	O
	an	O
	end	O
	last	O
	year	O
	december	O
	as	O
	he	O
	narated	O
	his	O
	story	O
	to	O
	me	O
	.	O
	He	O
	had	O
	the	O
	desire	O
	of	O
	pursuing	O
	his	O
	education	O
	but	O
	the	O
	conditions	O
	at	O
	their	O
	place	O
	did	O
	not	O
	allow	O
	.	O
	every	O
	day	O
	morning	O
	the	O
	father	O
	could	O
	wake	O
	him	O
	early	O
	to	O
	the	O
	farm	O
	and	O
	even	O
	had	O
	started	O
	forgetting	O
	anything	O
	about	O
	schooling	O
	infact	O
	he	O
	had	O
	complained	O
	to	O
	the	O
	village	O
	elder	O
	who	O
	hardly	O
	listened	O
	to	O
	him	O
	till	O
	last	O
	year	O
	when	O
	he	O
	made	O
	James	B-ADLT
	may	O
	from	O
	England	B-LOC
	.	O
	According	O
	to	O
	him	O
	","	O
	he	O
	opened	O
	up	O
	to	O
	this	O
	man	O
	who	O
	had	O
	come	O
	to	O
	their	O
	village	O
	in	O
	kipsigur	B-LOC
	-	I-LOC
	shinyalu	I-LOC
	constituency	I-LOC
	to	O
	carry	O
	research	O
	a	O
	birds	O
	in	O
	kakamega	B-LOC
	forest	I-LOC
	and	O
	indeed	O
	he	O
	received	O
	help	O
	.	O
	May	O
	took	O
	him	O
	to	O
	his	O
	country	O
	where	O
	he	O
	is	O
	pursuing	O
	his	O
	academics	O
	without	O
	any	O
	hindrance	O
	did	O
	even	O
	give	O
	his	O
	father	O
	some	O
	token	O
	to	O
	cool	O
	his	O
	temper	O
	.	O
	Today	O
	the	O
	family	O
	is	O
	prospering	O
	though	O
	Molanda	B-ADLT
	has	O
	not	O
	yet	O
	cleared	O
	studies	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	generous	O
	contribution	O
	by	O
	50	O
	Cent	O
	(	O
	Curtis	B-ADLT
	Jackson	I-ADLT
	)	O
	","	O
	Mariah	B-ADLT
	Carey	I-ADLT
	and	O
	Rihanna	B-ADLT
	to	O
	the	O
	UN	B-ORG
	is	O
	a	O
	good	O
	way	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	back	O
	the	O
	people	O
	of	O
	Libya	B-LOC
	.	O
	Having	O
	earned	O
	the	O
	money	O
	for	O
	performing	O
	for	O
	their	O
	dictator	O
	leader	O
	Col	B-ADLT
	.	I-ADLT
	Muammar	I-ADLT
	Qaddafi	I-ADLT
	in	O
	several	O
	functions	O
	held	O
	for	O
	the	O
	family	O
	.	O
	Qaddafi	B-ADLT
	who	O
	refused	O
	to	O
	give	O
	up	O
	power	O
	even	O
	after	O
	40	O
	years	O
	of	O
	ruling	O
	.	O
	His	O
	being	O
	condemned	O
	by	O
	the	O
	musician	O
	for	O
	his	O
	evil	O
	acts	O
	of	O
	ki8lling	O
	civilians	O
	from	O
	his	O
	own	O
	country	O
	who	O
	were	O
	protesting	O
	against	O
	his	O
	inhumane	O
	rule	O
	.	O
	The	O
	UN	B-ORG
	has	O
	said	O
	that	O
	the	O
	money	O
	would	O
	be	O
	used	O
	to	O
	help	O
	the	O
	injured	O
	and	O
	provide	O
	relief	O
	food	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Never	O
	worry	O
	says	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	.	O
	I	O
	will	O
	show	O
	you	O
	the	O
	secret	O
	to	O
	successful	O
	living	O
	.	O
	At	O
	first	O
	I	O
	could	O
	not	O
	imagine	O
	from	O
	the	O
	story	O
	if	O
	this	O
	young	O
	man	O
	.	O
	As	O
	young	O
	as	O
	he	O
	was	O
	he	O
	is	O
	a	O
	taxi	O
	driver	O
	driving	O
	his	O
	own	O
	vehicle	O
	.	O
	Parents	O
	of	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	took	O
	him	O
	for	O
	driving	O
	and	O
	after	O
	completing	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	had	O
	no	O
	job	O
	.	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	started	O
	off	O
	the	O
	journey	O
	.	O
	He	O
	went	O
	and	O
	took	O
	a	O
	good	O
	bicycle	O
	from	O
	(	O
	WEWASAFO	B-ORG
	)	O
	an	O
	NGO	O
	in	O
	town	O
	and	O
	started	O
	off	O
	by	O
	doing	O
	Boda	O
	Boda	O
	business	O
	.	O
	The	O
	parents	O
	could	O
	not	O
	understand	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	but	O
	after	O
	a	O
	few	O
	months	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	went	O
	and	O
	bought	O
	a	O
	motor	O
	bike	O
	on	O
	loan	O
	.	O
	He	O
	said	O
	if	O
	I	O
	paid	O
	my	O
	bicycle	O
	loan	O
	successfully	O
	why	O
	not	O
	a	O
	motor	O
	bike	O
	.	O
	Within	O
	one	O
	year	O
	Paul	B-ADLT
	he	O
	'll	O
	completed	O
	paying	O
	her	O
	motor	O
	bike	O
	loan	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Water	O
	is	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	most	O
	vital	O
	things	O
	in	O
	life	O
	more	O
	than	O
	just	O
	having	O
	wealth	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	in	O
	the	O
	area	O
	of	O
	Shandorama	B-LOC
	have	O
	suffered	O
	in	O
	a	O
	period	O
	of	O
	time	O
	because	O
	of	O
	water	O
	shortage	O
	in	O
	their	O
	area	O
	.	O
	The	O
	only	O
	place	O
	they	O
	could	O
	get	O
	the	O
	water	O
	was	O
	on	O
	a	O
	small	O
	stream	O
	which	O
	was	O
	far	O
	away	O
	from	O
	people	O
	's	O
	home	O
	.	O
	Through	O
	the	O
	principal	O
	of	O
	Shandorama	B-ORG
	Boys	I-ORG
	High	I-ORG
	School	I-ORG
	Mr	B-ADLT
	Fredric	I-ADLT
	Tali	I-ADLT
	in	O
	conjunction	O
	with	O
	the	O
	government	O
	through	O
	the	O
	ministry	B-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	water	I-ORG
	","	O
	come	O
	up	O
	with	O
	a	O
	strategy	O
	to	O
	cub	O
	this	O
	problem	O
	that	O
	had	O
	become	O
	a	O
	breath	O
	to	O
	area	O
	residence	O
	.	O
	Mr.	B-ADLT
	Fredrick	I-ADLT
	Tali	I-ADLT
	teamed	O
	up	O
	with	O
	the	O
	parents	O
	","	O
	the	O
	area	O
	residence	O
	and	O
	community	O
	to	O
	raise	O
	up	O
	money	O
	.	O
	He	O
	followed	O
	up	O
	the	O
	project	O
	unit	O
	finally	O
	when	O
	the	O
	government	O
	through	O
	the	O
	people	O
	of	O
	water	O
	services	O
	sent	O
	their	O
	staff	O
	to	O
	go	O
	and	O
	drill	O
	a	O
	borehole	O
	which	O
	is	O
	servicing	O
	the	O
	entire	O
	community	O
	of	O
	Shandorama	B-LOC
	through	O
	taped	O
	water	O
	and	O
	piped	O
	water	O
	services	O
	area	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Some	O
	years	O
	back	O
	an	O
	individual	O
	Mr.	B-ADLT
	Ken	I-ADLT
	Okoth	I-ADLT
	of	O
	children	B-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	Kibera	I-ORG
	foundation	I-ORG
	","	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	help	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	of	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	by	O
	offering	O
	students	O
	with	O
	extra	O
	knowledge	O
	apart	O
	from	O
	the	O
	one	O
	they	O
	acquire	O
	in	O
	school	O
	.	O
	The	O
	man	O
	has	O
	proved	O
	to	O
	be	O
	the	O
	most	O
	important	O
	person	O
	in	O
	our	O
	community	O
	due	O
	to	O
	his	O
	kind	O
	heart	O
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	help	O
	a	O
	lot	O
	of	O
	school	O
	by	O
	donating	O
	books	O
	","	O
	computers	O
	and	O
	other	O
	learning	O
	materials	O
	.	O
	April	O
	from	O
	that	O
	","	O
	Ken	B-ADLT
	has	O
	been	O
	in	O
	fore	O
	front	O
	in	O
	raising	O
	talents	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	since	O
	his	O
	organization	O
	children	B-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	Kibera	I-ORG
	which	O
	has	O
	grown	O
	big	O
	recently	O
	do	O
	organized	O
	an	O
	event	O
	which	O
	is	O
	a	O
	competition	O
	i.	O
	e	O
	drama	O
	competition	O
	which	O
	normally	O
	take	O
	place	O
	once	O
	a	O
	year	O
	.	O
	Through	O
	this	O
	","	O
	Ken	B-ADLT
	has	O
	really	O
	united	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	our	O
	community	O
	since	O
	the	O
	schools	O
	meet	O
	and	O
	compete	O
	during	O
	the	O
	drama	O
	competition	O
	.	O
	Students	O
	and	O
	best	O
	schools	O
	do	O
	get	O
	prizes	O
	and	O
	it	O
	is	O
	only	O
	during	O
	this	O
	event	O
	a	O
	TRUE	O
	talent	O
	of	O
	a	O
	child	O
	is	O
	seen	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Saumu	B-MINR
	loves	O
	joking	O
	with	O
	men	O
	everytime	O
	they	O
	meet	O
	at	O
	road	O
	home	O
	and	O
	school	O
	Saumu	B-MINR
	arrives	O
	one	O
	day	O
	very	O
	sad	O
	and	O
	feeling	O
	very	O
	unhappy	O
	.	O
	She	O
	has	O
	never	O
	been	O
	like	O
	that	O
	since	O
	everybody	O
	knows	O
	her	O
	.	O
	Her	O
	mother	O
	asked	O
	her	O
	what	O
	went	O
	or	O
	was	O
	wrong	O
	.	O
	She	O
	told	O
	her	O
	mother	O
	what	O
	happened	O
	with	O
	her	O
	neighbour	O
	Edu	B-MINR
	","	O
	herself	O
	and	O
	him	O
	.	O
	Her	O
	mother	O
	was	O
	disappointed	O
	to	O
	hear	O
	that	O
	his	O
	neighbour	O
	Edu	B-MINR
	who	O
	use	O
	to	O
	be	O
	Saumu	B-MINR
	's	O
	friend	O
	liked	O
	her	O
	as	O
	a	O
	brother	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	rape	O
	her	O
	daughter	O
	.	O
	Her	O
	mother	O
	adviced	O
	her	O
	never	O
	to	O
	go	O
	far	O
	or	O
	lonely	O
	places	O
	with	O
	boys	O
	.	O
	You	O
	can	O
	be	O
	raped	O
	infected	O
	with	O
	AIDS	O
	and	O
	many	O
	bad	O
	things	O
	.	O
	Edu	B-MINR
	came	O
	and	O
	apologize	O
	to	O
	her	O
	parents	O
	.	O
	Saumu	B-MINR
	's	O
	mother	O
	adviced	O
	them	O
	on	O
	how	O
	life	O
	is	O
	and	O
	how	O
	they	O
	can	O
	take	O
	car.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Toto	B-ORG
	lea	I-ORG
	is	O
	an	O
	organisation	O
	that	O
	is	O
	helping	O
	poor	O
	needy	O
	H.	O
	I.	O
	V	O
	positive	O
	children	O
	to	O
	use	O
	RVS	O
	and	O
	support	O
	the	O
	children	O
	and	O
	family	O
	with	O
	food	O
	and	O
	free	O
	medicines	O
	.	O
	They	O
	take	O
	care	O
	of	O
	the	O
	affected	O
	victim	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	","	O
	Kawangare	B-LOC
	","	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	Lenana	B-LOC
	and	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	really	O
	improved	O
	their	O
	health	O
	in	O
	the	O
	poor	O
	slum	O
	areas	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Beatrice	B-MINR
	is	O
	a	O
	pupuil	O
	at	O
	Elyon	B-ORG
	secondary	I-ORG
	school	I-ORG
	which	O
	is	O
	a	O
	community	O
	school	O
	centre	O
	.	O
	she	O
	likes	O
	accepting	O
	gifts	O
	from	O
	many	O
	different	O
	peoples	O
	.	O
	five	O
	months	O
	ago	O
	","	O
	a	O
	trader	O
	who	O
	is	O
	a	O
	white	O
	man	O
	had	O
	been	O
	from	O
	foreign	O
	country	O
	gave	O
	her	O
	a	O
	nice	O
	present	O
	and	O
	invited	O
	her	O
	for	O
	a	O
	dinner	O
	.	O
	Beatrice	B-MINR
	was	O
	very	O
	exited	O
	about	O
	the	O
	dinner	O
	.	O
	while	O
	they	O
	were	O
	having	O
	dinner	O
	.	O
	while	O
	they	O
	were	O
	having	O
	dinner	O
	he	O
	asked	O
	her	O
	if	O
	they	O
	can	O
	go	O
	and	O
	spent	O
	night	O
	in	O
	a	O
	hotel	O
	room	O
	.	O
	Beatrice	B-MINR
	accepted	O
	The	O
	white	O
	man	O
	had	O
	AIDS	O
	which	O
	he	O
	got	O
	from	O
	another	O
	person	O
	.	O
	Beatrice	B-MINR
	was	O
	infected	O
	.	O
	He	O
	gave	O
	her	O
	30	O
	thousand	O
	on	O
	top	O
	AIDS	O
	.	O
	Beatrice	B-MINR
	is	O
	now	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	She	O
	is	O
	still	O
	in	O
	high	O
	school	O
	but	O
	very	O
	sad	O
	what	O
	happened	O
	to	O
	her	O
	.	O
	she	O
	normally	O
	adviced	O
	other	O
	girls	O
	never	O
	to	O
	go	O
	out	O
	or	O
	accept	O
	gifts	O
	from	O
	strangers	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Save	B-ORG
	Africa	I-ORG
	Children	I-ORG
	is	O
	real	O
	saver	O
	for	O
	children	O
	especially	O
	who	O
	are	O
	HIV	O
	positive	O
	and	O
	orphans	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	and	O
	families	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	have	O
	benefited	O
	through	O
	Save	B-ORG
	Africa	I-ORG
	.	O
	HIV	O
	children	O
	and	O
	orphans	O
	are	O
	being	O
	offered	O
	education	O
	through	O
	Cornerstone	B-ORG
	Children	I-ORG
	Academy	I-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	.	O
	The	O
	support	O
	is	O
	given	O
	to	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	to	O
	support	O
	vulnerable	O
	children	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Food	O
	is	O
	being	O
	given	O
	by	O
	Save	B-ORG
	Africa	I-ORG
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	change	O
	community	O
	children	O
	way	O
	of	O
	living	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Plan	B-ORG
	internation	I-ORG
	has	O
	done	O
	alot	O
	especially	O
	in	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	Division	I-LOC
	.	O
	Many	O
	schools	O
	and	O
	centers	O
	have	O
	benefited	O
	from	O
	this	O
	organisation	O
	Franel	B-ORG
	children	I-ORG
	centre	I-ORG
	got	O
	abusary	O
	from	O
	the	O
	organisation	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	vulnerable	O
	children	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	","	O
	kawangware	B-LOC
	and	O
	lenana	B-LOC
	are	O
	being	O
	sponsored	O
	through	O
	plan	O
	.	O
	They	O
	buy	O
	books	O
	","	O
	pencils	O
	and	O
	pay	O
	fees	O
	for	O
	vulnerable	O
	orphan	O
	needy	O
	children	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	really	O
	improved	O
	the	O
	poor	O
	and	O
	gives	O
	hopes	O
	to	O
	this	O
	young	O
	children	O
	.	O
	Franel	O
	pupil	O
	can	O
	afford	O
	asmile	O
	on	O
	face	O
	as	O
	well	O
	as	O
	community	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Cane	B-ORG
	International	I-ORG
	has	O
	given	O
	Kevin	B-ADLT
	a	O
	smile	O
	on	O
	his	O
	face	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	Kevin	B-ADLT
	is	O
	on	O
	his	O
	fourth	O
	year	O
	in	O
	university	O
	.	O
	Kevin	B-ADLT
	is	O
	orphans	O
	his	O
	parent	O
	died	O
	on	O
	road	O
	accident	O
	.	O
	Kevin	B-ADLT
	is	O
	now	O
	going	O
	through	O
	support	O
	from	O
	Care	B-ORG
	International	I-ORG
	is	O
	graduating	O
	in	O
	Bachelor	O
	of	O
	Health	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Precious	B-ORG
	Talent	I-ORG
	through	O
	Oliech	B-ADLT
	who	O
	is	O
	akenyan	O
	footballer	O
	received	O
	a	O
	donation	O
	from	O
	Oliech	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Food	O
	was	O
	being	O
	issued	O
	with	O
	groups	O
	of	O
	Youth	O
	boys	O
	from	O
	Oliech	B-ORG
	foundation	I-ORG
	which	O
	was	O
	formed	O
	recently	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	has	O
	set	O
	up	O
	feeding	O
	program	O
	to	O
	the	O
	children	O
	where	O
	by	O
	lunch	O
	is	O
	being	O
	provided	O
	at	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	to	O
	eradicate	O
	poverty	O
	of	O
	hunger	O
	among	O
	children	O
	especially	O
	the	O
	needy	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Save	B-ORG
	Africa	I-ORG
	Children	I-ORG
	is	O
	real	O
	saver	O
	for	O
	children	O
	especially	O
	who	O
	are	O
	HIV	O
	positive	O
	and	O
	orphans	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	and	O
	families	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	have	O
	benefited	O
	through	O
	Save	B-ORG
	Africa	I-ORG
	.	O
	HIV	O
	children	O
	and	O
	orphans	O
	are	O
	being	O
	offered	O
	education	O
	through	O
	Cornerstone	B-ORG
	Children	I-ORG
	Academy	I-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	.	O
	The	O
	support	O
	is	O
	given	O
	to	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	to	O
	support	O
	vulnerable	O
	children	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Food	O
	is	O
	being	O
	given	O
	by	O
	Save	B-ORG
	Africa	I-ORG
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	change	O
	community	O
	children	O
	way	O
	of	O
	living	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Alice	B-ADLT
	lives	O
	in	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	Market	I-LOC
	Centre	I-LOC
	at	O
	corner	O
	.	O
	She	O
	likes	O
	being	O
	given	O
	lifts	O
	with	O
	matatu	O
	conductors	O
	and	O
	grivers	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	a	O
	matatu	O
	driver	O
	gave	O
	her	O
	a	O
	lift	O
	to	O
	town	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	111	O
	route	O
	ngong	B-LOC
	road	I-LOC
	.	O
	They	O
	went	O
	to	O
	town	O
	","	O
	ate	O
	chips	O
	and	O
	Alice	B-ADLT
	was	O
	very	O
	excited	O
	.	O
	The	O
	matatu	O
	driver	O
	invited	O
	her	O
	to	O
	his	O
	house	O
	in	O
	Ngong	B-LOC
	.	O
	Alice	B-ADLT
	accepted	O
	and	O
	went	O
	.	O
	While	O
	they	O
	were	O
	in	O
	the	O
	house	O
	","	O
	He	O
	asked	O
	her	O
	to	O
	have	O
	sex	O
	with	O
	him	O
	.	O
	The	O
	driver	O
	had	O
	AIDS	O
	which	O
	he	O
	got	O
	from	O
	other	O
	girls	O
	.	O
	because	O
	the	O
	keep	O
	on	O
	changing	O
	ladies	O
	.	O
	Alice	B-ADLT
	was	O
	very	O
	disappoited	O
	after	O
	realizing	O
	she	O
	was	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	she	O
	has	O
	learnt	O
	a	O
	lesson	O
	she	O
	has	O
	joined	O
	other	O
	women	O
	who	O
	are	O
	positive	O
	and	O
	are	O
	cancelling	O
	young	O
	women	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Enter	O
	on	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	and	O
	pray	O
	that	O
	you	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	fail	O
	test	O
	that	O
	is	O
	before	O
	you	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	story	I-ORG
	telling	O
	project	O
	.	O
	The	O
	key	O
	to	O
	success	O
	is	O
	entering	O
	of	O
	Global	O
	with	O
	an	O
	agenda	O
	that	O
	's	O
	amendable	O
	.	O
	Yes	O
	we	O
	know	O
	what	O
	we	O
	are	O
	seeking	O
	Global	O
	for	O
	bring	O
	before	O
	.	O
	With	O
	all	O
	promises	O
	given	O
	to	O
	us	O
	through	O
	Global	O
	we	O
	ca	O
	n't	O
	assume	O
	that	O
	we	O
	know	O
	exactly	O
	what	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	is	O
	doing	O
	in	O
	this	O
	situation	O
	.	O
	We	O
	seek	O
	based	O
	on	O
	what	O
	we	O
	perceive	O
	.	O
	It	O
	is	O
	possible	O
	let	O
	it	O
	be	O
	done	O
	to	O
	the	O
	community	O
	for	O
	a	O
	change	O
	.	O
	we	O
	declared	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	but	O
	we	O
	are	O
	amendable	O
	realizing	O
	we	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	know	O
	the	O
	will	O
	of	O
	Global	B-ORG
	giving	I-ORG
	.	O
	Bravo	O
	!	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Coptic	B-ORG
	church	I-ORG
	on	O
	Ngong	B-LOC
	road	I-LOC
	is	O
	a	O
	community	O
	church	O
	that	O
	gives	O
	support	O
	to	O
	needy	O
	children	O
	that	O
	comes	O
	in	O
	poor	O
	families	O
	Christabell	B-MINR
	is	O
	among	O
	the	O
	beneficiaries	O
	from	O
	the	O
	girls	O
	who	O
	is	O
	being	O
	paid	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	through	O
	church	O
	organisation	O
	.	O
	Coptic	B-ORG
	has	O
	really	O
	changed	O
	her	O
	life	O
	and	O
	she	O
	is	O
	on	O
	forth	O
	year	O
	.	O
	She	O
	really	O
	than	O
	Coptic	B-ORG
	for	O
	their	O
	support	O
	by	O
	changing	O
	children	O
	lives	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Vanila	B-MINR
	befriended	O
	a	O
	married	O
	man	O
	.	O
	The	O
	man	O
	use	O
	to	O
	come	O
	pick	O
	Vanila	B-MINR
	and	O
	go	O
	out	O
	.	O
	A	O
	man	O
	would	O
	always	O
	give	O
	Vanita	B-MINR
	a	O
	lift	O
	in	O
	his	O
	car	O
	sometimes	O
	he	O
	brought	O
	sweets	O
	and	O
	ice	O
	cream	O
	and	O
	give	O
	to	O
	her	O
	as	O
	a	O
	present	O
	.	O
	Vanita	B-MINR
	dearly	O
	paidforlt	O
	forgetting	O
	that	O
	she	O
	is	O
	still	O
	a	O
	student	O
	.	O
	They	O
	started	O
	dating	O
	.	O
	Vanita	B-MINR
	's	O
	parents	O
	never	O
	knew	O
	what	O
	was	O
	going	O
	on	O
	with	O
	their	O
	daughter	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	her	O
	mother	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	follow	O
	her	O
	after	O
	she	O
	had	O
	left	O
	home	O
	because	O
	she	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	know	O
	Vanita	B-MINR
	changing	O
	in	O
	home	O
	dress	O
	.	O
	She	O
	followed	O
	her	O
	until	O
	she	O
	saw	O
	the	O
	house	O
	she	O
	entered	O
	.	O
	She	O
	went	O
	direct	O
	to	O
	police	O
	station	O
	and	O
	the	O
	man	O
	and	O
	VanitaThey	B-MINR
	were	O
	taken	O
	to	O
	police	O
	station	O
	","	O
	beaten	O
	and	O
	the	O
	man	O
	was	O
	fired	O
	Vanita	B-MINR
	was	O
	trnsfered	O
	to	O
	boarding	O
	school	O
	.	O
	She	O
	change	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Kivuli	B-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	is	O
	community	O
	Catholic	O
	Centre	O
	started	O
	with	O
	Father	O
	Kizito	B-ADLT
	to	O
	improve	O
	lives	O
	of	O
	youth	O
	and	O
	children	O
	in	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	.	O
	We	O
	have	O
	vocational	O
	training	O
	for	O
	youth	O
	also	O
	they	O
	have	O
	a	O
	centre	O
	for	O
	orphans	O
	inside	O
	.	O
	They	O
	care	O
	give	O
	education	O
	to	O
	orphans	O
	where	O
	they	O
	have	O
	established	O
	a	O
	home	O
	for	O
	poor	O
	and	O
	orphans	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	really	O
	changed	O
	many	O
	many	O
	orphans	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Thank	O
	you	O
	father	O
	Kizito	B-ADLT
	for	O
	wonder	O
	work	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Sophira	B-ADLT
	and	O
	James	B-ADLT
	had	O
	two	O
	children	O
	called	O
	Ibra	B-MINR
	and	O
	Sifa	B-MINR
	.	O
	The	O
	two	O
	children	O
	grew	O
	together	O
	and	O
	played	O
	together	O
	.	O
	But	O
	they	O
	have	O
	no	O
	manners	O
	The	O
	parents	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	care	O
	about	O
	it	O
	.	O
	They	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	play	O
	when	O
	church	O
	service	O
	was	O
	going	O
	on	O
	.	O
	Ibra	B-MINR
	went	O
	out	O
	and	O
	met	O
	his	O
	other	O
	children	O
	.	O
	They	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	get	O
	out	O
	of	O
	the	O
	gate	O
	when	O
	parents	O
	were	O
	still	O
	in	O
	church	O
	.	O
	Coming	O
	to	O
	realize	O
	he	O
	is	O
	missing	O
	Sifa	B-MINR
	told	O
	them	O
	he	O
	went	O
	out	O
	with	O
	his	O
	friend	O
	.	O
	They	O
	found	O
	him	O
	begging	O
	money	O
	for	O
	cars	O
	with	O
	the	O
	othe	O
	two	O
	boys	O
	.	O
	They	O
	were	O
	very	O
	surprised	O
	but	O
	Sifa	B-MINR
	told	O
	them	O
	even	O
	he	O
	does	O
	n't	O
	attend	O
	school	O
	that	O
	is	O
	his	O
	habit	O
	way	O
	since	O
	.	O
	The	O
	boy	O
	was	O
	punished	O
	and	O
	taken	O
	to	O
	aboarding	O
	now	O
	he	O
	has	O
	completely	O
	changed	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Grooming	B-ORG
	leadership	I-ORG
	Network	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	Glean	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	is	O
	launching	O
	an	O
	awareness	O
	mobilizing	O
	campaign	O
	with	O
	donation	O
	of	O
	farm	O
	tool	O
	and	O
	seedling	O
	in	O
	school	O
	to	O
	promote	O
	farming	O
	in	O
	Rural	B-LOC
	Kenya	I-LOC
	and	O
	urban	O
	.	O
	Eutycus	B-ORG
	is	O
	among	O
	the	O
	school	O
	which	O
	are	O
	being	O
	educated	O
	.	O
	Education	O
	farming	O
	leadership	O
	school	O
	grooming	O
	.	O
	Model	O
	the	O
	youth	O
	in	O
	schools	O
	to	O
	better	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	in	O
	future	O
	.	O
	Continue	O
	Eutycus	B-ORG
	and	O
	change	O
	the	O
	world	O
	with	O
	(	O
	Glean	B-ORG
	)	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Hope	O
	and	O
	trust	O
	in	O
	Global	B-ORG
	giving	I-ORG
	it	O
	will	O
	make	O
	you	O
	go	O
	far	O
	.	O
	The	O
	Community	O
	will	O
	change	O
	","	O
	Education	O
	will	O
	be	O
	given	O
	free	O
	","	O
	The	O
	orphans	O
	and	O
	the	O
	needy	O
	will	O
	see	O
	light	O
	.	O
	Invest	O
	in	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	make	O
	it	O
	real	O
	through	O
	story	O
	telling	O
	.	O
	Brosis	B-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	in	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	can	O
	now	O
	changing	O
	community	O
	way	O
	to	O
	creating	O
	Ideas	O
	.	O
	Telling	O
	people	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	let	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	your	O
	heart	O
	ambitions	O
	and	O
	source	O
	of	O
	your	O
	heart	O
	delight	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Achieng	B-MINR
	was	O
	happily	O
	playing	O
	with	O
	fire	O
	.	O
	Her	O
	mother	O
	was	O
	outside	O
	washing	O
	clothes	O
	.	O
	Suddenly	O
	she	O
	heard	O
	Achieng	B-MINR
	scream	O
	.	O
	She	O
	ran	O
	to	O
	the	O
	house	O
	to	O
	find	O
	Achieng	B-MINR
	's	O
	clothes	O
	on	O
	fire	O
	.	O
	Achieng	B-MINR
	legs	O
	were	O
	badly	O
	burned	O
	by	O
	the	O
	fire	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	taken	O
	to	O
	the	O
	hospital	O
	where	O
	was	O
	hospitalized	O
	.	O
	She	O
	will	O
	never	O
	walk	O
	again	O
	because	O
	she	O
	was	O
	badly	O
	burned	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Lukas	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	christian	O
	at	O
	Keongo	B-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	Gospel	I-ORG
	mission	I-ORG
	.	O
	Keongo	B-ORG
	is	O
	for	O
	from	O
	matobo	B-ORG
	Gospel	I-ORG
	mission	I-ORG
	.	O
	Lukas	B-ADLT
	and	O
	other	O
	christians	O
	formed	O
	a	O
	small	O
	chrstian	O
	community	O
	in	O
	their	O
	village	O
	for	O
	prayer	O
	and	O
	support	O
	.	O
	Lukas	B-ADLT
	and	O
	other	O
	christians	O
	have	O
	travel	O
	to	O
	Motobo	B-ORG
	Gospel	I-ORG
	mission	I-ORG
	for	O
	worship	O
	.	O
	The	O
	elderly	O
	","	O
	sick	O
	and	O
	children	O
	could	O
	not	O
	travel	O
	long	O
	distances	O
	.	O
	After	O
	consulting	O
	with	O
	mission	O
	leaders	O
	","	O
	Lukas	B-ADLT
	and	O
	christians	O
	put	O
	up	O
	a	O
	building	O
	at	O
	Keongo	B-ORG
	centre	I-ORG
	.	O
	They	O
	have	O
	prayers	O
	services	O
	without	O
	priest	O
	at	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	.	O
	Twice	O
	a	O
	week	O
	","	O
	the	O
	christians	O
	meet	O
	at	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	for	O
	prayer	O
	.	O
	tHey	O
	also	O
	organize	O
	themselves	O
	to	O
	visit	O
	homes	O
	.	O
	Everyone	O
	is	O
	now	O
	able	O
	to	O
	able	O
	to	O
	attend	O
	prayers	O
	and	O
	services	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	changing	O
	peoples	O
	to	O
	follow	O
	God	O
	and	O
	many	O
	converting	O
	to	O
	christians	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Eytcus	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	community	O
	school	O
	in	O
	ngando	B-LOC
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	groups	O
	of	O
	boys	O
	in	O
	Eutycus	B-LOC
	were	O
	smoking	O
	cigarette	O
	behind	O
	school	O
	toilets	O
	.	O
	They	O
	knew	O
	it	O
	was	O
	bad	O
	to	O
	smoke	O
	.	O
	and	O
	it	O
	was	O
	a	O
	bad	O
	habit	O
	.	O
	Thus	O
	why	O
	they	O
	were	O
	hiding	O
	.	O
	Sarum	B-MINR
	was	O
	apolite	O
	boy	O
	in	O
	school	O
	and	O
	hardworking	O
	.	O
	They	O
	saw	O
	Sarum	B-MINR
	they	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	invite	O
	him	O
	to	O
	fun	O
	with	O
	them	O
	.	O
	Sarum	B-MINR
	got	O
	there	O
	a	O
	found	O
	them	O
	smoking	O
	.	O
	They	O
	greeted	O
	him	O
	and	O
	invite	O
	him	O
	to	O
	fun	O
	with	O
	.	O
	Sarum	B-MINR
	have	O
	a	O
	smoke	O
	.	O
	it	O
	is	O
	nice	O
	","	O
	one	O
	boy	O
	said	O
	.	O
	Sarum	B-MINR
	replied	O
	NO	O
	.	O
	I	O
	do	O
	nt	O
	smoke	O
	and	O
	will	O
	never	O
	.	O
	It	O
	is	O
	wrong	O
	also	O
	you	O
	are	O
	breaking	O
	one	O
	of	O
	school	O
	rules	O
	.	O
	The	O
	boys	O
	felt	O
	it	O
	and	O
	were	O
	very	O
	sad	O
	what	O
	his	O
	friend	O
	told	O
	them	O
	.	O
	They	O
	asked	O
	Sarum	B-MINR
	to	O
	forgive	O
	them	O
	","	O
	they	O
	will	O
	never	O
	do	O
	that	O
	again	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Many	O
	Youth	O
	are	O
	now	O
	turning	O
	their	O
	lives	O
	to	O
	God	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	community	I-LOC
	through	O
	Calvary	B-ORG
	Temple	I-ORG
	.	O
	Is	O
	a	O
	church	O
	where	O
	full	O
	counsel	O
	of	O
	God	O
	word	O
	is	O
	believed	O
	","	O
	taught	O
	without	O
	Compramise	O
	","	O
	live	O
	an	O
	obedience	O
	include	O
	a	O
	christian	O
	school	O
	","	O
	adult	O
	bible	O
	study	O
	","	O
	and	O
	aggressive	O
	mission	O
	program	O
	.	O
	It	O
	is	O
	now	O
	working	O
	as	O
	an	O
	independent	O
	ministry	O
	averseeing	O
	and	O
	training	O
	local	O
	Youth	O
	pastors	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	changed	O
	Youth	O
	and	O
	especially	O
	the	O
	community	O
	people	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	a	O
	vision	O
	for	O
	youth	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Make	O
	change	O
	for	O
	Ngando	B-ORG
	Youth	I-ORG
	group	I-ORG
	change	O
	","	O
	change	O
	change	O
	for	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Anne	B-ADLT
	is	O
	HIV	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	Recently	O
	I	O
	met	O
	Anne	B-ADLT
	very	O
	happy	O
	and	O
	beutiful	O
	.	O
	I	O
	was	O
	with	O
	my	O
	friend	O
	Anita	B-ADLT
	who	O
	is	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	I	O
	have	O
	no	O
	fear	O
	","	O
	I	O
	don`t	O
	know	O
	what	O
	future	O
	holds	O
	.	O
	They	O
	don`t	O
	want	O
	to	O
	take	O
	responsibility	O
	of	O
	caring	O
	for	O
	another	O
	person	O
	whose	O
	health	O
	is	O
	uncertain	O
	when	O
	their	O
	own	O
	health	O
	is	O
	not	O
	guaranteed	O
	","	O
	she	O
	said	O
	.	O
	It	O
	really	O
	affected	O
	me	O
	and	O
	I	O
	told	O
	her	O
	I	O
	do	O
	care	O
	.	O
	She	O
	narrated	O
	her	O
	story	O
	how	O
	she	O
	met	O
	someone	O
	really	O
	nice	O
	we	O
	have	O
	great	O
	relationship	O
	said	O
	Anne	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Anita	B-ADLT
	my	O
	friend	O
	join	O
	me	O
	and	O
	change	O
	others	O
	in	O
	our	O
	community	O
	.	O
	She	O
	met	O
	Aman	B-ADLT
	through	O
	club	O
	","	O
	she	O
	has	O
	told	O
	his	O
	sister	O
	her	O
	status	O
	they	O
	know	O
	but	O
	he	O
	has	O
	never	O
	told	O
	anyone	O
	and	O
	refuses	O
	to	O
	meet	O
	my	O
	family	O
	because	O
	he	O
	fears	O
	they	O
	may	O
	not	O
	accept	O
	him	O
	and	O
	may	O
	tell	O
	others	O
	people	O
	his	O
	status	O
	.	O
	Despite	O
	the	O
	difficulties	O
	I	O
	have	O
	no	O
	regrets	O
	about	O
	dating	O
	someone	O
	who	O
	is	O
	HIV	O
	-	O
	negative	O
	.	O
	It	O
	is	O
	easier	O
	than	O
	dating	O
	someone	O
	who	O
	is	O
	HIV	O
	-	O
	negative	O
	.	O
	Join	O
	the	O
	Club	O
	to	O
	change	O
	","	O
	share	O
	and	O
	be	O
	free	O
	with	O
	each	O
	other	O
	.	O
	Anita	B-ADLT
	accepted	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	they	O
	are	O
	changing	O
	other	O
	peoples	O
	lives	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Wanjiku	B-MINR
	and	O
	Iscar	B-MINR
	are	O
	children	O
	at	O
	city	O
	prime	O
	academy	O
	in	O
	Ngong	B-LOC
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	Wanjiku	B-MINR
	waited	O
	for	O
	Iscar	B-MINR
	so	O
	that	O
	they	O
	can	O
	go	O
	together	O
	.	O
	while	O
	Wanjiku	B-MINR
	a	O
	stranger	O
	came	O
	and	O
	found	O
	her	O
	standing	O
	a	O
	long	O
	road	O
	side	O
	.	O
	He	O
	asked	O
	her	O
	what	O
	she	O
	was	O
	waiting	O
	for	O
	.	O
	She	O
	told	O
	him	O
	she	O
	was	O
	waiting	O
	for	O
	her	O
	friend	O
	Iscar	B-MINR
	.	O
	He	O
	asked	O
	her	O
	to	O
	getinto	O
	the	O
	car	O
	for	O
	a	O
	lift	O
	to	O
	school	O
	Wanjiku	B-MINR
	entered	O
	the	O
	car	O
	not	O
	knowing	O
	the	O
	man	O
	wa	O
	a	O
	rapist	O
	.	O
	She	O
	took	O
	Wanjiku	B-MINR
	in	O
	Ngong	B-LOC
	forest	I-LOC
	","	O
	raped	O
	her	O
	and	O
	brought	O
	her	O
	near	O
	her	O
	school	O
	.	O
	The	O
	teacher	O
	on	O
	duty	O
	as	O
	he	O
	was	O
	walking	O
	found	O
	Wanjiku	B-MINR
	lying	O
	helplessly	O
	.	O
	He	O
	took	O
	her	O
	to	O
	school	O
	and	O
	took	O
	herto	O
	hospital	O
	.	O
	The	O
	children	O
	were	O
	warned	O
	never	O
	to	O
	accepts	O
	free	O
	lifts	O
	from	O
	strangers	O
	.	O
	Wanjiku	B-MINR
	recovered	O
	and	O
	she	O
	was	O
	cancelled	O
	after	O
	leaning	O
	a	O
	lesson	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Oliver	B-ADLT
	and	O
	Mburu	B-ADLT
	","	O
	six	O
	month	O
	ago	O
	they	O
	were	O
	told	O
	with	O
	his	O
	friend	O
	Elisha	B-ADLT
	they	O
	were	O
	going	O
	to	O
	jail	O
	.	O
	His	O
	two	O
	workmate	O
	had	O
	cheated	O
	and	O
	lied	O
	that	O
	they	O
	have	O
	stolen	O
	money	O
	from	O
	safe	O
	from	O
	a	O
	place	O
	of	O
	work	O
	.	O
	They	O
	lost	O
	their	O
	Jobs	O
	and	O
	also	O
	their	O
	car	O
	.	O
	Elisha	B-ADLT
	wondered	O
	how	O
	he	O
	can	O
	help	O
	his	O
	friends	O
	.	O
	He	O
	finally	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	pay	O
	for	O
	a	O
	lawyer	O
	to	O
	defend	O
	Oliver	B-ADLT
	and	O
	Mburu	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Because	O
	he	O
	knew	O
	the	O
	thieves	O
	are	O
	still	O
	in	O
	the	O
	office	O
	.	O
	The	O
	lawyer	O
	argued	O
	the	O
	case	O
	and	O
	finally	O
	they	O
	were	O
	freed	O
	.	O
	Elisha	B-ADLT
	was	O
	very	O
	happy	O
	.	O
	So	O
	Oliver	B-ADLT
	and	O
	mburu	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Elisha	B-ADLT
	had	O
	shown	O
	that	O
	he	O
	loved	O
	his	O
	friend	O
	dearly	O
	.	O
	Amonth	O
	later	O
	the	O
	same	O
	case	O
	appeared	O
	.	O
	Real	O
	victims	O
	were	O
	found	O
	and	O
	Oliver	B-ADLT
	and	O
	mburu	B-ADLT
	went	O
	back	O
	to	O
	their	O
	Jobs	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Create	O
	","	O
	think	O
	Participate	O
	and	O
	share	O
	with	O
	others	O
	make	O
	it	O
	happen	O
	.	O
	Help	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Go	O
	to	O
	Global	B-ORG
	and	O
	cry	O
	for	O
	your	O
	help	O
	.	O
	Ngando	B-ORG
	Universal	I-ORG
	is	O
	among	O
	that	O
	cried	O
	and	O
	now	O
	it	O
	is	O
	really	O
	changing	O
	the	O
	community	O
	especially	O
	on	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	story	O
	telling	O
	.	O
	Ngando	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	it	O
	will	O
	change	O
	through	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	with	O
	Ngando	B-ORG
	Universal	I-ORG
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Kamau	B-ADLT
	and	O
	John	B-ADLT
	were	O
	friends	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	they	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	go	O
	for	O
	a	O
	walk	O
	.	O
	while	O
	walking	O
	they	O
	came	O
	to	O
	a	O
	river	O
	and	O
	they	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	take	O
	a	O
	swim	O
	.	O
	while	O
	swimming	O
	John	B-ADLT
	started	O
	drowning	O
	Kamau	B-ADLT
	tried	O
	to	O
	help	O
	him	O
	but	O
	he	O
	was	O
	too	O
	late	O
	.	O
	That	O
	is	O
	how	O
	their	O
	walk	O
	ended	O
	with	O
	sorrows	O
	.	O
	Kamau	B-ADLT
	went	O
	back	O
	home	O
	crying	O
	and	O
	screaming	O
	for	O
	help	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	One	O
	afternoon	O
	six	O
	month	O
	ago	O
	i	O
	lost	O
	my	O
	friend	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	along	O
	Mombasa	B-LOC
	road	I-LOC
	near	O
	mlolonga	B-LOC
	market	I-LOC
	.	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	was	O
	travelling	O
	from	O
	Nairobi	B-LOC
	to	O
	Machakos	B-LOC
	in	O
	a	O
	bus	O
	where	O
	she	O
	met	O
	her	O
	death	O
	.	O
	They	O
	had	O
	not	O
	gone	O
	far	O
	when	O
	suddenly	O
	driver	O
	stopped	O
	.	O
	What	O
	could	O
	be	O
	wrong?She	O
	wondered	O
	.	O
	She	O
	soon	O
	heard	O
	a	O
	cry	O
	of	O
	a	O
	baby	O
	coming	O
	from	O
	the	O
	vihicle	O
	.	O
	Whch	O
	was	O
	lying	O
	across	O
	the	O
	road	O
	.	O
	The	O
	vehicle	O
	was	O
	on	O
	fire	O
	.	O
	All	O
	passengers	O
	were	O
	dead	O
	.	O
	except	O
	the	O
	baby	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	ran	O
	toward	O
	the	O
	burning	O
	car	O
	to	O
	rescue	O
	and	O
	help	O
	the	O
	baby	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	her	O
	end	O
	of	O
	everything	O
	Soon	O
	there	O
	was	O
	an	O
	explosion	O
	.	O
	which	O
	threw	O
	pieces	O
	of	O
	metal	O
	far	O
	and	O
	wide	O
	.	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	was	O
	burnt	O
	to	O
	ashes	O
	while	O
	helping	O
	the	O
	baby	O
	by	O
	petrol	O
	.	O
	The	O
	baby	O
	was	O
	rushed	O
	to	O
	hospitol	O
	.	O
	She	O
	died	O
	trying	O
	to	O
	help	O
	the	O
	desparate	O
	baby	O
	.	O
	How	O
	sad	O
	it	O
	was	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Rose	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	single	O
	lady	O
	.	O
	She	O
	has	O
	been	O
	struggling	O
	everywhere	O
	to	O
	meet	O
	her	O
	ends	O
	.	O
	Going	O
	round	O
	in	O
	estate	O
	asking	O
	people	O
	for	O
	casual	O
	work	O
	.	O
	Washing	O
	clothes	O
	for	O
	people	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	knew	O
	her	O
	in	O
	many	O
	places	O
	because	O
	her	O
	work	O
	was	O
	admirable	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	she	O
	was	O
	called	O
	to	O
	go	O
	and	O
	was	O
	in	O
	Adams	B-ORG
	Arcade	I-ORG
	.	O
	As	O
	she	O
	was	O
	coming	O
	because	O
	it	O
	was	O
	late	O
	","	O
	she	O
	met	O
	street	O
	boys	O
	who	O
	raped	O
	her	O
	and	O
	left	O
	her	O
	lying	O
	at	O
	the	O
	roadside	O
	.	O
	she	O
	was	O
	saved	O
	by	O
	a	O
	Good	O
	Samaritan	O
	an	O
	Asian	O
	called	O
	Doshi	B-ADLT
	.	O
	He	O
	took	O
	her	O
	to	O
	hospital	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	women	I-ORG
	.	O
	He	O
	paid	O
	her	O
	bill	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	cancelled	O
	and	O
	narrated	O
	her	O
	story	O
	to	O
	them	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	One	O
	afternoon	O
	six	O
	month	O
	ago	O
	i	O
	lost	O
	my	O
	friend	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	along	O
	Mombasa	B-LOC
	road	I-LOC
	near	O
	mlolonga	B-LOC
	market	I-LOC
	.	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	was	O
	travelling	O
	from	O
	Nairobi	B-LOC
	to	O
	Machakos	B-LOC
	in	O
	a	O
	bus	O
	where	O
	she	O
	met	O
	her	O
	death	O
	.	O
	They	O
	had	O
	not	O
	gone	O
	far	O
	when	O
	suddenly	O
	driver	O
	stopped	O
	.	O
	What	O
	could	O
	be	O
	wrong?She	O
	wondered	O
	.	O
	She	O
	soon	O
	heard	O
	a	O
	cry	O
	of	O
	a	O
	baby	O
	coming	O
	from	O
	the	O
	vihicle	O
	.	O
	Whch	O
	was	O
	lying	O
	across	O
	the	O
	road	O
	.	O
	The	O
	vehicle	O
	was	O
	on	O
	fire	O
	.	O
	All	O
	passengers	O
	were	O
	dead	O
	.	O
	except	O
	the	O
	baby	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	ran	O
	toward	O
	the	O
	burning	O
	car	O
	to	O
	rescue	O
	and	O
	help	O
	the	O
	baby	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	her	O
	end	O
	of	O
	everything	O
	Soon	O
	there	O
	was	O
	an	O
	explosion	O
	.	O
	which	O
	threw	O
	pieces	O
	of	O
	metal	O
	far	O
	and	O
	wide	O
	.	O
	Lilian	B-ADLT
	was	O
	burnt	O
	to	O
	ashes	O
	while	O
	helping	O
	the	O
	baby	O
	by	O
	petrol	O
	.	O
	The	O
	baby	O
	was	O
	rushed	O
	to	O
	hospitol	O
	.	O
	She	O
	died	O
	trying	O
	to	O
	help	O
	the	O
	desparate	O
	baby	O
	.	O
	How	O
	sad	O
	it	O
	was	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Jane	B-ADLT
	was	O
	very	O
	annoyed	O
	with	O
	Jacky	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Jacky	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	romour	O
	monger	O
	and	O
	spread	O
	something	O
	which	O
	is	O
	not	O
	real	O
	.	O
	She	O
	went	O
	and	O
	lied	O
	to	O
	Juma	B-ADLT
	that	O
	Jane	B-ADLT
	has	O
	many	O
	boys	O
	friends	O
	.	O
	when	O
	she	O
	met	O
	him	O
	he	O
	told	O
	her	O
	you	O
	are	O
	a	O
	prostitute	O
	you	O
	change	O
	men	O
	like	O
	clothes	O
	you	O
	friend	O
	told	O
	me	O
	.	O
	I	O
	will	O
	never	O
	forgive	O
	you	O
	nor	O
	her	O
	.	O
	Jane	B-ADLT
	said	O
	she	O
	wentat	O
	Jacky	B-ADLT
	's	O
	place	O
	and	O
	had	O
	an	O
	argument	O
	","	O
	telling	O
	him	O
	bad	O
	words	O
	she	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	left	O
	her	O
	with	O
	wounds	O
	.	O
	She	O
	wanted	O
	stab	O
	her	O
	boyfriend	O
	take	O
	knife	O
	out	O
	.	O
	She	O
	told	O
	him	O
	it	O
	does	O
	n't	O
	matter	O
	how	O
	many	O
	time	O
	you	O
	say	O
	sorry	O
	the	O
	scar	O
	will	O
	stay	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	conselled	O
	by	O
	Anne	B-ADLT
	who	O
	is	O
	a	O
	social	O
	worker	O
	of	O
	life	B-ORG
	link	I-ORG
	welfare	I-ORG
	she	O
	advice	O
	others	O
	be	O
	careful	O
	not	O
	to	O
	stab	O
	your	O
	friend	O
	with	O
	word.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Jane	B-ADLT
	was	O
	very	O
	annoyed	O
	with	O
	Jacky	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Jacky	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	romour	O
	monger	O
	and	O
	spread	O
	something	O
	which	O
	is	O
	not	O
	real	O
	.	O
	She	O
	went	O
	and	O
	lied	O
	to	O
	Juma	B-ADLT
	that	O
	Jane	B-ADLT
	has	O
	many	O
	boys	O
	friends	O
	.	O
	when	O
	she	O
	met	O
	him	O
	he	O
	told	O
	her	O
	you	O
	are	O
	a	O
	prostitute	O
	you	O
	change	O
	men	O
	like	O
	clothes	O
	you	O
	friend	O
	told	O
	me	O
	.	O
	I	O
	will	O
	never	O
	forgive	O
	you	O
	nor	O
	her	O
	.	O
	Jane	B-ADLT
	said	O
	she	O
	wentat	O
	Jacky	B-ADLT
	's	O
	place	O
	and	O
	had	O
	an	O
	argument	O
	","	O
	telling	O
	him	O
	bad	O
	words	O
	she	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	left	O
	her	O
	with	O
	wounds	O
	.	O
	She	O
	wanted	O
	stab	O
	her	O
	boyfriend	O
	take	O
	knife	O
	out	O
	.	O
	She	O
	told	O
	him	O
	it	O
	does	O
	n't	O
	matter	O
	how	O
	many	O
	time	O
	you	O
	say	O
	sorry	O
	the	O
	scar	O
	will	O
	stay	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	conselled	O
	by	O
	Anne	B-ADLT
	who	O
	is	O
	a	O
	social	O
	worker	O
	of	O
	life	B-ORG
	link	I-ORG
	welfare	I-ORG
	she	O
	advice	O
	others	O
	be	O
	careful	O
	not	O
	to	O
	stab	O
	your	O
	friend	O
	with	O
	word.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Ali	B-ADLT
	is	O
	very	O
	sick	O
	.	O
	Father	B-ADLT
	Mario	I-ADLT
	told	O
	me	O
	.	O
	Ali	B-ADLT
	might	O
	die	O
	.	O
	because	O
	medicine	O
	are	O
	no	O
	longer	O
	helping	O
	him	O
	.	O
	Father	B-ADLT
	Mario	I-ADLT
	believes	O
	in	O
	telling	O
	us	O
	the	O
	truth	O
	.	O
	So	O
	that	O
	we	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	get	O
	a	O
	shock	O
	when	O
	one	O
	of	O
	us	O
	dies	O
	from	O
	the	O
	virus	O
	.	O
	Ali	B-ADLT
	is	O
	in	O
	constant	O
	pain	O
	and	O
	he	O
	cries	O
	a	O
	lot	O
	.	O
	I	O
	pray	O
	to	O
	God	O
	to	O
	help	O
	Ali	B-ADLT
	regain	O
	his	O
	strength	O
	and	O
	Happiness	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Njuguna	B-ADLT
	's	O
	family	O
	lives	O
	in	O
	a	O
	small	O
	crowded	O
	house	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	because	O
	Njuguna	B-ADLT
	and	O
	his	O
	wife	O
	earn	O
	very	O
	little	O
	money	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	Njuguna	B-ADLT
	bought	O
	a	O
	very	O
	expensive	O
	suit	O
	for	O
	himself	O
	.	O
	There	O
	was	O
	no	O
	food	O
	and	O
	enough	O
	money	O
	that	O
	month	O
	.	O
	When	O
	his	O
	wife	O
	asked	O
	him	O
	where	O
	the	O
	money	O
	for	O
	suit	O
	had	O
	come	O
	from	O
	","	O
	Njuguna	B-ADLT
	cheated	O
	that	O
	friend	O
	had	O
	lent	O
	him	O
	the	O
	money	O
	.	O
	Njuguna	B-ADLT
	had	O
	a	O
	rich	O
	girl	O
	friend	O
	who	O
	mostly	O
	took	O
	him	O
	out	O
	and	O
	bought	O
	expensive	O
	things	O
	for	O
	him	O
	.	O
	Njuguna	B-ADLT
	lied	O
	because	O
	he	O
	knew	O
	he	O
	had	O
	done	O
	the	O
	wrong	O
	thing	O
	.	O
	Accepting	O
	money	O
	and	O
	present	O
	behind	O
	their	O
	marriage	O
	relationship	O
	.	O
	Also	O
	spending	O
	money	O
	on	O
	lesure	O
	instead	O
	of	O
	buying	O
	food	O
	to	O
	his	O
	family	O
	.	O
	The	O
	marriage	O
	wo	O
	nt	O
	last	O
	long	O
	.	O
	The	O
	girl	O
	friend	O
	revealed	O
	the	O
	secret	O
	because	O
	she	O
	was	O
	pregnant	O
	.	O
	Marriage	O
	was	O
	broken	O
	.	O
	Children	O
	now	O
	suffering	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Under	B-ORG
	Corporate	I-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	social	I-ORG
	responsibility	I-ORG
	(	I-ORG
	CRS	I-ORG
	)	I-ORG
	program	I-ORG
	","	O
	nakumatt	B-ADLT
	joined	O
	with	O
	UBICEF	B-ORG
	to	O
	assist	O
	schools	O
	in	O
	the	O
	Slums	B-LOC
	area	I-LOC
	.	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	and	O
	Mathare	B-LOC
	in	O
	korokocho	B-LOC
	slums	I-LOC
	were	O
	amongest	O
	the	O
	beneficieries	O
	.	O
	They	O
	partined	O
	th	O
	AMREF	B-ORG
	and	O
	various	O
	communities	O
	in	O
	giving	O
	sigh	O
	and	O
	changing	O
	lives	O
	Compaign	O
	that	O
	seek	O
	to	O
	address	O
	the	O
	effects	O
	of	O
	poor	O
	sanitation	O
	and	O
	lack	O
	of	O
	water	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Keep	O
	it	O
	up	O
	nakumatt	B-ADLT
	Go	O
	ahead	O
	and	O
	show	O
	others	O
	to	O
	change	O
	and	O
	give	O
	sight	O
	to	O
	community	O
	(	O
	poor	O
	)	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	am	O
	happy	O
	and	O
	proud	O
	to	O
	be	O
	associated	O
	with	O
	Nakumatt	B-ADLT
	Said	O
	John	B-ADLT
	.	O
	Some	O
	of	O
	the	O
	things	O
	caught	O
	his	O
	attention	O
	is	O
	when	O
	they	O
	came	O
	to	O
	their	O
	life	O
	by	O
	launching	O
	of	O
	the	O
	biodegradable	O
	paper	O
	bag	O
	which	O
	gave	O
	him	O
	a	O
	job	O
	as	O
	he	O
	used	O
	to	O
	be	O
	a	O
	street	O
	boy	O
	with	O
	such	O
	a	O
	huge	O
	step	O
	he	O
	conguralate	O
	Nakumatt	B-ADLT
	for	O
	changing	O
	his	O
	life	O
	completely	O
	.	O
	He	O
	encourage	O
	other	O
	companies	O
	to	O
	follow	O
	such	O
	and	O
	make	O
	change	O
	to	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	It	O
	is	O
	only	O
	when	O
	we	O
	can	O
	protect	O
	our	O
	environment	O
	that	O
	we	O
	can	O
	achieve	O
	sustainable	O
	development	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	by	O
	changing	O
	youth	O
	life	O
	through	O
	creating	O
	casual	O
	job	O
	for	O
	them	O
	.	O
	Nakumatt	B-ADLT
	is	O
	showing	O
	rest	O
	what	O
	corparate	O
	social	O
	responsibility	O
	is	O
	all	O
	about	O
	especially	O
	in	O
	community	O
	support	O
	projects	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Christian	B-ORG
	Community	I-ORG
	in	I-ORG
	Dagoretti	I-ORG
	came	O
	out	O
	in	O
	one	O
	voice	O
	to	O
	unite	O
	and	O
	kill	O
	poverty	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	churches	O
	were	O
	invited	O
	in	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	chapel	I-ORG
	compound	O
	to	O
	come	O
	together	O
	and	O
	form	O
	one	O
	society	O
	for	O
	the	O
	Dagoretti	B-ORG
	communities	I-ORG
	Christians	I-ORG
	.	O
	Communities	O
	existed	O
	since	O
	the	O
	early	O
	church	O
	.	O
	All	O
	Christians	O
	community	O
	are	O
	members	O
	of	O
	one	O
	body	O
	.	O
	The	O
	number	O
	attended	O
	was	O
	good	O
	","	O
	everyone	O
	was	O
	invited	O
	around	O
	","	O
	food	O
	was	O
	served	O
	.	O
	The	O
	group	O
	was	O
	formed	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	Christians	O
	orphans	O
	","	O
	widows	O
	","	O
	widower	O
	all	O
	vulnerable	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Their	O
	office	O
	is	O
	in	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	chapel	I-ORG
	and	O
	orphans	O
	identifies	O
	are	O
	being	O
	sponsored	O
	by	O
	the	O
	organization	O
	.	O
	Unity	O
	together	O
	change	O
	vulnerable	O
	and	O
	your	O
	community	O
	logo	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	dated	O
	aman	O
	who	O
	was	O
	positive	O
	but	O
	he	O
	did	O
	n't	O
	tell	O
	me	O
	his	O
	status	O
	.	O
	people	O
	were	O
	suprised	O
	when	O
	they	O
	realize	O
	it	O
	is	O
	not	O
	only	O
	friendship	O
	but	O
	we	O
	are	O
	in	O
	love	O
	.	O
	Sarah	B-ADLT
	recall	O
	.	O
	But	O
	before	O
	things	O
	got	O
	worse	O
	she	O
	was	O
	saved	O
	by	O
	three	O
	women	O
	in	O
	my	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Rabecca	B-ADLT
	","	O
	Lucy	B-ADLT
	and	O
	Elizabeth	B-ADLT
	asked	O
	if	O
	i	O
	was	O
	his	O
	girl	O
	friend	O
	i	O
	told	O
	them	O
	Yes	O
	and	O
	they	O
	told	O
	me	O
	to	O
	go	O
	for	O
	VCT	O
	.	O
	When	O
	i	O
	told	O
	my	O
	fiance	O
	about	O
	it	O
	he	O
	told	O
	me	O
	he	O
	has	O
	gone	O
	many	O
	hospital	O
	he	O
	is	O
	negative	O
	.	O
	He	O
	refused	O
	completely	O
	.	O
	Thus	O
	when	O
	i	O
	knew	O
	he	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	take	O
	advantage	O
	and	O
	infect	O
	meThanks	O
	for	O
	the	O
	ladies	O
	who	O
	save	O
	me	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Earthquake	O
	are	O
	caused	O
	by	O
	the	O
	quick	O
	movement	O
	of	O
	the	O
	Earth	O
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	mostly	O
	experienced	O
	in	O
	the	O
	Asia	O
	continent	O
	.	O
	Earthquakes	O
	can	O
	be	O
	dangerous	O
	when	O
	it	O
	is	O
	strong	O
	.	O
	Recently	O
	","	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	most	O
	rich	O
	country	O
	.	O
	Japan	B-LOC
	experienced	O
	an	O
	earthquake	O
	that	O
	destroyed	O
	the	O
	lives	O
	of	O
	many	O
	people	O
	","	O
	properties	O
	","	O
	buildings	O
	factories	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	the	O
	worst	O
	experience	O
	Japan	B-LOC
	have	O
	ever	O
	face	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	people	O
	have	O
	died	O
	and	O
	many	O
	have	O
	been	O
	displaced	O
	.	O
	Not	O
	only	O
	that	O
	","	O
	the	O
	earthquake	O
	interefered	O
	with	O
	the	O
	nuclear	O
	system	O
	which	O
	now	O
	posses	O
	a	O
	great	O
	danger	O
	not	O
	only	O
	to	O
	the	O
	place	O
	affected	O
	by	O
	the	O
	earthquake	O
	but	O
	the	O
	whole	O
	Japan	B-LOC
	Island	I-LOC
	.	O
	Although	O
	many	O
	have	O
	come	O
	to	O
	support	O
	them	O
	but	O
	they	O
	can	O
	not	O
	fill	O
	the	O
	hole	O
	left	O
	in	O
	the	O
	Japanese	O
	hearts	O
	.	O
	This	O
	has	O
	affected	O
	the	O
	economy	O
	.	O
	social	O
	and	O
	physical	O
	life	O
	of	O
	Japanese	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Maina	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	victim	O
	of	O
	polio	O
	he	O
	can	O
	not	O
	walk	O
	and	O
	he	O
	has	O
	to	O
	be	O
	carried	O
	around	O
	","	O
	by	O
	his	O
	relatives	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	Action	B-ORG
	Aid	I-ORG
	bought	O
	a	O
	wheelchair	O
	for	O
	him	O
	He	O
	can	O
	now	O
	move	O
	around	O
	using	O
	the	O
	wheelchair	O
	.	O
	Action	B-ORG
	Aid	I-ORG
	is	O
	a	O
	helpful	O
	organization	O
	thanks	O
	to	O
	them	O
	Maina	B-ADLT
	can	O
	now	O
	be	O
	independent	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	My	O
	parents	O
	were	O
	university	O
	lectures	O
	when	O
	they	O
	were	O
	alive	O
	.	O
	I	O
	attended	O
	a	O
	private	O
	school	O
	named	O
	Acacia	B-ORG
	academy	I-ORG
	after	O
	my	O
	parents	O
	died	O
	.	O
	I	O
	lived	O
	with	O
	my	O
	uncle	O
	for	O
	one	O
	year	O
	but	O
	he	O
	mistreated	O
	me	O
	.	O
	So	O
	my	O
	aunt	O
	brought	O
	me	O
	to	O
	Amboseli	B-ORG
	place	I-ORG
	.	O
	She	O
	did	O
	nt	O
	want	O
	to	O
	look	O
	after	O
	me	O
	because	O
	she	O
	found	O
	i	O
	was	O
	HIV	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	It	O
	makes	O
	me	O
	sad	O
	that	O
	she	O
	did	O
	nt	O
	want	O
	me	O
	to	O
	live	O
	with	O
	her	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	nt	O
	my	O
	fault	O
	that	O
	i	O
	am	O
	HIV	O
	positive	O
	say	O
	Anne	B-ADLT
	.	O
	God	O
	is	O
	a	O
	secret	O
	which	O
	knows	O
	where	O
	i	O
	got	O
	my	O
	AIDS	O
	.	O
	Nyumbani	B-ORG
	children	I-ORG
	home	I-ORG
	rescued	O
	me	O
	and	O
	has	O
	given	O
	me	O
	a	O
	home	O
	thanks	O
	for	O
	being	O
	my	O
	family	O
	nyumbani	B-ORG
	for	O
	orphans	O
	and	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	I'm	O
	a	O
	happy	O
	girl	O
	i	O
	will	O
	survive	O
	and	O
	change	O
	negative	O
	attitudes	O
	towards	O
	HIV	O
	-	O
	positive	O
	people	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Detko	B-ORG
	Heart	I-ORG
	run	O
	a	O
	compaign	O
	to	O
	raise	O
	funds	O
	for	O
	treatment	O
	of	O
	underprivileged	O
	children	O
	with	O
	cardiac	O
	ailment	O
	.	O
	Veessa	B-ADLT
	was	O
	among	O
	the	O
	benefecieries	O
	through	O
	DETTO	B-ORG
	Antiseptic	I-ORG
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	to	O
	alliviate	O
	the	O
	suffering	O
	of	O
	ailing	O
	children	O
	who	O
	are	O
	able	O
	to	O
	afford	O
	the	O
	cost	O
	of	O
	cardiac	O
	treatment	O
	due	O
	to	O
	financial	O
	background	O
	.	O
	Venessa	B-ADLT
	comes	O
	from	O
	poor	O
	single	O
	family	O
	in	O
	mathare	B-LOC
	slums	I-LOC
	many	O
	people	O
	participated	O
	to	O
	save	O
	needy	O
	children	O
	.	O
	The	O
	funds	O
	of	O
	Dettol	B-ORG
	Heart	I-ORG
	Run	I-ORG
	helped	O
	treat	O
	23	O
	children	O
	in	O
	poor	O
	families	O
	which	O
	were	O
	identified	O
	with	O
	local	O
	community	O
	projects	O
	in	O
	slums	O
	.	O
	Through	O
	Matter	B-ORG
	hospital	I-ORG
	Venessa	B-ADLT
	was	O
	performed	O
	open	O
	Heart	O
	surgeries	O
	and	O
	was	O
	possible	O
	done	O
	virtually	O
	free	O
	to	O
	charge	O
	.	O
	She	O
	urges	O
	other	O
	companies	O
	to	O
	open	O
	heart	O
	surgeries	O
	to	O
	the	O
	unfortunate	O
	children	O
	is	O
	poor	O
	community	O
	and	O
	back	O
	ground	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Gibben	B-ORG
	Children	I-ORG
	Center	I-ORG
	is	O
	in	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	.	O
	Through	O
	Action	B-ORG
	Aid	I-ORG
	","	O
	which	O
	is	O
	an	O
	international	O
	organisation	O
	giving	O
	feeding	O
	programme	O
	to	O
	poor	O
	centers	O
	","	O
	its	O
	among	O
	the	O
	beneficieries	O
	The	O
	children	O
	have	O
	been	O
	provided	O
	with	O
	school	O
	uniforms	O
	","	O
	shoes	O
	","	O
	socks	O
	and	O
	as	O
	well	O
	as	O
	taking	O
	lunch	O
	as	O
	feeding	O
	programme	O
	in	O
	the	O
	center	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	children	O
	have	O
	benefited	O
	from	O
	the	O
	organisation	O
	through	O
	food	O
	and	O
	clothes	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	changed	O
	the	O
	community	O
	way	O
	of	O
	living	O
	.	O
	No	O
	hunger	O
	to	O
	children	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	to	O
	eradicate	O
	poverty	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	by	O
	empowering	O
	children	O
	lives	O
	and	O
	their	O
	families	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Tessy	B-ADLT
	is	O
	living	O
	in	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	.	O
	Oneday	O
	as	O
	she	O
	was	O
	starting	O
	at	O
	the	O
	cars	O
	passing	O
	nearby	O
	her	O
	school	O
	","	O
	a	O
	car	O
	stopped	O
	beside	O
	her	O
	.	O
	she	O
	was	O
	very	O
	beutiful	O
	girl	O
	.	O
	The	O
	man	O
	in	O
	the	O
	car	O
	asked	O
	if	O
	she	O
	wanted	O
	a	O
	ride	O
	.	O
	in	O
	his	O
	beautiful	O
	car	O
	.	O
	stupid	O
	Tessy	B-ADLT
	accepted	O
	.	O
	Tessy	B-ADLT
	went	O
	on	O
	seeing	O
	this	O
	man	O
	everytime	O
	sometime	O
	she	O
	can	O
	skip	O
	school	O
	and	O
	go	O
	spend	O
	time	O
	at	O
	his	O
	place	O
	in	O
	langata	B-LOC
	.	O
	The	O
	man	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	have	O
	an	O
	affair	O
	with	O
	with	O
	her	O
	.	O
	Soon	O
	she	O
	was	O
	trapped	O
	and	O
	caught	O
	pregnant	O
	.	O
	when	O
	she	O
	went	O
	to	O
	hospital	O
	she	O
	found	O
	she	O
	was	O
	HIV	O
	positive	O
	.	O
	wishes	O
	comes	O
	after	O
	.	O
	She	O
	cried	O
	day	O
	and	O
	night	O
	that	O
	she	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	commit	O
	suicide	O
	Mary	B-ADLT
	a	O
	community	O
	social	O
	worker	O
	is	O
	the	O
	one	O
	who	O
	helped	O
	her	O
	.	O
	She	O
	accepted	O
	now	O
	she	O
	is	O
	happy	O
	living	O
	with	O
	her	O
	daughter	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Ketrine	B-ADLT
	lives	O
	in	O
	U.	B-ORG
	S.	I-ORG
	A.	I-ORG
	She	O
	was	O
	once	O
	here	O
	in	O
	kenya	B-LOC
	2010	O
	.	O
	twor	O
	month	O
	ago	O
	she	O
	wrote	O
	aletter	O
	to	O
	anne	O
	who	O
	is	O
	the	O
	co	O
	-	O
	ordinator	O
	of	O
	Link	B-ORG
	Life	I-ORG
	welfare	I-ORG
	association	I-ORG
	.	O
	As	O
	she	O
	recall	O
	how	O
	Anne	B-ADLT
	helped	O
	her	O
	when	O
	she	O
	was	O
	here	O
	on	O
	volunteering	O
	service	O
	.	O
	She	O
	promised	O
	she	O
	will	O
	help	O
	and	O
	going	O
	to	O
	find	O
	funds	O
	to	O
	develop	O
	Life	B-ORG
	link	I-ORG
	social	I-ORG
	Development	I-ORG
	Group	I-ORG
	.	O
	One	O
	monthe	O
	ago	O
	Life	B-ORG
	link	I-ORG
	benefited	O
	from	O
	ketrine	B-LOC
	where	O
	she	O
	send	O
	1	O
	.	O
	5	O
	million	O
	to	O
	help	O
	women	O
	to	O
	start	O
	small	O
	","	O
	small	O
	business	O
	atleast	O
	to	O
	earn	O
	aliving	O
	.	O
	many	O
	women	O
	through	O
	life	O
	link	O
	are	O
	now	O
	self	O
	employed	O
	to	O
	eradicate	O
	change	O
	of	O
	poverty	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	through	O
	ketrine	B-ADLT
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Irene	B-MINR
	is	O
	an	O
	orphan	O
	girl	O
	but	O
	very	O
	beautiful	O
	and	O
	admirable	O
	.	O
	But	O
	one	O
	day	O
	she	O
	met	O
	a	O
	man	O
	on	O
	road	O
	who	O
	stopped	O
	and	O
	gave	O
	her	O
	lift	O
	to	O
	school	O
	.	O
	They	O
	exchanged	O
	numbers	O
	and	O
	talk	O
	.	O
	As	O
	time	O
	went	O
	on	O
	he	O
	talked	O
	to	O
	Irene	O
	into	O
	going	O
	to	O
	a	O
	park	O
	.	O
	In	O
	the	O
	park	O
	he	O
	started	O
	touching	O
	her	O
	breasts	O
	At	O
	the	O
	beginning	O
	she	O
	resisted	O
	a	O
	bit	O
	.	O
	One	O
	day	O
	the	O
	man	O
	took	O
	her	O
	to	O
	a	O
	hotel	O
	room	O
	and	O
	forced	O
	her	O
	to	O
	have	O
	sex	O
	.	O
	somehow	O
	this	O
	frightened	O
	Irene	B-MINR
	.	O
	She	O
	shared	O
	this	O
	with	O
	Ruth	B-ADLT
	a	O
	peer	O
	educator	O
	in	O
	school	O
	.	O
	Ruth	B-ADLT
	had	O
	been	O
	trained	O
	as	O
	a	O
	peer	O
	educator	O
	during	O
	a	O
	course	O
	that	O
	had	O
	been	O
	held	O
	in	O
	school	O
	.	O
	Ruth	B-ADLT
	was	O
	friendly	O
	A	O
	good	O
	listener	O
	and	O
	would	O
	not	O
	tell	O
	your	O
	secrets	O
	to	O
	other	O
	people	O
	.	O
	Ruth	B-ADLT
	adviced	O
	Irene	B-MINR
	never	O
	to	O
	take	O
	gifts	O
	or	O
	lifts	O
	from	O
	unknown	O
	.	O
	You	O
	should	O
	not	O
	allow	O
	a	O
	man	O
	to	O
	touch	O
	your	O
	body	O
	.	O
	advised	O
	the	O
	friend	O
	.	O
	Infact	O
	you	O
	must	O
	always	O
	say	O
	No	O
	to	O
	any	O
	bad	O
	behaviour	O
	.	O
	These	O
	day	O
	we	O
	have	O
	many	O
	diseases	O
	.	O
	You	O
	can	O
	get	O
	AIDS	O
	remember	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Hesbon	B-MINR
	used	O
	to	O
	be	O
	a	O
	street	O
	boy	O
	in	O
	Lenana	B-LOC
	","	O
	ngando	B-LOC
	","	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	and	O
	Kawangware	B-LOC
	.	O
	Sometimes	O
	he	O
	used	O
	to	O
	spend	O
	most	O
	his	O
	time	O
	on	O
	cyber	O
	cafe	O
	","	O
	browsing	O
	he	O
	had	O
	that	O
	knowledge	O
	before	O
	his	O
	parents	O
	passed	O
	away	O
	.	O
	When	O
	googling	O
	he	O
	saw	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	chapel	I-ORG
	church	I-ORG
	has	O
	sponsorship	O
	.	O
	He	O
	applied	O
	for	O
	sponsorship	O
	to	O
	be	O
	trained	O
	because	O
	he	O
	was	O
	a	O
	form	O
	two	O
	drop	O
	out	O
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	accepted	O
	through	O
	online	O
	application	O
	.	O
	He	O
	been	O
	trained	O
	as	O
	a	O
	consellour	O
	in	O
	the	O
	church	O
	now	O
	he	O
	is	O
	going	O
	around	O
	preading	O
	the	O
	word	O
	of	O
	God	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	and	O
	recruiting	O
	youth	O
	to	O
	join	O
	him	O
	and	O
	change	O
	the	O
	society	O
	.	O
	Church	O
	change	O
	his	O
	life	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Peter	B-MINR
	and	O
	Timo	B-MINR
	were	O
	young	O
	christians	O
	student	O
	at	O
	Ngondo	B-ORG
	Catholic	I-ORG
	Church	I-ORG
	.	O
	The	O
	like	O
	joining	O
	other	O
	christians	O
	in	O
	worship	O
	and	O
	prayer	O
	.	O
	During	O
	April	O
	holiday	O
	","	O
	they	O
	joined	O
	a	O
	youth	O
	fellowship	O
	meeting	O
	near	O
	by	O
	school	O
	.	O
	Good	B-ORG
	hope	I-ORG
	centre	I-ORG
	.	O
	During	O
	one	O
	week	O
	fellowship	O
	they	O
	joined	O
	the	O
	youth	O
	in	O
	prayer	O
	and	O
	charitable	O
	work	O
	.	O
	They	O
	visited	O
	the	O
	sickin	O
	their	O
	homes	O
	and	O
	prayed	O
	for	O
	them	O
	.	O
	They	O
	donated	O
	food	O
	in	O
	poor	O
	slums	O
	familiy	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	village	I-LOC
	.	O
	They	O
	prepared	O
	a	O
	house	O
	for	O
	an	O
	old	O
	woman	O
	.	O
	They	O
	listen	O
	to	O
	pastor	O
	's	O
	visiting	O
	talk	O
	.	O
	He	O
	urged	O
	them	O
	to	O
	lead	O
	christian	O
	lives	O
	.	O
	He	O
	always	O
	depend	O
	on	O
	God	O
	for	O
	their	O
	needs	O
	.	O
	And	O
	this	O
	will	O
	fight	O
	to	O
	change	O
	and	O
	eradicate	O
	poverty	O
	in	O
	our	O
	communities	O
	.	O
	Food	O
	was	O
	given	O
	to	O
	poor	O
	familie.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Bebe	B-ADLT
	cool	I-ADLT
	a	O
	ugandan	O
	based	O
	musician	O
	has	O
	donated	O
	his	O
	new	O
	Prado	B-ORG
	C3	I-ORG
	to	O
	the	O
	businessmen	O
	and	O
	women	O
	of	O
	Mutongo	B-LOC
	market	I-LOC
	after	O
	their	O
	business	O
	places	O
	were	O
	burnt	O
	from	O
	a	O
	strange	O
	fire	O
	which	O
	started	O
	at	O
	midnight	O
	was	O
	spread	O
	with	O
	strong	O
	winds	O
	from	O
	Ruwenzori	B-LOC
	mountains	I-LOC
	.	O
	Bebe	B-ADLT
	cool	I-ADLT
	the	O
	self	O
	proclaimed	O
	king	O
	of	O
	Raggea	O
	in	O
	Uganda	B-LOC
	said	O
	that	O
	the	O
	businessmen	O
	and	O
	women	O
	are	O
	the	O
	ones	O
	who	O
	have	O
	assisted	O
	him	O
	to	O
	buy	O
	all	O
	things	O
	he	O
	has	O
	including	O
	the	O
	Prado	O
	by	O
	selling	O
	his	O
	music	O
	","	O
	and	O
	this	O
	was	O
	his	O
	only	O
	way	O
	to	O
	show	O
	his	O
	gratitude	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	I	O
	dated	O
	aman	O
	who	O
	was	O
	positive	O
	but	O
	he	O
	did	O
	n't	O
	tell	O
	me	O
	his	O
	status	O
	.	O
	people	O
	were	O
	suprised	O
	when	O
	they	O
	realize	O
	it	O
	is	O
	not	O
	only	O
	friendship	O
	but	O
	we	O
	are	O
	in	O
	love	O
	.	O
	Sarah	B-ADLT
	recall	O
	.	O
	But	O
	before	O
	things	O
	got	O
	worse	O
	she	O
	was	O
	saved	O
	by	O
	three	O
	women	O
	in	O
	my	O
	community	O
	.	O
	Rabecca	B-ADLT
	","	O
	Lucy	B-ADLT
	and	O
	Elizabeth	B-ADLT
	asked	O
	if	O
	i	O
	was	O
	his	O
	girl	O
	friend	O
	i	O
	told	O
	them	O
	Yes	O
	and	O
	they	O
	told	O
	me	O
	to	O
	go	O
	for	O
	VCT	O
	.	O
	When	O
	i	O
	told	O
	my	O
	fiance	O
	about	O
	it	O
	he	O
	told	O
	me	O
	he	O
	has	O
	gone	O
	many	O
	hospital	O
	he	O
	is	O
	negative	O
	.	O
	He	O
	refused	O
	completely	O
	.	O
	Thus	O
	when	O
	i	O
	knew	O
	he	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	take	O
	advantage	O
	and	O
	infect	O
	meThanks	O
	for	O
	the	O
	ladies	O
	who	O
	save	O
	me	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Thankful	O
	for	O
	Finland	B-LOC
	which	O
	came	O
	to	O
	the	O
	community	O
	in	O
	rural	O
	to	O
	alleviate	O
	poverty	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	Busia	B-LOC
	county	I-LOC
	benefit	O
	from	O
	Finland	B-ORG
	Aid	I-ORG
	for	I-ORG
	development	I-ORG
	programme	I-ORG
	aimed	O
	at	O
	achieving	O
	poverty	O
	participaters	O
	in	O
	the	O
	development	O
	programmes	O
	in	O
	the	O
	region	O
	have	O
	welcomed	O
	the	O
	intiative	O
	.	O
	The	O
	money	O
	is	O
	meant	O
	to	O
	benefit	O
	the	O
	community	O
	and	O
	allaviate	O
	poverty	O
	through	O
	Education	O
	for	O
	sustainable	O
	development	O
	workshop	O
	they	O
	mobilized	O
	three	O
	communities	O
	in	O
	the	O
	county	O
	to	O
	identify	O
	the	O
	projects	O
	they	O
	would	O
	work	O
	on	O
	to	O
	make	O
	a	O
	positive	O
	impact	O
	on	O
	development	O
	that	O
	would	O
	enable	O
	people	O
	to	O
	improve	O
	their	O
	livelihood	O
	through	O
	grain	O
	storage	O
	and	O
	kitchen	O
	garden	O
	programmes	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Thankful	O
	for	O
	Finland	B-LOC
	which	O
	came	O
	to	O
	the	O
	community	O
	in	O
	rural	O
	to	O
	alleviate	O
	poverty	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	Busia	B-LOC
	county	I-LOC
	benefit	O
	from	O
	Finland	B-ORG
	Aid	I-ORG
	for	I-ORG
	development	I-ORG
	programme	I-ORG
	aimed	O
	at	O
	achieving	O
	poverty	O
	participaters	O
	in	O
	the	O
	development	O
	programmes	O
	in	O
	the	O
	region	O
	have	O
	welcomed	O
	the	O
	intiative	O
	.	O
	The	O
	money	O
	is	O
	meant	O
	to	O
	benefit	O
	the	O
	community	O
	and	O
	allaviate	O
	poverty	O
	through	O
	Education	O
	for	O
	sustainable	O
	development	O
	workshop	O
	they	O
	mobilized	O
	three	O
	communities	O
	in	O
	the	O
	county	O
	to	O
	identify	O
	the	O
	projects	O
	they	O
	would	O
	work	O
	on	O
	to	O
	make	O
	a	O
	positive	O
	impact	O
	on	O
	development	O
	that	O
	would	O
	enable	O
	people	O
	to	O
	improve	O
	their	O
	livelihood	O
	through	O
	grain	O
	storage	O
	and	O
	kitchen	O
	garden	O
	programmes	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Aluda	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	carpenter	O
	on	O
	Ngong	B-LOC
	road	I-LOC
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	formed	O
	an	O
	organisation	O
	for	O
	youth	O
	in	O
	Lenana	B-ORG
	Community	I-ORG
	.	O
	He	O
	came	O
	out	O
	with	O
	this	O
	idea	O
	when	O
	many	O
	young	O
	youth	O
	working	O
	coming	O
	each	O
	asking	O
	for	O
	job	O
	.	O
	eithe	O
	sand	O
	paper	O
	.	O
	Aluda	B-ADLT
	has	O
	employed	O
	youth	O
	","	O
	training	O
	them	O
	how	O
	to	O
	curve	O
	pictures	O
	","	O
	making	O
	sofa	O
	sets	O
	","	O
	Table	O
	","	O
	chairs	O
	and	O
	many	O
	many	O
	carving	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	boosted	O
	the	O
	community	O
	where	O
	by	O
	idleness	O
	and	O
	poverty	O
	among	O
	the	O
	youth	O
	has	O
	reduced	O
	.	O
	There	O
	's	O
	a	O
	big	O
	change	O
	in	O
	Lenana	B-ORG
	Community	I-ORG
	on	I-ORG
	Youth	I-ORG
	as	O
	well	O
	as	O
	the	O
	society	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Bravo	O
	to	O
	Doshi	B-ORG
	group	I-ORG
	for	O
	the	O
	work	O
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	feeding	O
	children	O
	especially	O
	orphans	O
	and	O
	needy	O
	.	O
	Through	O
	Dosh	B-ORG
	group	I-ORG
	Ngando	B-ORG
	Universal	I-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	was	O
	given	O
	food	O
	to	O
	feed	O
	the	O
	needy	O
	.	O
	This	O
	is	O
	where	O
	we	O
	introduce	O
	feeding	O
	program	O
	in	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	.	O
	Thanks	O
	Doshi	B-ADLT
	for	O
	overcoming	O
	hunger	O
	achieving	O
	food	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Osore	O
	lives	O
	in	O
	Dunga	B-LOC
	Kisumu	I-LOC
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	formed	O
	young	O
	youth	O
	fish	O
	farming	O
	project	O
	in	O
	rural	O
	Kisumu	B-LOC
	.	O
	Youth	O
	are	O
	being	O
	trained	O
	how	O
	to	O
	do	O
	fish	O
	farming	O
	in	O
	their	O
	community	O
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	a	O
	big	O
	storage	O
	for	O
	fish	O
	where	O
	he	O
	has	O
	employed	O
	some	O
	youth	O
	to	O
	do	O
	business	O
	.	O
	Go	O
	along	O
	sea	O
	shore	O
	of	O
	lake	O
	","	O
	to	O
	catch	O
	fish	O
	in	O
	the	O
	lake	O
	with	O
	nets	O
	.	O
	They	O
	catch	O
	many	O
	fish	O
	then	O
	transport	O
	them	O
	to	O
	Kisumu	B-LOC
	where	O
	from	O
	Kisumu	B-LOC
	are	O
	being	O
	brought	O
	to	O
	Nairobi	B-LOC
	.	O
	Many	O
	orders	O
	are	O
	being	O
	given	O
	to	O
	the	O
	project	O
	to	O
	make	O
	them	O
	atleast	O
	earn	O
	a	O
	living	O
	especially	O
	to	O
	youth	O
	.	O
	This	O
	project	O
	has	O
	modeled	O
	many	O
	youth	O
	and	O
	changed	O
	them	O
	completely	O
	through	O
	idleness	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Kata	B-MINR
	comes	O
	from	O
	poor	O
	family	O
	.	O
	He	O
	did	O
	n't	O
	know	O
	he	O
	will	O
	come	O
	as	O
	best	O
	in	O
	k	B-OTHR
	c.	I-OTHR
	p.	I-OTHR
	e	I-OTHR
	exam	O
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	wondering	O
	who	O
	will	O
	pay	O
	for	O
	his	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	.	O
	Kata	B-MINR
	family	O
	lived	O
	in	O
	poverty	O
	.	O
	When	O
	the	O
	result	O
	were	O
	out	O
	Kata	B-MINR
	was	O
	not	O
	aware	O
	what	O
	he	O
	got	O
	.	O
	So	O
	in	O
	the	O
	mid	O
	day	O
	his	O
	mother	O
	was	O
	very	O
	sick	O
	.	O
	he	O
	was	O
	shocked	O
	to	O
	find	O
	more	O
	cars	O
	and	O
	people	O
	at	O
	home	O
	.	O
	He	O
	become	O
	uncomfortable	O
	thinking	O
	the	O
	had	O
	come	O
	to	O
	see	O
	his	O
	mother	O
	because	O
	she	O
	had	O
	fainted	O
	.	O
	They	O
	had	O
	note	O
	book	O
	","	O
	cameras	O
	","	O
	microphones	O
	but	O
	they	O
	looked	O
	like	O
	reporters	O
	.	O
	where	O
	is	O
	Kata?One	B-MINR
	of	O
	them	O
	asked	O
	.	O
	That	O
	's	O
	my	O
	name	O
	","	O
	what	O
	has	O
	he	O
	done	O
	?	O
	He	O
	scored	O
	470	O
	marks	O
	out	O
	500	O
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	ladies	O
	said	O
	.	O
	Tears	O
	of	O
	joy	O
	came	O
	out	O
	of	O
	Kata	B-MINR
	's	O
	mother	O
	as	O
	reporter	O
	recorded	O
	.	O
	One	O
	of	O
	reporter	O
	looked	O
	at	O
	Kata	B-MINR
	.	O
	I	O
	wo	O
	nt	O
	continue	O
	with	O
	my	O
	school	O
	because	O
	i	O
	do	O
	n't	O
	have	O
	fees	O
	i	O
	am	O
	going	O
	to	O
	look	O
	for	O
	a	O
	job	O
	in	O
	Nairobi	B-LOC
	to	O
	help	O
	my	O
	family	O
	.	O
	Kata	B-MINR
	wo	O
	n't	O
	work	O
	.	O
	one	O
	of	O
	them	O
	said	O
	.	O
	we	O
	are	O
	from	O
	organization	O
	that	O
	helps	O
	children	O
	from	O
	poor	O
	families	O
	.	O
	Your	O
	school	O
	fees	O
	will	O
	be	O
	paid	O
	with	O
	us	O
	.	O
	People	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	were	O
	happy	O
	and	O
	relatives	O
	for	O
	Kata	B-MINR
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	In	O
	the	O
	shores	O
	of	O
	lake	B-LOC
	Victoria	I-LOC
	there	O
	is	O
	a	O
	port	O
	in	O
	Busia	B-LOC
	knows	O
	as	O
	port	B-LOC
	Victoria	I-LOC
	.	O
	The	O
	community	O
	around	O
	that	O
	place	O
	are	O
	mostly	O
	fishermen	O
	.	O
	Women	O
	in	O
	that	O
	area	O
	dwell	O
	around	O
	fish	O
	","	O
	and	O
	that	O
	is	O
	why	O
	they	O
	are	O
	always	O
	","	O
	selling	O
	fish	O
	","	O
	dried	O
	","	O
	smoked	O
	","	O
	fresh	O
	fish	O
	from	O
	the	O
	lake	O
	.	O
	And	O
	that	O
	is	O
	why	O
	H.	O
	I.	O
	V	O
	Aids	O
	is	O
	always	O
	rumpant	O
	in	O
	that	O
	area	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	C	B-ORG
	F	I-ORG
	C	I-ORG
	Life	I-ORG
	is	O
	changing	O
	the	O
	lives	O
	of	O
	orphans	O
	in	O
	poor	O
	communities	O
	and	O
	urban	O
	slums	O
	.	O
	most	O
	of	O
	the	O
	pupils	O
	who	O
	attain	O
	300	O
	marks	O
	in	O
	K.	B-OTHR
	C.	I-OTHR
	P.	I-OTHR
	E	I-OTHR
	are	O
	adviced	O
	to	O
	apply	O
	through	O
	C.	B-ORG
	F.	I-ORG
	C	I-ORG
	club	I-ORG
	for	O
	sponsorship	O
	or	O
	busury	O
	.	O
	Amina	B-ADLT
	is	O
	an	O
	orphan	O
	but	O
	C.	B-ORG
	F.	I-ORG
	C	I-ORG
	has	O
	changed	O
	her	O
	life	O
	.	O
	I	O
	took	O
	her	O
	result	O
	slip	O
	and	O
	gave	O
	to	O
	Martin	B-ADLT
	Maila	I-ADLT
	who	O
	is	O
	a	O
	member	O
	and	O
	an	O
	employ	O
	in	O
	C.	B-ORG
	F.	I-ORG
	C	I-ORG
	life	O
	.	O
	Amina	B-ADLT
	was	O
	desparate	O
	","	O
	worried	O
	","	O
	crying	O
	what	O
	her	O
	life	O
	will	O
	be	O
	is	O
	not	O
	continue	O
	with	O
	her	O
	education	O
	.	O
	Martin	B-ADLT
	struggled	O
	to	O
	help	O
	Amina	B-ADLT
	and	O
	now	O
	is	O
	among	O
	those	O
	who	O
	are	O
	beneficiaries	O
	from	O
	C.	B-ORG
	F.	I-ORG
	C	I-ORG
	life	O
	.	O
	paying	O
	fees	O
	","	O
	shoppng	O
	and	O
	clothing	O
	she	O
	can	O
	afford	O
	to	O
	laugh	O
	and	O
	encourage	O
	the	O
	needy	O
	desparate	O
	to	O
	work	O
	hard	O
	C.	B-ORG
	F.	I-ORG
	c	I-ORG
	life	I-ORG
	can	O
	change	O
	their	O
	lives	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Nancy	B-ADLT
	is	O
	in	O
	standard	O
	Seven	O
	.	O
	At	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	Chapel	I-ORG
	academy	I-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	.	O
	She	O
	grew	O
	up	O
	going	O
	to	O
	church	O
	and	O
	following	O
	the	O
	rules	O
	of	O
	God	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	obedient	O
	to	O
	her	O
	grand	O
	parents	O
	who	O
	brought	O
	her	O
	in	O
	christian	O
	way	O
	.	O
	Though	O
	her	O
	parent	O
	passed	O
	away	O
	three	O
	years	O
	back	O
	in	O
	road	O
	accident	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	obedient	O
	to	O
	teachers	O
	other	O
	children	O
	and	O
	all	O
	community	O
	.	O
	She	O
	kept	O
	reading	O
	bible	O
	and	O
	praying	O
	always	O
	.	O
	Nancy	B-ADLT
	came	O
	to	O
	be	O
	as	O
	humble	O
	as	O
	an	O
	example	O
	given	O
	by	O
	Jesus	B-ADLT
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	loved	O
	by	O
	everyone	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	made	O
	as	O
	head	O
	prefect	O
	in	O
	school	O
	and	O
	a	O
	leader	O
	in	O
	youth	O
	church	O
	.	O
	Everybody	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	loved	O
	her	O
	.	O
	Good	O
	things	O
	happen	O
	to	O
	people	O
	who	O
	obey	O
	God	O
	.	O
	Nancy	B-ADLT
	now	O
	is	O
	being	O
	sponsored	O
	by	O
	church	O
	and	O
	now	O
	through	O
	her	O
	a	O
	program	O
	has	O
	been	O
	formed	O
	.	O
	Grooming	O
	leadership	O
	network	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Small	O
	girls	O
	in	O
	many	O
	different	O
	interior	O
	communite	O
	suffer	O
	from	O
	the	O
	cut	O
	.	O
	Most	O
	of	O
	them	O
	seek	O
	shelter	O
	from	O
	nearby	O
	churches	O
	or	O
	schools	O
	.	O
	FGM	O
	specialised	O
	mostly	O
	in	O
	the	O
	Kisii	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	and	O
	Nandi	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	.	O
	A	O
	friend	O
	of	O
	mine	O
	from	O
	the	O
	UN	B-ORG
	together	O
	with	O
	some	O
	NGO	O
	's	O
	form	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	are	O
	lying	O
	hard	O
	to	O
	stop	O
	the	O
	torture	O
	on	O
	our	O
	girls	O
	.	O
	They	O
	try	O
	to	O
	set	O
	up	O
	girl	O
	school	O
	only	O
	in	O
	order	O
	to	O
	help	O
	those	O
	who	O
	run	O
	away	O
	from	O
	'	O
	cut	O
	'	O
	.	O
	It	O
	is	O
	understood	O
	that	O
	if	O
	a	O
	girl	O
	child	O
	refuses	O
	to	O
	go	O
	through	O
	the	O
	'	O
	cut	O
	'	O
	they	O
	are	O
	tortured	O
	to	O
	death	O
	.	O
	The	O
	members	O
	of	O
	parliament	O
	are	O
	readily	O
	lying	O
	had	O
	to	O
	put	O
	this	O
	bill	O
	that	O
	forbids	O
	FGM	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Rose	B-ADLT
	had	O
	a	O
	friend	O
	called	O
	Joan	B-ADLT
	.	O
	They	O
	spent	O
	most	O
	of	O
	their	O
	free	O
	time	O
	together	O
	if	O
	Joan	B-ADLT
	was	O
	not	O
	in	O
	school	O
	","	O
	her	O
	friend	O
	Rose	B-ADLT
	did	O
	not	O
	enjoy	O
	her	O
	school	O
	work	O
	that	O
	day	O
	.	O
	Joan	B-ADLT
	was	O
	very	O
	kind	O
	and	O
	loving	O
	.	O
	She	O
	loved	O
	Rose	B-ADLT
	as	O
	a	O
	sister	O
	.	O
	They	O
	enjoyed	O
	doing	O
	their	O
	work	O
	together	O
	.	O
	Rose	B-ADLT
	was	O
	faithful	O
	to	O
	her	O
	friend	O
	and	O
	never	O
	did	O
	anything	O
	she	O
	knew	O
	would	O
	make	O
	her	O
	angry	O
	.	O
	Their	O
	friendship	O
	went	O
	to	O
	high	O
	school	O
	","	O
	university	O
	up	O
	to	O
	now	O
	they	O
	are	O
	both	O
	married	O
	but	O
	still	O
	the	O
	friendship	O
	is	O
	there	O
	.	O
	They	O
	are	O
	now	O
	helping	O
	needy	O
	young	O
	girls	O
	where	O
	they	O
	have	O
	open	O
	tailoring	O
	training	O
	to	O
	young	O
	girls	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	at	O
	Gorokocho	B-LOC
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Vision	O
	comes	O
	through	O
	I	O
	with	O
	the	O
	singleness	O
	of	O
	opinion	O
	","	O
	desire	O
	and	O
	mind	O
	.	O
	Its	O
	prudent	O
	to	O
	have	O
	Vision	O
	goal	O
	at	O
	time	O
	.	O
	Thus	O
	what	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	is	O
	doing	O
	to	O
	the	O
	people	O
	in	O
	Community	O
	.	O
	Ngando	B-ORG
	Universal	I-ORG
	Centre	I-ORG
	Parsue	I-ORG
	one	O
	of	O
	the	O
	goal	O
	through	O
	Global	B-ORG
	Giving	I-ORG
	.	O
	We	O
	are	O
	concerned	O
	with	O
	reaching	O
	the	O
	apex	O
	of	O
	our	O
	Vision	O
	.	O
	Thanks	O
	Global	B-ORG
	for	O
	changing	O
	children	O
	and	O
	community	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Wainaina	B-ADLT
	lived	O
	in	O
	Kariobangi	B-LOC
	slum	I-LOC
	in	O
	Eastland	B-LOC
	area	I-LOC
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	born	O
	as	O
	second	O
	in	O
	family	O
	of	O
	three	O
	.	O
	His	O
	parent	O
	seperated	O
	when	O
	they	O
	were	O
	very	O
	young	O
	.	O
	His	O
	mother	O
	hawked	O
	vegetable	O
	for	O
	living	O
	.	O
	Despite	O
	the	O
	hardship	O
	she	O
	faced	O
	she	O
	managed	O
	to	O
	educate	O
	them	O
	all	O
	.	O
	After	O
	he	O
	attended	O
	Gatunyi	B-ORG
	primary	I-ORG
	he	O
	joined	O
	high	O
	school	O
	where	O
	he	O
	passed	O
	.	O
	He	O
	determined	O
	to	O
	get	O
	out	O
	of	O
	poverty	O
	through	O
	education	O
	.	O
	He	O
	joined	O
	Kabete	B-ORG
	Technical	I-ORG
	as	O
	mechanic	O
	engineering	O
	to	O
	two	O
	yrs	O
	and	O
	motivate	O
	2	O
	other	O
	years	O
	for	O
	engineering	O
	and	O
	got	O
	skills	O
	.	O
	He	O
	tried	O
	to	O
	generate	O
	electricity	O
	using	O
	biogas	O
	from	O
	his	O
	pit	O
	.	O
	He	O
	opened	O
	a	O
	workshop	O
	and	O
	office	O
	to	O
	train	O
	young	O
	boys	O
	in	O
	biogas	O
	.	O
	He	O
	has	O
	his	O
	own	O
	foundation	O
	which	O
	is	O
	helping	O
	the	O
	community	O
	to	O
	generate	O
	small	O
	income	O
	to	O
	youth	O
	as	O
	he	O
	went	O
	through	O
	hardship	O
	.	O
	He	O
	is	O
	improving	O
	young	O
	stars	O
	way	O
	of	O
	like	O
	in	O
	kariobangi	B-LOC
	slums	I-LOC
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Umande	B-ORG
	Trust	I-ORG
	helping	O
	slum	O
	especially	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	.	O
	They	O
	build	O
	toilets	O
	and	O
	bathroom	O
	.	O
	Many	O
	projects	O
	in	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	have	O
	been	O
	funded	O
	by	O
	Umande	B-ORG
	Trust	I-ORG
	.	O
	Thanks	O
	Umande	B-ORG
	Trust	I-ORG
	foundation	I-ORG
	for	O
	the	O
	work	O
	they	O
	are	O
	doing	O
	in	O
	slum	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Lucy	B-ADLT
	lives	O
	in	O
	Lenana	B-LOC
	","	I-LOC
	Ngando	I-LOC
	village	I-LOC
	in	O
	dagoretti	B-LOC
	.	O
	she	O
	went	O
	to	O
	Nairobi	B-ORG
	chapel	I-ORG
	and	O
	told	O
	the	O
	pastor	O
	i	O
	know	O
	I	O
	am	O
	a	O
	sinner	O
	but	O
	help	O
	me	O
	see	O
	way	O
	forward	O
	.	O
	Ihave	O
	been	O
	in	O
	prostitution	O
	since	O
	i	O
	was	O
	12	O
	years	O
	old	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	crying	O
	and	O
	other	O
	people	O
	said	O
	to	O
	be	O
	sent	O
	away	O
	but	O
	pastor	O
	refused	O
	.	O
	Lucy	B-ADLT
	told	O
	pastor	O
	i	O
	am	O
	a	O
	big	O
	dog	O
	as	O
	there	O
	is	O
	","	O
	but	O
	even	O
	dog	O
	as	O
	there	O
	is	O
	.	O
	but	O
	even	O
	dogs	O
	eat	O
	the	O
	crumbs	O
	which	O
	fall	O
	from	O
	their	O
	masters	O
	table	O
	she	O
	would	O
	nt	O
	give	O
	up	O
	.	O
	Pastor	O
	told	O
	her	O
	woman	O
	great	O
	is	O
	your	O
	faith	O
	.	O
	be	O
	it	O
	unto	O
	you	O
	even	O
	as	O
	you	O
	he	O
	knew	O
	God	O
	wanted	O
	and	O
	forgive	O
	her	O
	and	O
	bless	O
	her	O
	every	O
	gift	O
	and	O
	perfect	O
	gift	O
	come	O
	from	O
	father	O
	light	O
	she	O
	is	O
	saved	O
	serving	O
	lord	O
	and	O
	her	O
	community	O
	in	O
	church	O
	.	O
	she	O
	is	O
	turning	O
	other	O
	women	O
	to	O
	God	O
	to	O
	change	O
	their	O
	life	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	The	O
	introduction	O
	of	O
	internet	O
	use	O
	is	O
	a	O
	very	O
	good	O
	investment	O
	for	O
	a	O
	school	O
	like	O
	Chavakali	B-ORG
	High	I-ORG
	School	I-ORG
	in	O
	the	O
	past	O
	it	O
	had	O
	no	O
	contact	O
	with	O
	the	O
	outside	O
	world	O
	until	O
	when	O
	our	O
	new	O
	principal	O
	Mr	B-ADLT
	Indimuli	I-ADLT
	Kahi	I-ADLT
	with	O
	partnership	O
	with	O
	safaricom	B-ORG
	managed	O
	to	O
	get	O
	the	O
	school	O
	connected	O
	.	O
	This	O
	inciative	O
	has	O
	assisted	O
	the	O
	Chavakali	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	atlarge	O
	and	O
	the	O
	students	O
	to	O
	be	O
	at	O
	per	O
	with	O
	the	O
	fast	O
	moving	O
	era	O
	of	O
	computer	O
	and	O
	internet	O
	.	O
	The	O
	school	O
	can	O
	now	O
	communicate	O
	with	O
	the	O
	outside	O
	world	O
	hence	O
	creating	O
	opportunity	O
	to	O
	get	O
	scholarships	O
	and	O
	jobs	O
	for	O
	the	O
	locals	O
	of	O
	Chavakali	B-LOC
	and	O
	its	O
	neighbours	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Cornelius	B-ADLT
	use	O
	to	O
	drink	O
	day	O
	","	O
	night	O
	he	O
	did	O
	n't	O
	care	O
	about	O
	life	O
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	time	O
	he	O
	realized	O
	her	O
	former	O
	girlfriend	O
	died	O
	with	O
	Aids	O
	.	O
	He	O
	was	O
	in	O
	denial	O
	about	O
	his	O
	status	O
	about	O
	his	O
	HIV	O
	status	O
	.	O
	He	O
	became	O
	suicidal	O
	and	O
	started	O
	drinking	O
	heavily	O
	.	O
	I	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	die	O
	","	O
	he	O
	said	O
	.	O
	During	O
	one	O
	of	O
	his	O
	drinking	O
	Speers	O
	","	O
	He	O
	became	O
	so	O
	drunk	O
	and	O
	disorderly	O
	that	O
	his	O
	friends	O
	could	O
	take	O
	it	O
	any	O
	more	O
	.	O
	they	O
	forcefully	O
	dragged	O
	him	O
	to	O
	the	O
	Association	B-ORG
	of	I-ORG
	people	I-ORG
	living	O
	with	O
	AIDS	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	TAPWAK	B-ORG
	offices	O
	based	O
	South	B-LOC
	c.	I-LOC
	TAPWAK	B-ORG
	helped	O
	cornelius	O
	and	O
	now	O
	he	O
	lead	O
	life	O
	acceptance	O
	.	O
	I	O
	found	O
	most	O
	kind	O
	and	O
	patient	O
	people	O
	who	O
	understand	O
	my	O
	plight	O
	.	O
	I	O
	can	O
	now	O
	talk	O
	about	O
	it	O
	and	O
	I	O
	am	O
	proud	O
	of	O
	TAPWAK	B-ORG
	for	O
	changing	O
	me	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Through	O
	generation	O
	for	O
	change	O
	and	O
	growth	O
	Edna	B-ADLT
	's	O
	life	O
	has	O
	really	O
	changed	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	model	O
	Edina	B-ADLT
	through	O
	education	O
	and	O
	now	O
	Edina	B-ADLT
	is	O
	a	O
	graduate	O
	in	O
	community	O
	health	O
	.	O
	Edina	B-ADLT
	is	O
	among	O
	the	O
	youth	O
	who	O
	are	O
	changing	O
	the	O
	other	O
	youth	O
	in	O
	Ngando	B-LOC
	","	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	and	O
	Lenana	B-LOC
	.	O
	They	O
	go	O
	round	O
	with	O
	her	O
	group	O
	helding	O
	vocational	O
	training	O
	for	O
	youth	O
	hw	O
	they	O
	can	O
	be	O
	leaders	O
	and	O
	change	O
	community	O
	live	O
	of	O
	living	O
	.	O
	The	O
	modelling	O
	and	O
	bringing	O
	generation	O
	for	O
	better	O
	world	O
	tomorrow	O
	through	O
	seminars	O
	and	O
	vocational	O
	training	O
	in	O
	Ngendo	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	If	O
	you	O
	have	O
	attitudes	O
	is	O
	everything	O
	say	O
	my	O
	friend	O
	Judy	B-ADLT
	who	O
	was	O
	trapped	O
	into	O
	marriage	O
	coming	O
	to	O
	realize	O
	it	O
	","	O
	It	O
	was	O
	too	O
	late	O
	for	O
	her	O
	to	O
	come	O
	out	O
	.	O
	The	O
	man	O
	was	O
	positive	O
	and	O
	had	O
	been	O
	changing	O
	women	O
	severally	O
	.	O
	Judy	B-ADLT
	found	O
	it	O
	when	O
	she	O
	was	O
	pregnant	O
	.	O
	Elizabeth	B-ADLT
	concelled	O
	her	O
	and	O
	gave	O
	her	O
	advice	O
	because	O
	she	O
	wanted	O
	to	O
	commit	O
	suicide	O
	.	O
	Elizabeth	B-ADLT
	told	O
	her	O
	you	O
	should	O
	have	O
	attitudes	O
	which	O
	is	O
	everything	O
	and	O
	you	O
	will	O
	live	O
	longer	O
	.	O
	Now	O
	Judy	B-ADLT
	is	O
	happy	O
	","	O
	her	O
	boy	O
	is	O
	healthy	O
	after	O
	following	O
	Doctor	O
	advice	O
	and	O
	they	O
	are	O
	living	O
	happy	O
	and	O
	comfortable	O
	life	O
	.	O
	with	O
	her	O
	boy	O
	.	O
	Thanks	O
	to	O
	Elizabeth	B-ADLT
	chang.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Dagoretti	B-ORG
	community	I-ORG
	health	I-ORG
	centre	I-ORG
	was	O
	open	O
	to	O
	give	O
	free	O
	medical	O
	camps	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
	to	O
	serve	O
	poor	O
	people	O
	in	O
	slums	O
	.	O
	of	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	.	O
	It	O
	was	O
	started	O
	by	O
	an	O
	organisation	O
	from	O
	U.	B-ORG
	S.	I-ORG
	A	O
	called	O
	save	O
	African	B-ORG
	Children	I-ORG
	.	O
	This	O
	was	O
	to	O
	eradicate	O
	poverty	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	it	O
	is	O
	offering	O
	free	O
	services	O
	to	O
	orphans	O
	under	O
	low	O
	payment	O
	of	O
	medicinesto	B-LOC
	keep	O
	the	O
	clinic	O
	going	O
	.	O
	It	O
	has	O
	really	O
	improve	O
	the	O
	health	O
	life	O
	of	O
	many	O
	vulnerable	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	It	O
	was	O
	valentine	O
	day	O
	when	O
	Juliet	B-ADLT
	lost	O
	her	O
	both	O
	parents	O
	.	O
	Father	O
	Juliet	B-ADLT
	told	O
	mother	O
	Juliet	B-ADLT
	they	O
	are	O
	going	O
	out	O
	for	O
	dinner	O
	in	O
	the	O
	evening	O
	as	O
	the	O
	day	O
	tells	O
	itself	O
	.	O
	They	O
	out	O
	in	O
	Kawangare	B-LOC
	bar	O
	where	O
	the	O
	husband	O
	started	O
	drinking	O
	and	O
	ordered	O
	meat	O
	[	O
	roasted]They	O
	started	O
	an	O
	argument	O
	where	O
	they	O
	involved	O
	in	O
	fighting	O
	.	O
	tHe	O
	people	O
	around	O
	stopped	O
	the	O
	fight	O
	.	O
	They	O
	moved	O
	to	O
	another	O
	bar	O
	nearby	O
	where	O
	the	O
	woman	O
	took	O
	a	O
	penknife	O
	from	O
	her	O
	husband	O
	pocket	O
	and	O
	stabled	O
	him	O
	.	O
	Then	O
	she	O
	stabble	O
	herself	O
	living	O
	Juliet	B-MINR
	orphan	O
	.	O
	Juliet	B-MINR
	has	O
	been	O
	adopted	O
	by	O
	Hidden	B-ORG
	Talent	I-ORG
	because	O
	she	O
	had	O
	nowhere	O
	to	O
	go	O
	no	O
	family	O
	.	O
	Hidden	O
	Talent	O
	is	O
	really	O
	helping	O
	the	O
	orphans	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Elca	B-ADLT
	for	O
	women	O
	around	O
	the	O
	world	O
	ha	O
	been	O
	improving	O
	and	O
	building	O
	of	O
	strong	O
	body	O
	for	O
	women	O
	","	O
	girls	O
	and	O
	children	O
	in	O
	Dagoretti	B-LOC
	Community	I-LOC
	Area	I-LOC
	.	O
	Through	O
	corner	O
	stone	O
	church	O
	they	O
	are	O
	helding	O
	many	O
	free	O
	medical	O
	camp	O
	for	O
	women	O
	and	O
	children	O
	.	O
	People	O
	from	O
	poor	O
	community	O
	Kawangware	B-LOC
	","	I-LOC
	Ngando	I-LOC
	","	O
	Lenana	B-ADLT
	Wanyee	I-ADLT
	were	O
	among	O
	the	O
	beneficiaries	O
	medical	O
	prevention	O
	and	O
	treatment	O
	were	O
	given	O
	to	O
	poor	O
	women	O
	it	O
	really	O
	changes	O
	community	O
	people	O
	health	O
	life	O
	and	O
	we	O
	should	O
	move	O
	camps	O
	campains	O
	in	O
	the	O
	communit.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	John	B-ORG
	cames	O
	from	O
	Siaya	B-LOC
	he	O
	had	O
	two	O
	wives	O
	.	O
	One	O
	was	O
	older	O
	than	O
	the	O
	other	O
	one	O
	.	O
	He	O
	decided	O
	to	O
	put	O
	them	O
	live	O
	together	O
	in	O
	the	O
	same	O
	compound	O
	.	O
	Two	O
	months	O
	ago	O
	they	O
	broke	O
	into	O
	a	O
	quarrel	O
	.	O
	They	O
	fought	O
	one	O
	another	O
	.	O
	the	O
	younger	O
	wife	O
	was	O
	Julie	B-ADLT
	she	O
	was	O
	forced	O
	to	O
	marry	O
	the	O
	man	O
	by	O
	her	O
	parents	O
	.	O
	She	O
	was	O
	a	O
	standard	O
	6	O
	dropout	O
	.	O
	Due	O
	to	O
	her	O
	age	O
	the	O
	other	O
	wife	O
	used	O
	to	O
	mistreat	O
	her	O
	.	O
	But	O
	their	O
	husband	O
	was	O
	polite	O
	man	O
	it	O
	forced	O
	the	O
	community	O
	to	O
	interviene	O
	.	O
	They	O
	went	O
	to	O
	chief	O
	area	O
	to	O
	help	O
	the	O
	younger	O
	wife	O
	.	O
	John	B-ORG
	was	O
	forced	O
	to	O
	build	O
	a	O
	house	O
	far	O
	from	O
	the	O
	wife	O
	for	O
	Julie	B-ADLT
	.	O
	The	O
	community	O
	elder	O
	forced	O
	John	B-ORG
	to	O
	tale	O
	Julie	B-ADLT
	back	O
	to	O
	school	O
	Though	O
	Julie	B-ADLT
	has	O
	two	O
	children	O
	but	O
	she	O
	is	O
	happy	O
	to	O
	finish	O
	her	O
	school	O
	and	O
	determined	O
	to	O
	change	O
	other	O
	girls	O
	n	O
	the	O
	community	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	John	B-ADLT
	and	O
	Wekesa	B-ADLT
	were	O
	digging	O
	a	O
	pit	O
	latrine	O
	.	O
	they	O
	had	O
	dug	O
	about	O
	fiften	O
	feet	O
	.	O
	Wekes	B-ADLT
	was	O
	in	O
	the	O
	hole	O
	while	O
	John	B-ADLT
	was	O
	up	O
	pulling	O
	the	O
	stone	O
	in	O
	a	O
	bucket	O
	and	O
	pouring	O
	the	O
	out	O
	.	O
	Out	O
	of	O
	nowhere	O
	the	O
	walls	O
	of	O
	the	O
	hole	O
	gave	O
	in	O
	and	O
	Wekesa	B-ADLT
	was	O
	buried	O
	alife	O
	.	O
	John	B-ADLT
	screamed	O
	for	O
	help	O
	.	O
	Fortunatel	O
	for	O
	Wekese	B-ORG
	people	O
	were	O
	able	O
	to	O
	rescue	O
	he	O
	.	O
	He	O
	sustained	O
	minor	O
	injuries	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	It	O
	is	O
	a	O
	good	O
	thing	O
	seeing	O
	how	O
	the	O
	Kibera	B-LOC
	society	O
	is	O
	embracing	O
	back	O
	those	O
	with	O
	HIV	O
	and	O
	AIDS	O
	.	O
	Its	O
	a	O
	good	O
	thing	O
	to	O
	see	O
	the	O
	end	O
	of	O
	stigmatization	O
	against	O
	those	O
	living	O
	with	O
	the	O
	virus	O
	.	O
	Amref	B-ORG
	has	O
	planned	O
	","	O
	a	O
	major	O
	role	O
	in	O
	ensuring	O
	that	O
	those	O
	with	O
	virus	O
	are	O
	living	O
	positively	O
	while	O
	those	O
	without	O
	the	O
	virus	O
	are	O
	embracing	O
	them	O
	into	O
	the	O
	society	O
	and	O
	help	O
	them	O
	put	O
	their	O
	lives	O
	back	O
	on	O
	track	O
	after	O
	the	O
	traumatic	O
	revelation	O
	of	O
	their	O
	status	O
	.	O
	Only	O
	such	O
	positive	O
	actions	O
	can	O
	help	O
	the	O
	infected	O
	back	O
	to	O
	normalay	O
	.	O
		
	stop-x	stop-x
		
	Vision	B-ORG
	Aid	I-ORG
	has	O
	a	O
	vision	O
	for	O
	African	O
	communities	O
	in	O
	Kenya	B-LOC
	.	O
	Benamu	B-ORG
	centre	I-ORG
	is	O
	over	O
	populated	O
	due	O
	to	O
	many	O
	children	O
	in	O
	the	O
	centre	O
	Learning	O
	classed	O
	are	O
	too	O
	small	O
	.	O
	The	O
	pupils	O
	are	O
	much	O
	squeezed	O
	no	O
	space	O
	.	O
	Thank	O
	you	O
	for	O
	Vision	O
	aid	O
	through	O
	their	O
	aid	O
	fund	O
	it	O
	has	O
	renovated	O
	the	O
	school	O
	classroom	O
	issued	O
	books	O
	to	O
	pupils	O
	and	O
	initiating	O
	Drainage	O
	system	O
	in	O
	the	O
	area	O
	.	O
	The	O
	people	O
	in	O
	the	O
	community	O
